<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 3 - Anomaly detection - when ambidexterity tears organizations apart | Mario LE GLATIN</title>
    <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Part 3 - Anomaly detection - when ambidexterity tears organizations apart</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Part 3 - Anomaly detection - when ambidexterity tears organizations apart</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Results</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/chapter6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/chapter6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this first batch of results, we task ourselves to demonstrate an
anomaly in the presented case studies by opposition to the literature
models in our  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter3/&#34;&gt;research questions chapter&lt;/a&gt;,
p.). The results are presented in the same fashion for the three
selected case studies. They are also detailed in different articles in
the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/&#34;&gt;publications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systematically, we present the trajectory of the project where we stress
what appears to be a &lt;em&gt;weak signal&lt;/em&gt; with respect to generative processes
at stake. It appears as an obstacle for collective action, something
that has created a management issue for involved designers, engineers
and managers. We then propose to use the &lt;strong&gt;adaptive, interactive and
encapsulated&lt;/strong&gt; models to &lt;strong&gt;predict&lt;/strong&gt; what could have been the course of
action. It will serve as a reference point for the actual course of
action and detect the anomaly with more precision as explained in the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter4/&#34;&gt;methodology section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We first present the analysis of the &lt;em&gt;Icing conditions detection&lt;/em&gt; case
(see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#icing-conditions-detection&#34;&gt;description&lt;/a&gt;). It reveals what could be considered as absurd or
even irrational decision-making as depicted in (Le Glatin, Le Masson,
and Weil &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;b&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017&#34;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt;), can be accessed in the
appendix (). The product ends up in a paradoxical tension between the
developed technology, its legitimacy and the organizational anchoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, we present another case of platform engineering exploration for
aircraft seat design: &lt;em&gt;Business Class Seat platform&lt;/em&gt; (see description,
p.), which has been analysed in (Le Glatin, Le Masson, and Weil
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2018a&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;) and that can be accessed in the appendix
(p.). The trajectory reveals a transitioning for exploration to
exploitation regime with several difficulties questioning the efficiency
of both exploration and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third and finally, we analyse &lt;em&gt;Airbus Development Team - Design
Thinking&lt;/em&gt; cases (see description, p.). The &lt;em&gt;performance nature&lt;/em&gt; of
generative processes is at the heart of this case as discussed in (Le
Glatin et al. &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;; Le Glatin, Le Masson, and Weil
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) and that can be accessed in the appendix
(p.). Again organizational ambidexterity is challenged by specificities
of generativity causing several complications to enable a sustainable
innovation management.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;icing-conditions-misunderstood-entrepreneur-or-absurdity&#34;&gt;Icing conditions: misunderstood entrepreneur or absurdity?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trajectory-of-the-project&#34;&gt;Trajectory of the project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As described previously in the methodology sections (see p.), the case
was suggested to the researcher for analysis as the R&amp;amp;T manager had
managed the project from the beginning and had increasing pressure on
the conditions of exploitation after the years of exploration and
financial constraints to continue exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure.&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:IcingTraj&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:IcingTraj&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;
below, gives the chronology of the project as it was developed over more
than two decades. The sequence can be followed through the numbers at
the corner of several boxes and years highlighted at the bottom. The
arrows indicate sequence and causality operating for actions, decisions
and the design of decisions. It is, of course, a condensed view of the
history of the project but we can stress the nature of exploration
(disrupt monopoly), when exploitation (client request and market
opportunity) could have occurred and when exploration was launched
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vertical dotted line is the critical part in the project trajectory.
A first exploration was carried out by the project team looking for
alternative solution overcoming limitations known of the monopoly’s
solution. They scouted the field, several test campaigns were conducted
with the support of national laboratories and aircraft manufacturers.
These were proven successful despite some caveats as the first
technology developed addressed only ice detection on ground. However,
another solution was developed with further test campaigns. Regional
aircraft manufacturers were looking for an alternative solution to the
monopoly and possibly for an integrated system: detection and protection
from ice. Restrictions were looming over regional aircrafts as they were
statistically known more sensitive to icing conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, instead of going for this aircraft program and
system/product development between ZFCS and ZEEU that was at hand’s
reach, the current technology development were stopped altogether.
Exploitation promises were discarded, in order to launch a new wave of
exploration addressing yet to be specified icing conditions: new
undefined regulations, scientific knowledge on icing conditions, and
appropriate technology. We propose then to zoom on this key moment of
the project history that balances exploration and exploitation in order
to make sense of it through the lens of literature models.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-a-onstituted-path-challenging-bu-strategy-and-organization-ties&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/IcingTraj.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;A onstituted path challenging BU strategy and organization ties&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/IcingTraj.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    A onstituted path challenging BU strategy and organization ties
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;models-predictions&#34;&gt;Models’ predictions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;adaptive-model-predictions-for-icing-condtions&#34;&gt;Adaptive model predictions for Icing condtions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Predictions of the &lt;em&gt;adaptive&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BU management and group top management were involved in key decisions (search direction for technology development, patenting, business acquisition, etc.). &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: BU management could have selected the program opportunity with the development of the system between ZFCS and ZEEU as a means to set a first foot on the monopoly for future learning promises in the new environment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration was rich in finding existing alternatives but generating new ones that are undecidable is not considered by adaptive models. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The exploration movement should have been gradually adapted to fit exploitation constraints. Make or Buy strategy for the detection technology (e.g. acquire Vibrometer firm) in order to bring value added with an integrated system (detection and protection) by opposition to a standalone solution.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Interactions were created with laboratories, test facilities and potential clients to guide the search direction: overcome limitations of monopoly’s solution. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Wait for the environment to stabilize and prescribe new requirements on icing conditions regulations, which can make the generated concepts decidable.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&amp;amp;T team dedicated to exploration, spatially isolated from engineering department. It was identified as a new standalone product line. The development engineering was familiar with systems engineering. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The exploitation could have been conducted for the icing conditions detection and protection system between ZFCS and ZEEU. Resources were available.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;interactive-model-predictions-for-icing-conditions&#34;&gt;Interactive model predictions for Icing conditions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Predictions of the &lt;em&gt;adaptive&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&amp;amp;T engineers and managers created and made sense of the surveyed technologies. Meetings were organized with middle and top management to structure future course of action. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Middle and top management allow and enable further interactions to gain awareness and act accordingly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Test campaigns, studies and meetings were conducted and shared among engineers and managers. Presentations are held with management to envision new positioning &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;:  The appropriate sense and knowledge could have eventually captured through subsequent interactions. R&amp;amp;T manager could have then refined the new meaning emerging from further exploration.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Numerous interactions with clients, laboratories and potential clients were conducted to address uncertainties of icing conditions and required technologies. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Shape new networks, lead-users and unknown interpreters to gradually design new technologies for icing conditions. Continue developing open innovation practice.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration team had expanded beyond the ZFCS boundaries and gradually gaining recognition. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: This open innovation should have easily shaped a fully autonomous product line as the legitimation process is carried out. Perhaps even a new BU (ad-hoc) could be created.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;encapsulated-model-predictions-for-icing-conditions&#34;&gt;Encapsulated model predictions for Icing conditions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Predictions of the &lt;em&gt;adaptive&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration was seen as sequenced projects probing alternatives’ validity and success. The overall icing condition detection theme could be considered as a program but without the management structure, despite having a governance with middle and top management sessions. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Road-mapping activities to pave the way for future projects.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Each specific project encapsulated design and engineering practices to refine the selected alternatives. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;:  These trial-and-error projects proving the technology, regulation and market landscape should continue until an appropriate fit is crystallized.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Each project engaged with clients and test facilities, and they allowed building upon each other. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Each project will explore the environment in a given direction and contribute to future projects. For instance, the program could have enforced the exploitation opportunity to sustain further exploration on the side.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The projects relied on R&amp;amp;T engineers and request additional resources if needed. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Transferring the project to the development engineering to develop the integrated system would have been possible due to system related knowledge.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;anomaly-market-legitimacy-for-the-market-but-no-organizational-support&#34;&gt;Anomaly: market legitimacy for the market but no organizational support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Actual course of action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The team conducting exploration didn’t support the exploitation opportunity but rather continued exploration. They handed over some R&amp;amp;T engineers to develop &amp;ldquo;on the shelf&amp;rdquo; the first version of the explored product, whilst further exploration continued shaping the unknown (norms and regulations, and aircraft integration and safety)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration was guided by a future prospect of exploitation: safety norm evolution and associated icing conditions typologies. They willingly reversed preferences by choosing a highly uncertain technology, but managing the environment legitimacy in parallel.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The environment is shaped by the R&amp;amp;T manager constituting a collective path for the market: deciding regulation’s scope and application, steering scientific discoveries and applied research on icing conditions, and specifying norm and technological performance.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The projects managed by the R&amp;amp;T team were rather autonomous with partnerships and funding agreements. They gained autonomy up to a point where developing a product required to hand over some R&amp;amp;T engineers to the Product Development department.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What our descriptors reveal is that the conducted project does partially
fit some of the models with an emphasis on the interactive and
encapsulated models. The team engaged with the environment’s actors and
pushed the trial-and-error pattern to ensure the legitimation of the
developed technology as well as the primacy/leadership of the newly
reconfigured icing conditions detection market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we see that the exploration is guided by exploitation
constraints that still requires to be fully settled and designed. The
project is at odds with organization design as they have evolved in
autonomy and developed capabilities so far unmatched by legacy
engineering departments. Top management, despite having sponsored the
exploration, still tries to keep the BU &lt;em&gt;together&lt;/em&gt; and avoids having a
spin-off. As the technology is not fully mandatory for existing
heavy-body aircraft (statistically proven by manufacturers), it still
requires to make a case for itself beyond small/regional aircraft
market. The BU strategy is thus challenged by this market re-orientation
and the lack of technology-market fitness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;lone-irrational-entrepreneur&#34;&gt;Lone irrational entrepreneur?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could argue the R&amp;amp;T manager used foolishness (March

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;) to refuse the first exploitation opportunity
benefiting from synergies with another BU. He is however a sane spirit
in a sane body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adaptation of technology is performed dynamically with the
environment being shaped by managing safety regulation and norms as well
as technology legitimation. Exploration of technologies and product
concept are guided by generating and refining alternatives of what
exploitation (regulation and standard) could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The non-mutual conditioning of the regimes is compromised, but brings
new hopes for exploitation. As discussed in (Le Glatin, Le Masson, and
Weil 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;b&lt;/a&gt;, see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-leglatin2017a/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;), preferences were reversed, representing a violation of rational theory
of choice, but at the same time allowed uncovering prospective
alternatives requiring a contingent environment management.
This entrepreneurial effort is not isolated, it was sustained through a
rich engagement with the environment, learning for the R&amp;amp;T team, but
also support from BU management and top management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-bu-for-zssm&#34;&gt;New BU for ZSSM?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This offshoot generated by the R&amp;amp;T team dedicated to icing conditions
detection was established as a young product line. The issue for top
management is the absence of a clearly defined market for heavy-body
aircraft, which are the &lt;em&gt;norm&lt;/em&gt; for other products in the BU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is probably the paradox of this exploration project and the autonomy
gained through open innovation practice, path constitution and funding
schemes. It is abnormal for the three models, as the top management
sponsored the emergent strategy from the beginning, and steered the
process along the way as a strong technological advantage could be
developed to overcome the monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, exploitation is shifted from its standard belief and
conception to market the product, from a marketing and engineering
standpoint. In fact, the prototype developed and tested by R&amp;amp;T implies a
lot of rework for development engineering, in terms of robustness,
quality and manufacturing engineering. Nevertheless, the prototype can
also be seen as a means to support learning of the new technology so far
unfamiliar to the engineering department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a new BU appeared out of the equation. BU management preferred
to capitalize on the exploration and develop the new technology on the
shelf. They also allowed with external funding to let the new technology
version to be further explored as the norms and regulations being
co-managed by the R&amp;amp;T manager have created new slots requiring applied
research and product development to ensure aircraft safety and
airworthiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-seat-platform-poor-exploration-management&#34;&gt;A seat platform: poor exploration management?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trajectory-of-the-project-1&#34;&gt;Trajectory of the project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As described previously in the case presentation (see p.), the
researcher was encouraged to have a closer look to this seat design
after we had organized several meetings and workshops to support the BU
in implementing their own management tools and practice to evaluate TRL
for R&amp;amp;T projects and support handovers with Development Engineering.
This Business Class seat platform project, not only raised the
assessment issue for isolated technologies and its integration, but
rather emphasised the criticality of design robustness as a system to
meet requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:BCTraj&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:BCTraj&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;
below, gives the chronology of the project as it was developed over more
than two years. The sequence can be followed through the numbers at the
corner of several boxes and years highlighted at the bottom. The arrows
indicate sequence and causality operating for actions, decisions and the
design of decisions. It is a condensed view of the history of the
project but we can stress the nature of exploration (platform envelop
definition and selection) and the shift towards exploitation requested
by a demanding client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vertical dotted line is the critical part in the project trajectory.
A first exploration was carried out by the project team looking for
alternative solution overcoming limitations of packaging and
certification for business class (BC) seat. Several options were found
in the market (patents, competition benchmark) and they designed several
alternatives before elaborating criteria with BU stakeholders to decide
on the concept. They ended up with a seat architecture sharing a frame
with neighbouring seat (like a bench) supporting their own load and a
shell providing volume and several valuable BC features. The modular
design puts the emphasis on the seat lower frame as being the core on
which all other modules would plug in (foot rest, backrest, shell,
etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is when sales and program management teams saw the attractivity of
the product with a greater living space which seduced a demanding
client. The concept design was then selected by the client and further
refined with their own design studio. However, this shift from
exploration to exploitation revealed several complications in the design
architecture. For instance, the 3 legged seat and the load of both seat
and shell packaged together as whole for certification (i.e. airworthy
and safe for passenger) raised the mechanical engineering complexity.
This a priori successful balance from exploration to exploitation came
out to be quite disastrous: quality issues, delays, engineering cost
overruns, and jeopardized seat platform.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-a-jeopardized-platform-engineering&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/BCTraj.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;A jeopardized platform engineering&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/BCTraj.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    A jeopardized platform engineering
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;models-predictions-1&#34;&gt;Models’ predictions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;adaptive-model-predictions-for-bc-seat-platform&#34;&gt;Adaptive model predictions for BC seat platform&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Predictions of the &lt;em&gt;adaptive&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sales, Engineering and Strategy managers took part in balancing out exploration and exploitation effort. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Management would actually encourage exploitation of the explored alternatives and subsequent decision-making (concept selection process )&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration was rich in finding and generating alternatives, ensuring enough room for engineering to develop a solution. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Once the concept is selected, the uncertainty reduction mindset of development projects would be applied to meet client requirements and product early-specifications (modularity).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The technology and patent scouting was rich and allowed finding &lt;em&gt;white spaces&lt;/em&gt; to develop new solutions. Known issues for packaging, aircraft integration and certification-ease were used to design alternatives. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Once a client can make a demand fitting existing offer (preliminary design), the exploitation should be launched and further development would be based on adapting the course of action.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&amp;amp;T team dedicated to exploration and isolated from engineering department. They were tasked to create a new product concept based on modularity and new requirements. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: When exploitation requirements are given, the project should transfer its resources to development engineering.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;interactive-model-predictions-for-bc-seat-platform&#34;&gt;Interactive model predictions for BC seat platform&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Predictions of the &lt;em&gt;adaptive&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&amp;amp;T engineers and manager designed digital mock-ups, coordinated with stakeholders to select concepts. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;:  Middle and top management pushes the mock-up and prototypes among department to learn by doing and meet requirements along the development process.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tests, simulations and meetings were held around digital mock-ups to refine and generate choices. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The mutual interactions between individuals and prototypes during presentations, and client meetings will gradually ensure a smooth uncertainty reduction.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Demonstrated awareness and scouting of the environment through presentations and consultations with BU stakeholders (engineering, marketing, packaging, certification). &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;:  Added requirements will be identified through interactions with client and prescribers (design studio). In exchange, the proposed seat platform features will be discussed and mutually adjusted.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The initial R&amp;amp;T project spreads beyond the R&amp;amp;T team boundaries with involvement and consultation of different stakeholders. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Depending on the evolution and definition of requirements, the necessary resources will be found and support the product design. The Engineering department may have to be reconfigured to fit the modular design.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;encapsulated-model-predictions-for-bc-seat-platform&#34;&gt;Encapsulated model predictions for BC seat platform&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Predictions of the &lt;em&gt;adaptive&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration project had a concern for platform engineering feasibility and an exploitation target (packaging, ease certification). Middle management as well as BU management supported the initiative. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The project would be part of a product line or stream of projects, and eventually a program for business class seat platform.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The design practice to define the seat platform made an effort to define the minimum and common features required for modularity. The selection criteria also shaped the design of alternatives. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: As new requirements would be demanded by the client, the project would gradually adapt and propose variations to the platform.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The project reached out for unmet needs from value chain and aircraft integration to extend the project’s requirements. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The client’s project would define new requirements and induce constraints that would have to be adjusted to the R&amp;amp;T project’s specifications.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The projects relied on R&amp;amp;T engineers and request additional resources if needed. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Transferring the project to the development engineering to develop the seat platform would require to temporarily find resources in engineering departments to solve conflicting requirements.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;anomaly-a-rich-exploration-jeopardized-by-a-demanding-client&#34;&gt;Anomaly: a rich exploration jeopardized by a demanding client&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Actual course of action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration is guided by exploitation objectives. The shift is capitalized by the client and its requirement. During the actual product development, mechanical engineering issues were faced due to novelty/unfamiliarity of the product for development engineers.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Careful exploration was conducted with criteria for selecting them defined with BU stakeholders. The complications faced by exploitation activities raise numerous questions on the evaluation of generated/selected alternatives. In the end, the platform design is no longer modular and the client’s product becomes specific and has generated cost overruns.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;After exploring the environment to define the platform, the client and its design studio imposed requirements forcing the platform design to be adapted. The built-up awareness for exploration is reduced and non-negotiated with the client (imposed requirements).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The project gradually moved from R&amp;amp;T to Engineering, but also had to come back to some R&amp;amp;T engineers to solve complications in mechanical engineering practice. The Engineering Department struggled to meet requirements.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This comparison shows that the actual course of action is far more
complex and raises again numerous obstacles the literature models would
not have fully grasped. For instance, the decision-making process
organized during the exploration phase was used not only to select a
platform design, but also as a basis to generate new alternatives in
between decision meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition from exploration to exploitation was seen from the angle
of the client who identified a feature (increased living space and leg
space) in the platform seat (with its enhanced packaging and
certification). However, the difficulties were treated by the
Engineering department requiring to call back R&amp;amp;T engineer to support
them. There is then an overlap of the influences between exploration and
exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;lack-robust-design-practice-between-rt-and-development&#34;&gt;Lack robust design practice between R&amp;amp;T and Development?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could argue that the engineering is overall of poor quality. It is
an argument hard to sustain as the BU is one of the market leaders and
pioneered several designs. Moreover, the product development is
conducted in short time period (2 years approximately) and it requires a
lot of flexibility within engineering departments to support the design
and development. The researcher had the occasion on multiple occasions
to witness the density of relationships and knowledge sharing within a
project’s scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with the Engineering Director, ex-post reviews were conducted
to evaluate the maturity and robustness of the design during the
exploitation phase (client’s program gates). It revealed that the
several mechanical issues relating to the interference of the platform
design and client requirements were understood late in the development
process. The researcher found that traditional product development (i.e.
no modularity) relies a lot on the physical testing conducted quite late
in the process due to parts availability&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. However, simulation test
engineers had flagged several flaws of the design, but were not heard by
development engineering preferring to witness the physical test, whereas
they were by R&amp;amp;T engineers during the exploration phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is not a complete failure as teachings have been transferred
to R&amp;amp;T team and advanced concept team (group of internal designers and
engineers) to study again the possibility to develop a new modular
design, with more emphasis on the shell design. Another topic on
modularity was also launched by the R&amp;amp;T team approaching the concept
differently, for instance, not in seat-centric way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;too-early-explorationexploitation-transition&#34;&gt;Too early exploration/exploitation transition?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could also argue the project was handed over to quickly to the
engineering department. However, it is not really the case as the
selection of concepts was made collectively and interactively with BU
stakeholder. The client’s request for proposal and bid award was an
actual great opportunity to value the exploration phase conducted by the
R&amp;amp;T team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is perhaps missing is the weakness in countering the demanding
client’s request which have pushed the physical limits of the platform
design. Why not using the client’s opportunity and constraints to
develop in parallel a full platform design instead of trying to keep
some complicated associated features (e.g. totally new compact seat
kinematic)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exploration and exploitation were put on a same continuum, being
perhaps overlapped at the beginning of the project. Later, it
unfortunately over-complexified the product design and development, to a
point where the innovation effort in the platform design is killed by
switching to a normalized exploitation regime. When discussing with
engineers and managers why some alternatives had been discarded
(designed by the researcher with C-K Theory, see (Le Glatin, Le Masson,
and Weil 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2018a&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;, see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-leglatin2018a/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;),
signs of regret were identified explaining the difficulty to identify
and articulate the exploration/exploitation divide earlier in design
practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adtdesign-thinking-resistance-death-valley-and-organizational-misfit-by-design&#34;&gt;ADT/Design Thinking: resistance, death valley and organizational misfit by design?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trajectory-of-the-project-2&#34;&gt;Trajectory of the project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last case we are presenting here is the synthesis of two projects
managed by the Airbus Development Team (see p.). The researcher had the
occasion to analyse two projects led by two different members (engineer
and designer) who had been trained to Design Thinking. The other ADT
participants had been also introduced, if not trained to it, like it was
the case of ADT’s manager. The latter had given access to all
documentation available on their server and requested his colleagues to
save some time for my interviews. The team had been tasked to generate
proposals valuing BU’s know-how and combined synergies in the form of
Multi-BU projects. They usually referred to the recurrent argument of
the &lt;em&gt;not-invented here syndrome&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;resistance to change&lt;/em&gt; to explain
the absence of follow-up by BUs to develop their generated concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, they stressed some cases where BUs were thrilled by having
opened their eyes to the competencies of sister BUs in the group,
unlocking interdependencies between products that are usually hidden by
market segmentation and sales channels. The projects based on Design
Thinking adapted the method to have BUs not only learn from user
knowledge, but also to have multi-BU design workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As presented in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/project/design-thinking-for-innovation-management/&#34;&gt;publications on Design Thinking&lt;/a&gt;, the cases were analysed with the help of C-K design theory in
order to understand the performance of the generative processes in the
projects and their impact for BUs (ADT’s mission). The C-K mappings were
synthesized from control groups of students from Mines ParisTech. The
figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:ADTTraj&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:ADTTraj&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;
below shows the synthesis of the projects’ trajectory. Both design
briefs (Better Waste Management and Turn Around Time Optimization)
followed the same pattern as they had defined a methodology canvas
adapted from their practice, experience and Design Thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our focus is on the output of the projects as they come to a standstill.
If Design Thinking may not be the key to everything, it is worth
understanding the relationship between the nature of generative
processes and their organization impact: concept appropriation and
development by business units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/project/ambidexterity-exploration-exploitation/&#34;&gt;publications on ambidexterity&lt;/a&gt;, this transition from exploration to an absence of exploitation is
analysed. Below, we propose rephrasing it with descriptors and models’
predictions derived from our literature review. The trajectory is
summarized in figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:ADTTraj&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:ADTTraj&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;,
and they strech over less than a year (approximately 8 months).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-a-constituted-path-challenging-bu-strategy-and-organization-ties&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/ADTTraj.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;A constituted path challenging BU strategy and organization ties&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/ADTTraj.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    A constituted path challenging BU strategy and organization ties
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;models-predictions-2&#34;&gt;Models’ predictions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;adaptive-model-predictions-for-adtdesign-thinking-projects&#34;&gt;Adaptive model predictions for ADT/Design Thinking projects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Predictions of the &lt;em&gt;adaptive&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ADT manager leaded the balancing of exploration and exploitation prospects (BU’s interests). Sponsorship from the VP of Business Development &amp;amp; Strategy. Workshops were organized to balance out concepts and their rework. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Leadership and top management identifies how the concepts can fit BUs’ strategies.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration was supported by Design Thinking generative power driven by user empathy and extreme user cases. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: As user/client value is supported by Design Thinking practice, the product development (exploitation) should naturally occur.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The environment and value chain was scouted with the help of Design Thinking and other ADT’s activities such as previous projects and technical support. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The newly explored environment should ensure enough decisional/problem-solving background for BUs to engage in exploitation of concept proposals.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ADT team is an example of contextual ambidexterity organized at the group level. The exploration is delocalized, interactions with relevant BUs are maintained along the exploration process (for organizational learning). &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Exploitation of proposed concepts will be slightly adapted to the products design as they may require contractual development between BUs. Organization design should mirror the product as they have accepted and participated to the concepts’ user/client value.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;interactive-model-predictions-for-adtdesign-thinking-projects&#34;&gt;Interactive model predictions for ADT/Design Thinking projects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Predictions of the &lt;em&gt;adaptive&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ADT members and BUs correspondents, at stake with project’s topic, are in continuous contact to share knowledge and co-design concepts. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Middle management should naturally embrace the concepts as meaning is created and circulated. Top management will sponsor the initiative due to emergent strategic interest.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Users and observation studies provided the foundations to generate concepts and solve existing or non-existing issues creating justified value-added. Co-design sessions with BUs also contributed to it in addition to knowledge sharing. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The gradual sense-making and demonstrated client value should ensure concept appropriation and development.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BUs’ environment knowledge was integrated as well as extended by scouting. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;:  The explored environment with new conceptual alternatives extends the network for BUs and allows them to build system thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration project used internal ADT resources and progressively solicited BUs’ resources for exploration. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The proposed concepts may call for an intra-BU or inter-BU development depending on the interactions with existing BUs’ product architecture. BUs should then align as value is demonstrated.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;encapsulated-model-predictions-for-adtdesign-thinking-projects&#34;&gt;Encapsulated model predictions for ADT/Design Thinking projects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Predictions of the &lt;em&gt;adaptive&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration projects were part of the overall ADT’s program of making boundary-spanning proposal for BUs to develop intra and/or inter BU products. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The sum of projects would potentially generate organizational learning for BUs, if not, create product development opportunities through top management program governance and sponsorship from VP of Business Development and Strategy.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Design Thinking, combined with ADT’s experience and Practices, supported the exploration effort, in addition to the ADT overarching design brief. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The generativity would be driven by user observation and BUs segmentation to create the appropriate associations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The generative processes have encoded the need to scout the environment by targeting user experiences. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: The exploration projects would open a new and demonstrated product development environment for BUs.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration projects rely on ADT’s resources and handover to BUs after selection. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;: Transferring would imply technical documentation to fit BUs available resources or identify new ones.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;anomaly-client-value-demonstrated-but-no-npd&#34;&gt;Anomaly: client value demonstrated but no NPD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Actual course of action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The exploration is guided by exploitation objectives (user pains) that are potentially in-between BUs boundaries.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The generativity is supported by Design Thinking and added practices (multi-BU co-design workshops). The assumption is made that the user and client value being demonstrated, the concepts will naturally trigger their product development. The generative process is naturally fixated by users (encoded in design method).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;User experiences and BUs’ environment are scouted. Design Thinking mainly develops concepts fixated by the existing environment. When crazy concepts are generated, they are adapted to what a BU would develop without considering capabilities (re-)generation of the environment (product standards, certification, sales channels).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;When crazy concepts are generated, they are adapted to what a BU can develop without actually considering new or recombination of capabilities within the BU or with other BUs.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comparison of the actual course of action with the models’
prediction reveals again the necessity to understand the
micro-foundations of exploration and exploitation, and their balance.
The generative process practice of Design Thinking gives an idea of the
direction of generativity and how it tries to build to innovation
potential of attraction through demonstrated user and client value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, none of the business units were interested in actually
committing to pushing the concepts further. They had accepted the
concepts and recognized their interest and client value. They had even
co-designed the concepts with ADT members, validated by VP Business
Development sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exploration opened the path to new knowledge and better awareness of
the environment and system thinking. Opportunities of connecting BUs
together, through concepts revisiting interdependencies, were identified
as they would be usually hidden behind their traditional market and
product perspective. Nevertheless, the models fail in explaining why the
concepts are not developed by BUs as we discuss below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;co-design-acceptance-and-no-follow-up&#34;&gt;Co-design, acceptance and no follow-up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;non-invented here syndrome&lt;/em&gt; could be of course flagged as being the
main reason for BUs not accepting to making these concepts their own.
Indeed, no project lines were added to the budget by Business Unit. Only
one added a line, but with zero budget, meaning they would perhaps
consider a paper study. The &lt;em&gt;death valley&lt;/em&gt; argument (Markham et al.

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Markham2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;) is also not really valid as BU can budget the
project, and budget consolidation is discussed with group CTO, ExCom and
each BU manager to decide how they size the budget with support from the
holding’s budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is even more surprising is the fact that engineers, designers and
managers from BUs participated to co-design workshops with other BUs.
They legitimized and made sense of the concepts themselves in addition
to welcoming the shared knowledge on users and value chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;exploring-alternative-aircraft-spaces&#34;&gt;Exploring alternative aircraft spaces&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the concepts generated with Design Thinking, as presented in

&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/project/design-thinking-for-innovation-management/&#34;&gt;our publication&lt;/a&gt;, were designed as if for BUs wouldn’t change. Moreover, the
decision process to rank and select concepts in order to be promoted to
BUs reinforced the stability of existing boundaries and engineering
capabilities, as well as markets domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some other cases, concepts generated through &lt;em&gt;What Ifs? scenario&lt;/em&gt;
allowed relieving some operational constraints (e.g. passengers storing
their personal luggage in containers, passengers participating to waste
sorting). These concepts unlocked interdependencies between aircraft
equipment and engineering as seen in C-K reference mapping. However, the
concepts were promoted as if BUs could just adapt them, without
emphasizing the radicality of the new perspective implying deep
reconfiguration of engineering design, system architecture and market
positioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have overall a good example of ambidextrous organization with a
supportive top management leadership, a valuable generative process,
deep interactions at different management levels. But, our literature
models fail to explain the absence of further product development or
even re-use of a feature in their technology and product roadmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Based on the methodology designed for our research questions, we have
taken each case individually by identifying a critical snapshot in the
project trajectories where the adaptive, interactive and encapsulated
models where used for predictions. By categorizing these with our
descriptors, and comparing them with the actual course of action, we
have spotted anomalies and discussed their justification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we have demonstrated the fact that ambidexterity actually kills
innovation, which answers our first research question. We have also
managed to specify the different obstacles revealed by the analysis
supported by design theory and engineering bringing the necessity for an
micro-approach to the balancing of exploration and exploitation. Several
biases and fixations effects stem from the &lt;em&gt;non-mutual conditioning&lt;/em&gt;
between these two regimes, which appears to be no longer valid in the
unknown and high uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we have also stressed that the black-boxing of generative
processes within projects can later create controversies for middle/top
management as well as strategic coherence. Indeed, the separation of
exploration from exploitation at the organizational levels tends to
bring and reinforce &lt;strong&gt;organization design fixations&lt;/strong&gt;. It does not
encourage taking them into account within generative processes to value
the necessary change dynamics among resources nor the routines
supporting engineering practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, these results, specified in different ways through intra and
inter BU cases, give several hints to try to overcome the literature
models’ limitations to design an extended model reconciling with the
observed anomalies. Our aim would be to reconnect the ambidexterity
models with the unknown since innovation management has developed in
ways that the original non-mutual conditioning has lost ground.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Glatin, Mario, Pascal Le Masson, Armand Hatchuel, and Benoît Weil.
2018. “Design Paradigm in innovation management - analysing and
extending design thinking methods with design theory.” In &lt;em&gt;R&amp;amp;D
Management Conference&lt;/em&gt;. Milan, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Glatin, Mario, Pascal Le Masson, and Benoit Weil. 2016. “Measuring
the generative power of an organisational routine with design theories:
the case of design thinking in a large firm.” In &lt;em&gt;6th Cim Community
Workshop - 25th Anniversary of the Creativity and Innovation Management
Journal&lt;/em&gt;. Potsdam.

&lt;a href=&#34;https://hal.archives-ouvertes.fr/hal-01367471%7B%5c#%7D.V9u4ZMmiS0k.mendeley&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://hal.archives-ouvertes.fr/hal-01367471{\#}.V9u4ZMmiS0k.mendeley&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Glatin, Mario, Pascal Le Masson, and Benoît Weil. 2017a. “Decision
design and re-ordering preferences: the case of an exploration project
in a large firms.” In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 21st International Conference
on Engineering Design (Iced17)&lt;/em&gt;, 7:81–90. August. Vancouver, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2017b. “Generative action and preference reversal in exploratory
project management.” &lt;em&gt;CERN IdeaSquare Journal of Experimental
Innovation&lt;/em&gt; 1 (2): 39–46. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2018a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2018. “Can Ambidexterity kill innovation? A case for non-expected
utility decision-making.” In &lt;em&gt;EURAM 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Reykjavik, Iceland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-March2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March, James G. 2006. “Rationality, foolishness, and adaptive
intelligence.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 27 (3): 201–14.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.515&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.515&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Markham2010&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markham, Stephen K., Stephen J. Ward, Lynda Aiman-Smith, and Angus I.
Kingon. 2010. “The valley of death as context for role theory in product
innovation.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Product Innovation Management&lt;/em&gt; 27 (3): 402–17.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-5885.2010.00724.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-5885.2010.00724.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is almost a &lt;em&gt;religious&lt;/em&gt; moment for engineers and the client who
is sometimes invited. People come to witness the first dynamic crash
test as it were a major milestone in the qualification process which
validates design choices &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - Management anomaly specification</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/chapter7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/chapter7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, we propose to synthesize the anomalies highlighted by
the cases’ results of the previous chapter before listing the
requirements to design a new model extending the literature models of
non-mutual conditioning between exploration and exploitation, in order
to understand the observed phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first feature raised through the descriptors and the comparison
between models’ prediction is perhaps the continuity and orthogonality
of exploration/exploitation that is dealt at different levels:
generative processes, coordination mechanisms, environment cognition and
organization design. So, we confirm the nuances expressed in (Gupta,
Smith, and Shalley 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gupta2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;). What is perhaps more
surprising and natural at the same time is the fact that exploration can
be based on exploitation characteristics. However, the cases show these
can be beneficial or counter-productive for innovation management, thus
requiring an careful management to counter the forces of traditional
models of ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second aspect is that we can assert that ambidexterity kills
innovation. It is of course a bold statement, but the meta-language of
exploration/exploitation tends to ignore the micro-foundations of
collective action such as decision-making and generative processes
(Birkinshaw and Gupta 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;). The actual
implementation of ambidexterity, be it contextual, structural or
sequential, induces numerous complications dealing with
exploration/exploitation regime separation for practice. More
specifically, it appears to be incompatible with practices where the
unknown is effectively managed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cases show they follow organizational ambidexterity, but at the same
time, have mitigated efficiency when it comes to exploration or
exploitation standalone. Radical innovation is not really achieved for
the originally intended exploration project, despite having several
other valuable takeaways (Elmquist and Le Masson

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Elmquist2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;). There is tendency to leave exploitation
routines as a static reference point, as a fixation effect, and let
exploration free float in other directions without carefully managing
the search and generation directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organization design being constricted by certification and market
constraints, generative processes and organization ambidexterity clashes
to support this enclosed change calling for a support of organizational
metabolism and potential &lt;em&gt;regenerative dynamic capabilities&lt;/em&gt; (Ambrosini,
Bowman, and Collier 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Ambrosini2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;). Despite appropriate
interactionism, we have seen that practices are not sufficient to
sustain generative processes into a full settlement organizations. At
best, in the case of the icing conditions detection, the settlement is
partial as the alignment with BU management and Engineering department
remains controversial. Consequently, reconsidering organization design
supported/supporting generative processes appears crucial, as it
probably implies considering the mirroring of the engineering efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consequently, we would propose some requirements extending the
literature models presented previously. These where limited to
non-mutual conditioning of exploration and exploitation. This extension
is crucial since the observed phenomena tends to show dynamics sustained
at the level of engineering design practices challenging the
coordination of exploration/exploitation conditioning and the management
of its innovation potential of attraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose to simply name this extended model by considering the
&lt;strong&gt;mutual conditioning between exploration and exploitation&lt;/strong&gt; as a means
to overcome the fixation effects which are managed at the engineering
design, organizational and environment levels.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;synthesis-of-anomalies&#34;&gt;Synthesis of anomalies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three cases presented in the previous chapter have insisted on
different limitations of the three proposed literature models of
non-mutual conditioning between exploration and exploitation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adaptive model:&lt;/strong&gt; the search-based assumption of exploration is
overstretched by generative processes of different nature and locus.
Exploration is guided by uncertain or unknown (i.e. to be designed)
exploitation constraints as cleverly managed in the icing conditions
detection case. Whereas, it can also be a lock-in despite valuable
generativity on the user experience domain, as several fixation
effects of existing business units are not revisited as presented in
the ADT’s cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive model:&lt;/strong&gt; creation of meaning and value circulation
among (silent) designers around meetings and prototypes are not
sufficient to sustain radical innovation and the associate unknown
gradual shaping. The business class seat platform shows the
interference and conflicts arising from the exploration/exploitation
handover and agenda differences. It would require a management of
deeper learning mechanisms. Exploration and exploitation are
unfortunately both jeopardized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encapsulated model:&lt;/strong&gt; As already stressed in the literature on
project-based management, the need to link project trajectories with
underlying organizational ties, resources and routines is even more
critical at the light of exploration projects searching for
exploitation landing fields. Learning and change management tend to
be dissociated in exploration and exploitation regimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Below, we stress the anomalies raised by the cases compared to the
synthetic model portrait in the research questions chapter (p.). As the
reader will notice, some anomalies are reformulations further specifying
the limitations already raised in the literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we come back on the different observed anomalies based on the
models predictions by comparison with the actual course of actions. We
start then disentangling these anomalies before formulating our new
model requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Non-mutual conditioning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mutual conditioning results&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1. Not necessarily on the same continuum, exploration and exploitation call for two dissociate action regimes. &lt;br&gt;2. Balancing is left as a paradox at different levels of analysis: structure (centralization, distribution), time and individuals.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1. Exploration is driven by exploitation characteristics, sometimes with loss of control. &lt;br&gt;2. Leaving the balancing as a paradox leaves innovation unmanaged. Balancing exploration and exploitation can be managed through sensemaking around prototypes and meetings, but does not address the change management properly (partial or dynamic mirroring)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3. The nature of generative processes supporting exploration appears quite free, random and sometimes even foolishness-based. &lt;br&gt;4. Generativity of the product development may not be sustained by (temporary) organizations (floating issue).&lt;br&gt;5. The performance and reference is light structured: reduced to a selection issue or sometimes to complex interactionist phenomenon.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3. Generative processes are partly directed if not biased by exploitation constraints and not necessarily managed carefully. &lt;br&gt;4. Generativity may indeed require radical organizational learning and change but is not properly managed at the engineering design practice level.&lt;br&gt;5. Performance is not necessarily discussed nor sanctioned but appears as a conscious struggle that goes beyond selection process or sensemaking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6. One-way interaction: Environment to Organization. &lt;br&gt;7. The environment structures the response, nature and distribution of generative processes. &lt;br&gt;8. The environment is used to augment the product development requirements.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6. The environment may be actively managed to legitimize the innovation potential. &lt;br&gt;7. Generative processes do not (systematically) address and leverage fixations by the environment. &lt;br&gt;8. The environment awareness does augment design requirements but struggles in identifying the mirroring organization change.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9. Organization design is pre-conceived or uncontrolled. &lt;br&gt;10. Organization design creates gaps for managing generative processes and the dynamics of their organizational ties.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9. Organizational ambidexterity conflicts with design and engineering organizational mirroring. &lt;br&gt;10. Organization design is isolated by exploration/exploitation dichotomy.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;generativity-biased-by-explorationexploitation-dichotomy&#34;&gt;Generativity biased by exploration/exploitation dichotomy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, it is important to note again that our research agenda set
from the beginning was to use advances in design reasoning and theory to
understand how generative processes and associated management of unknown
allows revisiting innovation management and the major construct of
ambidexterity. The cases presented earlier show how the models black-box
the nature of generative processes and their interferences with several
managerial dimensions such as: coordination mechanisms, environment
cognition and organization design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angela Dumas with Henry Mintzberg (Dumas and Mintzberg

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dumas1989&#34;&gt;1989&lt;/a&gt;) had stressed the importance of &lt;em&gt;silent design&lt;/em&gt;
occurring across the organization. The cases reveal how these
distributed design activities can be framed and segregated by what
exploration and exploitation are in an ambidextrous organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the cases of the business class seat and ADT, the generative
processes had used clear exploitation characteristics to base their
exploration: seat packaging, integration and certification issues, and
user pains. It is used as a reference point, but at the same time when
balancing out exploration/exploitation, the generative processes require
an extreme adaption to exploitation organizational constraints despite
having made a strong effort on the cognitive and interactive dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exploitation is conducted as if a simple extended or new list of
requirements had been given to the engineering departments. Risks can be
assessed, as well as maturity, but these registers are unfortunately
rather static. They may not capture and manage &lt;em&gt;epistemic
interdependencies&lt;/em&gt; accordingly (Puranam, Raveendran, and Knudsen

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Puranam2012a&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploration efforts are then potentially biased by the non-mutual
conditioning. And inversely, the exploitation is heavily burdened by
exploration features that lack articulation with generated novelties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;killing-sustained-innovation-capabilities&#34;&gt;Killing sustained innovation capabilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of unknown, its management and generativity have been
underestimated in how they collide with adaptive, interactive and
encapsulated models. They stretch the boundaries of these management
models and challenge their viewpoint of collective action. The radical
innovation intent is severed by their limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, among the expected capabilities, the role of leadership,
top management and governance is stressed as being crucial. However, the
actual practice and implementation is rarely discussed in detail. The
different cases showed how management layers took an active role in
projects trajectories. Valuable practices were implemented ranging from
sensemaking, decision-making to sponsorship. These were meant to balance
the contradictions of exploration/exploitation trade-offs and the
results are partially successful and riddled by controversies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The icing condition detection case creates a critical tension between
its business environment legitimacy and BU strategy and Engineering
appropriation. Following the retirement of the R&amp;amp;T manager, the
researcher had relayed his idea of licensing the technology to an
external firm capable (adequate cost-structure) to develop and
industrialize it for small aircrafts. This move would be a means to
actually set a foot on the aviation market, make a case for it before
fully demonstrating its usefulness for heavier aircrafts enhancing
flight safety. Again, such emergent strategy would be possible by fully
considering separation nor balance of both, as they explore and exploit
interconnected fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ignoring-organization-design-and-its-engineering-design-mirror&#34;&gt;Ignoring organization design and its engineering design mirror&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizational ambidexterity had highlighted ways of structuring the
balancing of exploration/exploitation adding different typologies on how
to sustain a competitive advantage. Oddly, separating it in space, time
or leaving it in context, brings some organization design into play but
only by sketching the organic dimension of it. For example, the
centralization of ADT at the group level or creation of a standalone R&amp;amp;T
team are fully prescribed. It still leaves numerous ties among members
with exploitation activities and extended environment constraints.
However the black-boxing of generative practices into these organic
systems ignores the risks associated with the potential need for
reconfiguration of stakeholders ties. Thus, the dynamics induced by
design practices require, not only a partial-mirroring by organizations,
but rather a mirroring dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, the required adjustments, in terms of engineering
capabilities to engineer a seat platform architecture, require a
mirroring organization (Colfer and Baldwin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Colfer2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;). The
change is not addressed within generative process and with &lt;em&gt;integrators&lt;/em&gt;
contributing to &lt;em&gt;interdependence shift&lt;/em&gt; (Stan and Puranam

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Stan2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;). The managers in charge of the projects were
acting as integrators. In the case of the seat platform, they a priori
managed to articulate the integration for the Engineering Department and
were later called back for further support. The same goes for ADT:
numerous sessions were organized during the exploration but also after
concept selection to follow up and adapt the preliminary designs trying
to facilitate the integration. As specified in the limitations section
(Stan and Puranam 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Stan2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;, 1058):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A significant weakness of this study is that it does not provide direct evidence for the micro-mechanisms of how integrators help to cope with interdependence shifts—only that they do (and that these effects are visible even at intermediate performance stages).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of a triple-loop of organizational learning (Leifer and
Steinert 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Leifer2011&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;; McClory, Read, and Labib

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-McClory2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;), and the regenerative capabilities point in
that direction. But as they engage in a recursive pattern, as discussed
in the literature review, it appears crucial in the case studies to
frame the organization of collective action with practices that are
tightly linked to generative processes. In a more successful way, the
icing conditions detection case shows how future exploitation
constraints (regulation and norms) are shaped to support the technology
search and selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;specifying-requirements-for-a-new-model-of-ambidexterity&#34;&gt;Specifying requirements for a new model of ambidexterity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to our research questions (p.), we have stressed how
organizational ambidexterity can severe radical innovation practices
embodied by different generative processes. One could say that it is the
fault of organizational culture, but we have pointed in ZA’s
presentation (see p.), there are no signs of bad intentions raising
barriers again these radical innovation in the cases presentation and
results. Several practices and management tools were used to circulate
emergent value among stakeholders, including collective decision and
co-design workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, our first assumption would be to put the emphasis on the
micro-foundations. The nuts and bolts of generative processes and
interactions with value management, action and decision-making would be
absolutely critical to embody ambidextrous management. It fits the
behavioural foundations of March’s agenda (Gavetti, Levinthal, and
Ocasio 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gavetti2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;) and it lies at the crossroads of design
theory and reasoning which can be understood as science extending
H.Simon’s work (Simon 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Simon1996&#34;&gt;1996&lt;/a&gt;; Hatchuel

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2001a&#34;&gt;2001&lt;/a&gt;). Considering everyone as a designer in its
own way and practice, generating actions, interacting with other
(silent) designers and artefacts, could be a means to think of
generative processes among all of these organs and processes, which call
for a meta-process such as metabolism (Hatchuel, Weil, and Le Masson

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;; Segrestin et al. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Segrestin2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Among our descriptors, we could then propose to consider what could be
explained by a metabolism. We consequently need to target what
contributes to such phenomenon that is neither structure nor traditional
process. Deriving from our observed and justified anomalies, we propose
to recentre organizational ambidexterity around decision-making by
bringing in the teachings of design theory at that level as well as
organizational design. We would then embed some sort hacking of the
constraints and biases induced by exploitation/exploration non-mutual
conditioning. Moreover, it will bring a dynamic mirroring hypothesis as
a means to reflect the organizational change supporting the generative
engineering design.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;generative-process-and-ambidexterity-micro-foundations&#34;&gt;Generative process and ambidexterity micro-foundations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the beginning of our literature review up to the cases analyses, we
have discussed the course of action, decision-making and generative
processes. We have justified how organization ambidexterity can kill
sustained innovation management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we have to come back to foundations of the exploration versus
exploitation model whilst also keeping in mind the limitations and
perspectives identified in the interactive and encapsulated models.
The model’s extension we propose to address in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/&#34;&gt;following part&lt;/a&gt;, should then almost start from a similar reasoning introduced in the
foundational paper (March 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;). However, the
dichotomy of exploration and exploitation should be fully revisited by
considering &lt;strong&gt;a mutual conditioning&lt;/strong&gt; of both regimes as it was sketched
by the practices highlighted in the projects’ trajectories.
The nature of problems, their (re-)formulation and solving should be
reworked around the uncertainty and unknown management. Decision and
problem management should be enhanced by generative processes. For
instance, in (Le Glatin, Le Masson, and Weil 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;)
(see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-leglatin2017a/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;, we associate the possibility to deliberately play around the
reversal of preferences to push decision-making into the unknown. We
have proposed to call such pattern &lt;strong&gt;decisional ambidexterity&lt;/strong&gt;.
Such practice should aim at identifying fixation effects and their
(epistemic) interdependencies. This &lt;strong&gt;technology of organizing&lt;/strong&gt; should
support creation of meaning, value management, engineering and a
baseline for coordination and collective action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;generative-processes-and-organization-design&#34;&gt;Generative processes and organization design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The free-floating of exploration projects, as they look for
organizational ties, should also think through the lens of design theory
and reasoning. The idea of design-oriented organization (Hatchuel, Weil,
and Le Masson 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;) already pointed in that
direction. We need to specify with more clarity the organization design,
as we have seen that assumptions of temporary organization or
project-based organization tend to hide the complexities of changing
engineering design briefs in exploration project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design theories and reasoning are usually discussed for products and
services, but one could consider the organization, its resources and
routines as concept-enabling-knowledge for design. So, the key
requirement of the model is to avoid black-boxing generative processes,
as we have seen they expand onto several management dimensions. We
should then put the emphasis on potential &lt;strong&gt;organization design
fixation&lt;/strong&gt; that are not naturally part of the engineering design
practice, nor traditional project management. These are usually
discussed in change (project) management and organizational change but
would probably benefit from richer synergies if embedded in actual
project management (Pollack 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Pollack2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;; Hornstein

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hornstein2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;).
Consequently, our &lt;strong&gt;model of mutual conditioning between exploration and
exploitation&lt;/strong&gt; should also aim at managing an organizational metabolism
necessary to sustain organization re-design as a necessary condition
supporting the innovation potential of attraction of - so far
black-boxed - generative processes in exploration project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thanks to the previous chapter, we were able to identify literature
models’ weaknesses and several hints given by the case studies. The
synthesis of results reveals, through tracking of generative processes
in projects trajectories, that there is in fact a conditioning managed
or left uncontrolled between exploration and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we propose to return to the micro-foundations of organizational
ambidexterity as generative processes interfere with several management
dimensions depending on their generativity. Some are indeed more or less
fixated by exploitation constraints, and some are actually actively used
to generate concepts. Therefore, focusing on the model of action,
decision-making and generative processes would be a means to specify how
managers, individual and (silent) designers should interact with such
constraints to manage the generativity of their practice embedded in
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the case studies results encourage to focus on the dynamics of
the mirroring hypothesis, as the generative processes may challenge to
some extent interdependencies that can be catastrophic to exploration
value and subsequent exploitation. Radical innovation fostered by
generative processes may indeed be fixated by organization design, thus
winking at bringing organization design as concept enabling knowledge
supporting product design practices. Change management could be then
brought at the level of product project management and the underlying
generative mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have a requirements baseline to continue our journey to
design a &lt;strong&gt;model of mutual conditioning between exploration and
exploitation&lt;/strong&gt;. We have new grounds extending the studied literature
models and reconnecting ambidexterity with its behavioural foundations
at the light of the teachings of design theory and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Ambrosini2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambrosini, Véronique, Cliff Bowman, and Nardine Collier. 2009. “Dynamic
Capabilities: An Exploration of How Firms Renew their Resource Base.”
&lt;em&gt;British Journal of Management&lt;/em&gt; 20 (SUPP. 1): S9–S24.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8551.2008.00610.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8551.2008.00610.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birkinshaw, Julian, and Kamini Gupta. 2013. “Clarifying the distinctive
contribution of ambidexterity to the field of organization studies.”
&lt;em&gt;The Academy of Management Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; 27 (4): 287–98.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Colfer2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colfer, Lyra J., and Carliss Y. Baldwin. 2016. “The mirroring
hypothesis: Theory, evidence, and exceptions.” &lt;em&gt;Industrial and Corporate
Change&lt;/em&gt; 25 (5): 709–38. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/icc/dtw027&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/icc/dtw027&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Dumas1989&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dumas, Angela, and Henry Mintzberg. 1989. “Managing Design Designing
Management.” &lt;em&gt;Design Management Journal (Former Series)&lt;/em&gt; 1 (1): 37–43.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1948-7169.1989.tb00519.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1948-7169.1989.tb00519.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Elmquist2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elmquist, Maria, and Pascal Le Masson. 2009. “The value of a ’failed’
R&amp;amp;D project: An emerging evaluation framework for building innovative
capabilities.” &lt;em&gt;R and D Management&lt;/em&gt; 39 (2): 136–52.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9310.2009.00546.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9310.2009.00546.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gavetti2007&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gavetti, Giovanni, Daniel A. Levinthal, and William Ocasio. 2007.
“Neo-Carnegie: The Carnegie school’s past, present, and reconstructing
for the future.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 18 (3): 523–36.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.1070.0277&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.1070.0277&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gupta2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gupta, Anil K, Ken G Smith, and Christina E Shalley. 2006. “The
Interplay Between Exploration and Exploitation.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management
Journal&lt;/em&gt; 49 (4): 693–706. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amj.2006.22083026&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amj.2006.22083026&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hatchuel2001a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatchuel, Armand. 2001. “Towards Design Theory and Expandable
Rationality: The Unfinished Program of Herbert Simon.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Management and Governance&lt;/em&gt; 5 (3-4): 260–73.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1014044305704&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1014044305704&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hatchuel2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatchuel, Armand, Benoît Weil, and Pascal Le Masson. 2006. “Building
innovation capabilities. The development of design-oriented
organizations.” In &lt;em&gt;Innovation, Learning and Macro Institutional Change:
Patterns of Knowledge Changes&lt;/em&gt;, edited by J T Hage, 1–26. Oxford,
England: Oxford University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hornstein2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hornstein, Henry A. 2015. “The integration of project management and
organizational change management is now a necessity.” &lt;em&gt;International
Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 33 (2): 291–98.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.08.005&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.08.005&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Glatin, Mario, Pascal Le Masson, and Benoît Weil. 2017. “Generative
action and preference reversal in exploratory project management.” &lt;em&gt;CERN
IdeaSquare Journal of Experimental Innovation&lt;/em&gt; 1 (2): 39–46.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Leifer2011&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leifer, Larry, and Martin Steinert. 2011. “Dancing with Ambiguity:
Causality Behavior, Design Thinking, and Triple-Loop-Learning.” In
&lt;em&gt;Management of the Fuzzy Front End of Innovation&lt;/em&gt;, 10:151–78. 1. Cham:
Springer International Publishing.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-01056-4_11&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-01056-4_11&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-March1991&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March, James G. 1991. “Exploration and exploitation in organizational
learning.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 2: 71–87.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-McClory2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McClory, Sue, Martin Read, and Ashraf Labib. 2017. “Conceptualising the
lessons-learned process in project management: Towards a triple-loop
learning framework.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 35
(7): 1322–35. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2017.05.006&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2017.05.006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Pollack2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pollack, Julien. 2017. “Change Management as an Organizational and
Project Capability.” In &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Handbook of Organizational Project
Management&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Shankar Sankaran, Ralf Muller, and Nathalie
Drouin, 236–49. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316662243.021&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316662243.021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Puranam2012a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puranam, Phanish, Marlo Raveendran, and Thorbjørn Knudsen. 2012.
“Organization Design: The Epistemic Interdependence Perspective.”
&lt;em&gt;Academy of Management Review&lt;/em&gt; 37 (3): 419–40.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2010.0535&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2010.0535&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Segrestin2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Segrestin, Blanche, Franck Aggeri, Albert David, and Pascal Le Masson.
2017. “Armand Hatchuel and the Refoundation of Management Research:
Design Theory and the Epistemology of Collective Action.” In &lt;em&gt;The
Palgrave Handbook of Organizational Change Thinkers&lt;/em&gt;, 1–15.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-49820-1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-49820-1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Simon1996&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon, Herbert A. 1996. &lt;em&gt;The sciences of the artificial&lt;/em&gt;. MIT press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Stan2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stan, Mihaela, and Phanish Puranam. 2017. “Organizational adaptation to
interdependence shifts: The role of integrator structures.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic
Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 38 (5): 1041–61. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.2546&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.2546&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
