<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 5 - Intervention and complementary testing | Mario LE GLATIN</title>
    <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Part 5 - Intervention and complementary testing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Part 5 - Intervention and complementary testing</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11 - Intervention and steering committee</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/chapter11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/chapter11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping up with our research agenda, now that we have validated our
model with two comparable case studies, we engage with the presentation
of how the researcher intervened in the firm to test &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; the model
of decisional ambidexterity. It allows us to further specify the
subtleties of the model and the management requirements revealed by the
mutual conditioning between exploration and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We show how the project trajectory was set and guided with design of
decisions constantly articulated with fixations and interdependencies so
that the engineering practice encapsulated in the project could be
largely grounded and supported by stakeholders. Furthermore, we exhibit
how this R&amp;amp;T funded project aiming for a potentially new product
embedding TRL6 technologies, managed its organizational ties to find
sufficient echoes inducing the regeneration of engineering capabilities
enabling future new product development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We come back on a management device we often referred to inter-BU cases
such as the Design Thinking cases, the Lower Deck and the Connected
Cabin. The Multi-BU committee, created in 2012 by a former CEO, was an
opportunity to foster top-down projects as well as some bottom-up
projects requiring strong sponsorship enabling corporate
entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not a case study comparable to others, as it cannot be identified
as project on its own. However, it is rather a &lt;em&gt;governance body for
radical innovation&lt;/em&gt;. This locus of innovation within the conglomerate of
SMEs can be analysed through the lens of decisional ambidexterity and we
propose to specify some of its characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter further tests our model of decisional ambidexterity and
continues justifying its validity to extend models of ambidexterity and
exploration project management presented in the literature review. These
series of arguments provide us strong foundations to go into the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/chapter12/&#34;&gt;following chapter&lt;/a&gt;
where we present the researcher’s contribution to the quality
management system for &lt;em&gt;Design and Develop&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Innovation&lt;/em&gt; processes
(EN9100).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the first section, we start by presenting one of the researcher’s
intervention at Zodiac Oxygen Systems Europe for a funded exploration on
hypoxia protection device for pilots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second section, we give more detail on the Multi-BU management
with respect to decisional ambidexterity. It is not an intervention but
it clearly shows the importance of heuristics at work to design
decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hypoxia-probing-and-structuring-the-ecosystem-interdependencies&#34;&gt;Hypoxia: probing and structuring the ecosystem interdependencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case presentation (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#hypoxia-protection---researchers-intervention&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;) gave a first global picture of the project’s
trajectory and context. The specificity of this case is that the
researcher actively participated to the project on the R&amp;amp;T manager’s
request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, we propose to present what was specifically done to implement
heuristics of decisional ambidexterity and its induced effects. We
picture the trajectory with the global descriptors in Figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:HypoxiaTraj&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:HypoxiaTraj&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;,
as well as the phenomena relative to model of coordination and
collective action, and its innovation potential of attraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organizational-context-and-project-target&#34;&gt;Organizational context and project target&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zodiac Oxygen Systems Europe (ZOSE), whose Engineering and Product
Development board is common with its twin sister BU in the United States
(ZOSU) is one of the two market leaders in pilot, cabin crew and
passenger oxygen masks in addition to oxygen tanks. In the past decades,
with ageing patents, an increase of replacement parts providers with an
&lt;em&gt;Parts Manufacturer Approval&lt;/em&gt; (PMA), the risk of obsolescence and market
share losses became higher to the point that Engineering Director
included it in its roadmap and practices the necessity to think of
market regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of ZOSE flagship product, EROS mask (see Figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:EROSmask&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:EROSmask&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;
below) along with an equivalent product offered by the competition (B/E
Aerospace), are provided to aircraft manufacturers on catalogue. They
are issued with a TSO (Technical Standard Order) that allows to certify
a piece of equipment with sufficient autonomy over the aircraft
manufacturer. It induces then several design rules with associated
qualification standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equipment was originally developed upon transferred and licensed
technologies from the US to support equipment design and supply for
Dassault (Darrieulat 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Darrieulat1993&#34;&gt;1993&lt;/a&gt;). Later, in the 1960s,
the engineering department developed its own capabilities and winning
its contracts on its own. In a pure entrepreneurial spirit, Georges
Gutman, then development engineer, created a oxygen regulator solving
several limitations such as having oxygen on demand, making breathing
more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-eros-pilot-oxygen-mas&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/EROSmask.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;EROS Pilot Oxygen mas&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/EROSmask.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    EROS Pilot Oxygen mas
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improvements were made including the innovation of having an
expandable/retractable harness to adjust with the single push of a
button the mask to any face whilst guaranteeing a perfect fit and air
tightness. Smoke and fire protection with fogging prevention were also
developed with a fixed or removable lens attached on the oro-nasal
piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given a historical and established dominant design, market players have
put on the top of their priorities the urgency of reinforcing safety and
preparing for the unexpected with new designs. Indeed, several threats
of obsolescence due to ageing patents had been identified, and the
aviation ecosystem was concerned by some isolated cases of hypoxia&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,
usually due to other equipment failure. A CleanSky2 project, with Airbus
as partner, made a call for proposal considering the new safety
regulation requiring extended mask wear whenever a pilot is alone on
duty in the cockpit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was then a proposal to rethink the ergonomics and features of the
oxygen mask for this new restrictive requirement. Indeed, several
feedback had pointed out that pilots were not following the rule because
of the discomfort caused by the mask on their face. However, ensuring a
pilot safety, whilst alone in a cockpit, is a first step before removing
the copilot position. The flight engineer was removed several decades
ago, so it appears to think of one-man cockpit before even examine
unmanned commercial aircrafts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-trajectory&#34;&gt;Project trajectory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As explained in the case presentation (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#hypoxia-protection---researchers-intervention&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;), the researcher had first
proposed a C-K mapping of the Open Innovation Challenge in order to
position the proposed concepts relatively to the dominant design. And,
as he was familiar with the R&amp;amp;T manager who was first in charge of the
project, he was requested to support their exploration and their
methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had already been working for 6 months on the project. Several
brainstorming sessions, workshops with industrial designers were held
and digital mock-ups had been generated. However, they were confronted
with a dilemma. They were expected to provide a product concept to
Airbus: a product requirement had been issued largely inspired by the
general pilot oxygen mask but with some changed words calling for
innovative design. For instance, the word &lt;em&gt;mask&lt;/em&gt; was replaced by
&lt;em&gt;device&lt;/em&gt;, the adjective &lt;em&gt;disruptive&lt;/em&gt; had been added on some
requirements, and they also referred to a future cockpit without clearly
specifying its characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher supported them in clustering their previously generated
concepts, and in creating meaning around new product categories. The
clustering was eased by the use of C-K theory. But, more importantly,
the researcher insisted on the team’s ability to discuss the future
decision of committing to a product design and development. So, the
interactions with the client should explicitly rely on the extent of
their design effort provided and their capabilities, as well as the
necessity to discuss fixations and interdependencies. They were
encouraged to present the design method, the clustering and how they
made sense of the uncertainties and the unknown surrounding the
ill-defined problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:HypoxiaTraj&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:HypoxiaTraj&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;
below shows the trajectory of the project. Initially, the concept could
have been simply an extreme optimization ($d^+$) of the existing mask.
It was a simple and easy way to identify action necessary for legacy
products. It would allow anchoring to the dominant design and
established product roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The necessity of wearing the mask for extended periods of time actually
ensures that before an actual emergency, the pilot is wearing the mask
in a standby mode, so the researcher pushed forward the nuance of
prevention to counterbalance the emergency mode. It created a category
discriminant to make sense of the generated concepts through
brainstormings and industrial design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, it allowed to consider two other concepts to decide that
would fall under genericity ($d^{gen}$) and alternative situation
($d^{alt}$) as they wished for an evolving regulation where the nuance
between prevention and emergency is specified. Finally, since the future
cockpit is yet undefined, the potential threat of a guaranteed air tight
cockpit would make oxygen mask pointless ($d^*$)? Furthermore, without
fully exploring such disruption, they took into account nearby equipment
that could be integrated with the oxygen device ($d^{alt}$).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the designed decisions where mapped through C-K with the project
team input, and iteratively discussed so that they would gain in
familiarity with the model. The researcher also encouraged to come up
with means of avoiding isolation of the project within the engineering
department. The project manager also repeatedly came to ask specific
questions to the researcher at the beginning as the heuristics were not
made clear enough; so some short sessions were quite randomly set at the
beginning with him and his lead engineer, to give some guidance to think
of the different decisions categories and the required engineering
design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following subsections, we offer more detail on the benefits of
decisional ambidexterity and its practice through the researcher’s
intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-conservative-client-asking-for-radical-innovation&#34;&gt;A conservative client asking for radical innovation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;paradoxical-request&#34;&gt;Paradoxical request&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stated that the team was facing a dilemma when the researcher was
called. The request made by the client was a mix of encouraged
innovative design, but at the same time heavily constrained by mimetic
requirements from existing dominant design. It created a lot of
confusion and they were quite lost on ranking critical to quality
requirements. They also doubted on the client for knowing what they were
expecting from the product design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The request was already ambidextrous in itself but perhaps in the wrong
way as it was prescribed in an almost client-supplier relationship
(Airbus to ZOSE). The team had the expectation that Airbus knew their
need, and symmetrically ZOSE would engineer whatever is physically
possible as long as it sustains and extends the product line. Reaching
out for methodical innovative design, managed value management and
project-based concern for engineering capabilities are clearly
formulated despite being an open-ended exploration project funded by
CleanSky2 program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where decisional ambidexterity can help specifying the nuances
between pure exploitation (prescription, engineering and development)
and exploration. Decisional ambidexterity overcomes paradoxical tension
of non-mutual conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;exploiting-for-exploration&#34;&gt;Exploiting for exploration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of C-K theory, having such specified dominant
design makes it easier to build the rest of the concepts. So, the
researcher did it whilst also re-using some of the mapping made for Open
Innovation Challenge. The researcher then encouraged the project members
to anchor the value of the generated concept to established requirement
by specifying the distant and its nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It allowed to make a design document presenting three main concepts
categories, with a digital mock-up each, stressing how they came about
these options. The researcher had insisted on the necessity to explain
their method, their line of thought and its decision parameters so that
they could better discuss underlying hypotheses that Airbus may be
deliberately or not hiding: interactions with other projects, cockpit
elements, physical constraints, or just a vision for their future
cockpit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has also forced Airbus to be more specific and answer questions that
they did not expected to. For example, several debates gravitated around
the head clearance (i.e. distance between the cockpit sealing and
pilot’s head top) as some design features encouraged the use of
surrounding space for prevention. The concepts considering the
integration with other cockpit elements such as the seat (engineering
knowledge and capability exist at Zodiac Seats France), forced Airbus to
solicit FAA/EASA to start thinking carefully about potential evolution
of regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;opening-the-project-routines-to-the-organization&#34;&gt;Opening the project routines to the organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;stress-tested-proof-of-concepts&#34;&gt;Stress-tested proof of concepts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept categories presented and the design method were really
helpful in discussing the unknown fraction of the project, but also key
to articulate the interdependencies of the future product and
technologies. Due to the nature of the requirements demanded by the
client, several interdependencies could have been easily challenged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the project manager’s support, the researcher encouraged the need
to specify ripples caused by different generated features. The purpose
was to find knowledge interactions and conjunctions triggered by the
designed decisions. The manager organized open weekly meetings inviting
several representatives from quality, purchasing, testing, prototyping,
repair shop and other engineering sub-units. The aim of these sessions
was to identify fixations held by these sub-organizations and the
interdependent ties maintained by their engineering or management
practices. Consequently, the project team was able to specify further
the different concept categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;looking-for-organizational-echoes&#34;&gt;Looking for organizational echoes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the most stimulating side-effect of this practice was not
the manoeuvre of the project trajectory to provide a well-defined and
methodological approach to the client to co-explore the unknown. It was
the reflexion of these practices in BU sub-organizations. The
interactions organized around decision parameters, product design
features and requirements were the occasion to regenerate their
capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Engineering Director launched several side mini-projects within some
of his engineering units to address radical changes in product
architecture. These have proven the technical feasibility of some
features envisioned in the decision categories, and some opened new
perspectives for product lines. For example, the air regulator has
always been integrated in the oro-nasal piece because of pressure losses
between the system and mouth/nose. Distancing the regulator through a
hose was unimaginable however interactions during the open-meetings to
update and consult BU stakeholders and prototyping allowed reconsidering
its engineering and interfaces between sub-units. It also invited them
to think of product systems and cockpit integration differently, and
opened possibilities to change the engineering organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, despite having been made fun of at the beginning of the
project by other BU members, some of the originally generated concepts
were indeed seen as coming out of the blue. These concepts were in the
end grounded with exploitation regime and the distance created by
exploration was sustained by knowledge identification, generation, and
initiated organizational, generative learning and change. Decisional
ambidexterity helped stimulating organizational metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-from-decisional-tension-to-satisfy-requirements-to-organizational-echoes&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/HypoxiaTraj.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;From decisional tension to satisfy requirements to organizational echoes&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/HypoxiaTraj.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    From decisional tension to satisfy requirements to organizational echoes
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;decisional-ambidexterity-analysis&#34;&gt;Decisional ambidexterity analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-mutual conditioning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mutual conditioning&lt;/strong&gt; extended model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Originally, the project was organized in a non-mutual conditioning fashion. An upstream and isolated project from exploitation regime.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The research-intervention with a practice of decisional ambidexterityemphasized the absolute necessity to make explicit reference to exploitation parameters to generate alternatives and design concepts into the unknown. The project team mirrored the patterns with client and BU departments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The first sessions aiming at framing the scope and generating concepts were conducted without a clear conditioning with exploitation regime. The direction of search and generativity was ambiguous and encourage the R&amp;amp;T manager to look for methodological advice.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Decision ambidexterity was practiced with clustering of concepts through C-K theory, definition of decision categories. It helped framing previously generated concepts and organize further exploration based on exploitation features and hacking constraints.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;At first, the exploration environment was defined by Airbus with a paradoxical and ill-defined problem. Several issues relative to certification, and acceptation by pilots but struggled in formulating concepts to the client.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Decisional ambidexterity practice allowed clarifying means of collective action to gradually uncover unknown environments (certification evolution, client needs, system integrations) since they addressed the nature and importance of interdependencies (head clearance, prevention/emergency, seat and cockpit, etc.).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;At first, the project was isolated from the rest of the BU and could have been kept out of product development portfolio even to a point of creating a new product line. This risk of incoherence for the BU competencies and market segmentation was sensed by the R&amp;amp;T manager who was more inclined to regenerate.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Working on the mutual conditioning of exploration by exploitation parameters helped organizing learning and disentangling interdependencies, and organization design fixations. For instance, the air regulator is integrated in the oro-nasal piece, and both are mirrored two engineering sub-units working tightly. Questioning it through the designed alternatives, opening the project to stakeholders, and prototyping, facilitated the launch of an internal side project to think of how it could be made and integrated differently. It encouraged to work other engineering interdependencies with other engineering sub-units.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mbu-committees-a-steering-committee-looking-for-purpose&#34;&gt;MBU Committees: a steering committee looking for purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Multi-BU committee was established by the ExCom to launch top-down
projects as well as to offer a place for bottom-up initiatives. It was
created in 2012 hosting to steer key projects whose strategic interest
was acknowledged by the ExCom. For instance, the fuel cell development
was initiated by the former CEO as the greener aircraft initiative
became more and more important in the aviation sector. A project team
was constituted and hosted by Zodiac Oxygen Systems Europe as a
potential growth driver and technology transfers. The project aimed at
developing the technology for aircraft use with the promise of having
multiple sources to be reuse across the aircraft (electrical power,
water and heating). The project was conducted in partnership with two
aircraft manufacturers and funded by European programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MBU committee also hosted numerous other projects that would call
less for a new BU, but rather insist on inter-BU collaboration; others
were rather intra-BU bearing a strategic interest as it was developing a
&lt;em&gt;game-changing&lt;/em&gt; technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we explain, in the case presentation (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#multiBU-committee&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;), the committee with its
quarterly meetings was a locus of innovation to give a chance to
entrepreneurial spirit&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    We propose to discuss some features of this MBU activity at the light of
decisional ambidexterity, since it hosted several projects we have
discussed previously such as the Lower Deck and the Connected Cabin. We
specify the nature of the discussions held in these meetings, the impact
of project’s trajectory and how it relates to decision-designing.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organizational-context-and-ecosystem&#34;&gt;Organizational context and ecosystem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, it is important to understand that the MBU committee was
set at a time when the homogenization of the conglomerate of SMEs was
barely starting. The re-branding of business units was starting and the
rate of mergers &amp;amp; acquisitions was diminishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The business units were exploiting their respective niches, and ZA as a
group already covered a wide range of equipment and systems across the
aircraft. The former CEO as well as other ExCom members, are all
engineers and have a propensity for technical discussions. Niches were
segregated with a variety of technologies, with high entry barriers. BU
managers and the ExCom helped identifying M&amp;amp;A targets to be the first
entrant to gain a strong foothold on these markets. The pattern had been
reproduced across all existing ZA market segments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ExCom, as reported by the former CEO, wanted to leave a strong
responsibility at each BU level, with Profits &amp;amp; Losses reporting, a
certain financial autonomy with a holding consolidation. They avoided
imposing projects to BUs. The MBU committee was then a means to drive
exploration for BUs through technological development. Some technical
barriers (engineering, certification, market interest, supply chain,
etc.) would be extensively studied so that one or several BUs would take
it onboard. If necessary they arbitrate on the project’s allocation
depending on how the ExCom judges the BU capacity to sustain the
development. The former CEO also saw the MBU as a management device to
overcome the limited &lt;em&gt;bandwidth&lt;/em&gt; of BU and Divisions managers. It is
also the role of branch executives (ExCom members) to seize and support
these initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;managing-exploration-added-value-for-the-conglomerate&#34;&gt;Managing exploration added value for the conglomerate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The committee was a locus for discussion, where top management met with
middle management, engineers, designers and marketers. All ExCom members
were former engineers, including middle management and BU managers. As
confirmed by the former CEO, he encouraged debate on the quality of
models and input data used to make decisions on the technologies,
products to be developed. The VP of Business Development and Strategy
would usually question the Intellectual Property and aircraft
manufacturers’ risk of claiming primacy. The former group CEO and branch
CEOs would dig into the details of the project, questioning engineering
topics, partnerships, competition, market shares, suppliers and
potential launch customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever they felt the model was stress-tested enough given their
knowledge on the topic or insight they had from their interactions with
other executives inside/outside the firm, they would delegate the
responsibility to the BU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages-conditions-and-limitations---former-ceos-feedback-to-the-researcher&#34;&gt;Advantages, conditions and limitations - former CEO’s feedback to the researcher&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the limitations we can find in the MBU device, some can be seen by
reflecting on the difference between two cases such as the Connected
Cabin and the Lower Deck. These two show that despite benefiting from
the same context, they did not hold similar results. Of course we could
go on listing numerous reasons, but they were treated alike during MBU
and additional ExCom meetings. In other words, the same discussion on
hypotheses, input data and modelling was heavily challenged by board
members. Such pattern has been reported for executives not familiar with
topics (Loch, Mähring, and Sommer 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Loch2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;), but here, the
ExCom is made exclusively of engineers who have cultivated over their
careers a deep interest for technologies and applied sciences. They also
have market and ecosystem knowledge through other firm’s corporate
governance participation and external networks (consortia, group of
industrial partners, conferences, etc.). For example, the former CEO had
good knowledge for both topics before they were launched as actual
projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the lower deck, he was aware of the decline of the air freight
and its share in commercial cargo area. He was already convinced by
the market interest and value for airline yield management, to the
point that when the results of the market study were presented, he
cut through the presentation to address technical and engineering
issues. He would be more interested in securing the concept on that
issue to gain autonomy from aircraft manufacturer and raise the
entry barrier as they knew competition (B/E Aerospace) had been
consulted for a similar project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the connected cabin, he challenged a lot the value proposition
as he was asking for proof of legitimacy for ZA to organize such
service market platform. In an interview in May 2018, a year after
the AIX 2017, he told the researcher he tried to encourage Zodiac
Data Systems BU manager to develop a technological advantage
securing the nascent market. It was another way of scouting for
different scenarios and testing the fixations of different BUs as
well as interdependent engineered product between BUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having same discussion goals to &lt;em&gt;define what makes rationality&lt;/em&gt;
collectively with project representatives and potential stakeholders, it
appears that the steering committee could benefit from a technology of
organizing, by opposition to &lt;em&gt;fostering a culture of curiosity and sound
debate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to sustain innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears then that several conditions can only be surfaced through
engineering design, project-based management and change management and
its active management around a model such as decisional ambidexterity.
Interactions and networking are not sufficient. Indeed, the former CEO
recognized the interest of having a practice to specify the model
testing, rationality testing practice on countless occasions. He was
very receptive to the decisional ambidexterity model and even felt it
was natural. The formalization is a real plus for a set of heuristics
that may not be acknowledged by everyone. Otherwise, he believes that it
is a widespread practice which counters procedural practices fixating
rationality. He also insisted on the danger of such mechanistic models
of thought (e.g. rational choice theory, operations research) which can
be the best way to go to the wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis-a-reconciliatory-model-for-ambidexterity&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis: a reconciliatory model for ambidexterity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We show in this chapter how the researcher intervened in a project to
seed decisional ambidexterity. It reveals the significance to understand
the practice of design reasoning, modelling and formalization to discuss
the potential decisions and its categories. Coming back to the Multi-BU
committee we referred to in previous chapters, we also reveal how some
behaviours and practices relate to decisional ambidexterity and how it
could further benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher specified several different heuristics and supported the
team to effectively address the decision-design to address the
difficulty faced when dealing with a paradoxical request putting in
tension exploitation regime and exploration incentives. The work
conducted with them allowed to translate the engineering design work
with its mirroring for client relationship management, product
integration and internal engineering capabilities and organization
design. The methodological approach constantly addressed the mirroring
dynamics of the unknown in order to support generative learning and
capabilities regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Multi-BU committee with the heuristics and culture fostered by the
ExCom can be considered from the perspective of decisional
ambidexterity. It wasn’t a decision meeting place, but rather networking
(Christiansen and Varnes &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Christiansen2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;). However, this
networking benefited some systematic debate on the modelling,
hypothesis, problem formulation and value management. It allowed to
sustain a culture of curiosity and generative learning developing
vigilance for project management. But, we also point out that the
debates held in these meetings could also have benefited from a
technology of organization where decision-design could have been better
structured. For instance, we would have helped to systematically address
the interactions and the disentanglement of interdependencies in order
to overcome (organization) fixations effects rising from the
conglomerate of SMEs sustaining their respective niche markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in this chapter we have given further proof that the model of
decisional ambidexterity helps in managing the mutual conditioning
between exploration and exploitation, supporting decision-making in the
unknown for innovative design and interrelated change management.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Christiansen2007&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christiansen, John K., and Claus J. Varnes. 2007. “Making decisions on
innovation: Meetings or networks?” &lt;em&gt;Creativity and Innovation
Management&lt;/em&gt; 16 (3): 282–98.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8691.2007.00441.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8691.2007.00441.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Darrieulat1993&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darrieulat, Olivier. 1993. “Intertechnique : un sous-traitant
indépendant.” &lt;em&gt;Histoire, économie &amp;amp; Société&lt;/em&gt; 12 (1): 137–63.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Loch2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loch, Christoph, Magnus Mähring, and Svenja Sommer. 2017. “Supervising
Projects You Don’t (Fully) Understand.” &lt;em&gt;California Management Review&lt;/em&gt;
59 (2): 45–67. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0008125617697944&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0008125617697944&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See for instance Helios Airways Flight 522 &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among ZA values, Entrepreneurship is put to the fore in order to
honour the historical fits of engineering of several engineers and
managers, but also to cultivate it. As it is usually acknowledged
among managers, people will be given the occasion to pitch their
concepts and given the opportunity to demonstrate its value for the
firm &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words in italic are extract of the former CEO’s interview
conducted on September 4, 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 12 - Validation by peers: quality management system contributions</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/chapter12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/chapter12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The heart of a good work is a puzzle and an idea.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Andrew Abbott&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapters, we have given further proof of the usefulness
of a model of mutual causality between exploration and exploitation:
decisional ambidexterity. The role of decision-designers and the
technology of organizing are sustained by interactions with the
decision-design in the unknown, mapping, categorizing oriented towards
by interdependencies and fixation effects. We have also sketched by
contrast the usefulness of having an engineering-oriented approach to
it: considering methodological approaches and objects to effectively
organize collective action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present in this chapter several other contributions of the researcher
to adapt process management and existing R&amp;amp;T and Innovation practices in
Zodiac Aerospace. The initiative was part of a global program on Quality
Management System and for Operational Excellence following issues
encountered by a few BUs. The CTO was the process leader for &lt;em&gt;Design &amp;amp;
Develop&lt;/em&gt;, a key process for &lt;em&gt;Program Management&lt;/em&gt;. He fought to have an
&lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt; process, which finally was allocated by the Chief Operations
Officer despite not being directly linked with operations in the short
term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an occasion to reinforce the value of innovation practices as
potential contributor and enhancer to operational issues. In other
words, we can think that operational issues faced in manufacturing
engineering and quality engineering, can be rooted in design choices.
This processual view can then be seen as an occasion to work around the
mutual causality between exploration and exploitation, instead of only
separating an innovation process and management as a totally isolated
regime compared to other organizational concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram below
(Fig.&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:globalZAOS&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:globalZAOS&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;)
gives a global picture of the 3 main pillars (Drive, Execute, and
Support).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zodiac-aerospace-operational-system-3-main-pillars-sustained-by-13-major-processes&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/globalZAOS.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Zodiac Aerospace Operational System: 3 main pillars sustained by 13 major processes&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/globalZAOS.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Zodiac Aerospace Operational System: 3 main pillars sustained by 13 major processes
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the first section, we start by presenting the procedures written for
the ZAOS with the researcher’s contributions. They cover the &lt;em&gt;Design &amp;amp;
Develop&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt; processes. The first defines a traditional new
product development, a representation of an exploitation regime, with a
strong influence from the optimization of project management. The second
process is then seen as upstream, and the researcher tried to distil it
in the model of decisional ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we discuss the feedback gained from several R&amp;amp;T managers community
workshops where the procedures were reviewed and where the researcher
had the occasion to discuss his model of decisional ambidexterity.
Similarly to the ZAOS procedures, these contributions show the issues of
surfacing an organizational metabolism against the duality of processes
and structure.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;group-procedures-design--develop-and-innovate&#34;&gt;Group procedures: Design &amp;amp; Develop and Innovate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following some quality and delay issues, corporate teams had launched
programs of &lt;em&gt;operational excellence&lt;/em&gt; across the group. Originally, it
was formalized in key requirements for operations (supply chain,
manufacturing, industrialization, customer management). Later, it was
formalized into an update of the quality management system to prescribe
a set of key principles and procedures. The movement initiated for
critical process then moved &amp;ldquo;upstream&amp;rdquo; to tackle &lt;em&gt;Design &amp;amp; Develop&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher had first participated to the &lt;em&gt;Program Management&lt;/em&gt;
procedures writing to identify how R&amp;amp;T activities could be articulated
(TRL assessment for risk management, technology acquisition and
integration and multi-BU projects). Then, an even more active
contribution was made to &lt;em&gt;Design &amp;amp; Develop&lt;/em&gt;. It was an occasion to
contribute and gain sufficient knowledge on exploitation regime.
Consequently, it helped formulate proposals for management devices
instilled by decisional ambidexterity in &lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt; procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We present the linear view of designing and developing products in the
ZAOS. It is part of a more global processual perspective of the
exploitation regime that tries to avoid referring to organization
structures. Innovation is then placed as an upstream process, we discuss
its interface and assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we show the &lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt; procedure and how the researcher tried
accommodating decisional ambidexterity by introducing the governance
construct for road-mapping activities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;design--development-procedures&#34;&gt;Design &amp;amp; Development procedures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the figure below, we present the overall process of &lt;em&gt;Develop &amp;amp;
Sustain&lt;/em&gt; with inputs/outputs from other processes, as well as suppliers
and customers of different processes: Design &amp;amp; Develop, Perform
industrialization, Perform maintainability engineering for repair, and
Maintain continued airworthiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall perspective of designing and developing makes several
assumptions on the linearity of the process. Customer have need, voiced
to the business unit through bidding teams and programs framing the
undertaking waterfalled to different underlying processes (see
figure.&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:globalZAOS&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:globalZAOS&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;).
As we see below in
Figure.&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:DesignDevelopProcessCard&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:DesignDevelopProcessCard&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;,
the suppliers/customers in bold purple letters are other processes
providing and expecting actions and deliverables (note: circular
references are possible because of iterations).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zaos---design--develop-process-card-sipoc-view---supplier-input-process-output-customer&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/DesignDevelopProcessCard.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;ZAOS - Design &amp;amp; Develop process card (SIPOC view - Supplier Input Process Output Customer)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/DesignDevelopProcessCard.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    ZAOS - Design &amp;amp; Develop process card (SIPOC view - Supplier Input Process Output Customer)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given several inputs and interactions with other processes,
responsibility, accountability, support, consultation and information
are distributed among functional activities (jobs), with some overlap,
interactions but with a global movement forward, the sub-processes are
the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create Technical Proposal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyse Customer Needs &amp;amp; Capture Requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perform Preliminary Design Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create Detailed Design Data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perform Verification and Qualification&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obtain or Support Certification&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configuration Management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exploitation regime is heavily dependent on the client’s demand and
makes the assumption the client knows to some extent how to formulate
requirements to a congruent business unit (bidding and engineering team)
capable to discuss and support in the formulation of engineering
specifications and rules to conduct product development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous debates during writing workshops (for program management,
develop &amp;amp; sustain, as well as innovation) took place because of
differences in organization design. The struggle was hard to adopt the
view of the quality management system which enforces a strong processual
view. The process should be high-level enough to be transposable between
business units. The compromise found to avoid specificities was to add
some depth to the processes for organizations to better identify with
maturity matrices.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zaos---design--develop-sequential-view&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/RTinterfaceProc.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;ZAOS - Design &amp;amp; Develop sequential view&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/RTinterfaceProc.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    ZAOS - Design &amp;amp; Develop sequential view
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;project-based-management-principles&#34;&gt;Project-based management principles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project management principles are induced by the framing and management
of overarching programs. They impose the breakdown of the activities in
work packages supported by team. Resources are picked among whatever
organization is in place following the matrix-form (Galbraith

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Galbraith1971&#34;&gt;1971&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources are allocated depending on customer requirements and derived
specifications. What is rather surprising in the writing of these
activities and responsibilities is the implicit reference to the
necessary competencies and capabilities to continuously be able to
develop new products and cope with adaptation to change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;rt-and-innovation-interface&#34;&gt;R&amp;amp;T and Innovation interface&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see in the previous figure, they have linearized the R&amp;amp;T
activities, through the TRL assessment (Mankins

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Mankins2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;). It corresponds to a stage-gate equivalent
(Cooper 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Cooper2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;). Of course, such linear and adaptive
view is more appropriate for incremental innovation. Product development
and engineering refers to a pool of technologies capable of being
integrated as the TRL freezes the integration environment to measure the
technology maturation. So, if the engineering rules for products remain
stable enough and that these are made clear, it can be considered that
maturity assessment will filter and perhaps bring adjustments to
technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, when it comes to major innovations initiatives, they would
originate from another process that necessarily challenges or even
by-passes traditional adaptive and maturation processes. From the
researcher’s viewpoint and as discussed on multiple occasions with the
CTO, the quality management system had to sanctuarise these processes in
&lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt;. Indeed, &lt;em&gt;Design &amp;amp; Develop&lt;/em&gt; restricts its scope to a
traditional exploitation regime with its lot of hypotheses on nature of
risks, certainties, fixations and marginal correction of biases &amp;amp;
heuristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The structure of the ZAOS, with the cross-referencing of processes of
different nature, forces to build coherence between them as well as
delimiting their perimeter. The scope and the risk of leaving activities
unmanaged was taken care of by the ZAOS project team. On some occasions,
it was also circumvented by using maturity matrices to provide
additional detail on how activities can be conducted with underlying
competencies and capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &lt;em&gt;Design &amp;amp; Develop&lt;/em&gt; describes the exploitation regime fed by
some optimizations that can be decided as they improve product design &amp;amp;
development with technologies capable of being integrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the decisional ambidexterity perspective, it provides enough ground
to envision designing decisions capable of changing products, their
development and required capability. Since, we face a traditional model
of ambidexterity, decisional ambidexterity model is bound to be upstream
but encourage to disentangle fixations effects and interdependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;innovate-procedures&#34;&gt;Innovate procedures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt; process was the last in being written in the ZAOS
program. Some place had been made already for incremental innovation
with more traditional R&amp;amp;T activities focusing on technology maturation
made available to product development and program management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A preliminary round between the CTO, his North America delegate, the
Intellectual Property director, and the PhD Candidate was organized to
provide an overall framing. This original draft helped giving some
directions to the writing workshop participants. The main issue was
defining whether or not the process should consider product design and
innovation, in addition to technologies. And more common to other
processes in the ZAOS, sub-processes and topics were reallocated and
articulated differently under the umbrella of the agreed main processes
after several iterations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define, Implement and Maintain Product &amp;amp; Technology Road maps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manage Research &amp;amp; Technology Projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manage patents and create patent landscape&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt; complements what exploitation doesn’t cover. In other words,
it feeds exploration regime. It is regarded &lt;em&gt;upstream&lt;/em&gt; to provide
technologies to improve continuously product along its roadmap. However,
the group quickly insisted on approaching the subject with additional
processes catching other forms of innovation. It was necessary due to
the variety of products, sometimes relying on several common
technologies (material, composite, flammability, electronics, EMI,
etc.), and due to the value of design and layouts for cabin and seats
equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the working group had to precise the articulation of other
innovation streams and practices contributing to exploration and
differing from the linear, continuous and adaptive view of innovation.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zaos---innovate-process-card-sipoc-view&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/InnovateProcessCard.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;ZAOS - Innovate process card (SIPOC view)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/InnovateProcessCard.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    ZAOS - Innovate process card (SIPOC view)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we show, in the following paragraphs, decisional ambidexterity
explains the nature of these innovation streams contributing in more
complex ways and differing from traditional models of ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;revisiting-the-innovation-funnel&#34;&gt;Revisiting the innovation funnel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to provide a basis for discussion, the researcher used
traditional ways of representing innovation. The famous funnel implies
uncertainty reduction through a stage-gated with an hypothetical target
and environment. It is rather fixated. He then proposed to use its
parameters and assumptions to show that other innovations, differing
from technology maturation could be considered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technologies and Products can be created but do not have yet a
market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markets can be created but do not have yet a product or technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two simple statements encourage after defining what the funnel
is&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, to envision other scenarios and concepts to be decided. The
figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:InnovationFunnel&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:InnovationFunnel&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;
below incites to revisit the innovation funnel, not only to show the
necessary feedback loops between gates to reach an a priori defined
target, but also to show the porosity of the funnel and its
elasticity/plasticity as new decisions rule its scope and curvature.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-extending-the-innovation-funnel-with-decisional-ambidexterity&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/InnovationFunnel.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Extending the Innovation Funnel with Decisional Ambidexterity&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/InnovationFunnel.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Extending the Innovation Funnel with Decisional Ambidexterity
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colour code identifies different types of concepts relying on a
specific decision-making. The light blue refer to technologies and
(design) concepts that can fit the environment and adjust with existing
engineering design rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark blue is for new concepts that tend to modify the shape of the
funnel. Some can be fully discarded (red-cross) because they are decided
to be out of scope, e.g. they require escalating decision and involve
strategic discussions challenging the overall model of business or
firm’s identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others may be left in a &lt;em&gt;parking lot&lt;/em&gt; (yellow) as the decision requires
deeper value management to understand how to generate a future fit with
organizations: e.g. the lower deck project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, the dark blue concepts may require to search or support
suppliers in developing technologies, or inversely searching or
co-innovating with customers and users to shape the future market. The
Icing Conditions Detection project revealed several features of this
interplay between technology and market design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;decision-design-and-innovation-governance&#34;&gt;Decision-design and Innovation governance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing such interactions touching upon organizational metabolism,
the writing team had to provide a means to manage such decisions. They
relied on existing practices, i.e. road mapping activities for
technologies and products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the group included the product road map as part of &lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt;
whereas in the past it was absent and only focused on technologies
(R&amp;amp;T). It allowed to be more representative of &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; business units who
focus rather on design features (cabin and seats), besides common topics
such as materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the main issue raised by writing workshop participants was the
handover between innovation teams and product development and
sales/marketing. The issue was not the handover dossier nor technical
items, but rather to have some buy-in from them. Moreover, enforcing a
top-down was not necessarily the solution according to participants’
experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the CTO, they proposed to introduce a governance body to
orchestrate the alignment and change of roadmaps for technologies and
products. The American colleague (CTO’s delegate for the Americas) was
not very comfortable with it as it has a stronger meaning than in France
(more related to the firm’s Board). Nevertheless, due to the weight and
twist they wanted to give to this management of decisions and concepts,
they kept it. The procedure asks to organize meetings with BU
stakeholders, invited experts from the group (if relevant), and the
group CTO. Interactions in meetings are encouraged then to discuss what
can change for the funnel and in between roadmaps. The point is to
discuss what makes decision and position concepts accordingly. Experts
can bring additional knowledge. And the CTO can spot opportunities
outside of the BU, or find connections for multi-BU projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, we insisted on the innovation potential of attraction,
resurfacing rules for decisions on product engineering and development,
in order to fit to them or redesign them with according knowledge and
organizational change. The word metabolism wasn’t used but the
interactions and the management device through this governance body is
here to support such phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt; process defined as complement to the exploitation regime
in &lt;em&gt;Design &amp;amp; Develop&lt;/em&gt; offers a first to reconsider a reductive model of
ambidexterity for R&amp;amp;T activities and articulate other innovation
streams. Decisional ambidexterity is used to condition exploration by
exploitation parameters and constraints usually represented through a
funnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the obstacles reported by R&amp;amp;T managers and innovation
practitioners, they proposed to work on the articulation of their
activities with exploitation regime. Bringing interactions and managing
them around fixations effects and interdependencies through the lens of
&lt;em&gt;decisional ambidexterity&lt;/em&gt;, allows to propose new means of actions for
existing objects such as road maps. The decision design is distilled in
the process and embodied by &lt;em&gt;governance&lt;/em&gt; of roadmaps during meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;approach-and-validation-with-rt-managers&#34;&gt;Approach and validation with R&amp;amp;T Managers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former &lt;em&gt;Aérazur&lt;/em&gt; group of business units had their own quality
management system and shared common practices as well similar
technologies (fabric, composite material, injection moulding). When the
R&amp;amp;T activities had been gradually established in 2013, they had set up
an exchange group with the recently appointed R&amp;amp;T managers. In late
2016, after a year without meetings, the group was set up again, and
enlarged to other business units in France, i.e. not restricted to
former &lt;em&gt;Aérazur&lt;/em&gt;. The researcher was already known to these managers,
had worked with them on their management practice, and had consulted
them to collect input for innovation procedures update (before and
during ZAOS project).
They held five meetings between 2017 and 2018 to discuss several topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Performance Indicators for R&amp;amp;T management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handover between R&amp;amp;T and other BU stakeholders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expertise and technologies knowledge access across BUs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decision-making and design practices for R&amp;amp;T and advanced concepts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agenda was set by the main organizer and the researcher. The group
was consulted beforehand to adjust according to their interests and were
requested to present their perspective on agenda’s topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Below, we share feedbacks collected through the five workshops organized
by the R&amp;amp;T managers community. The researcher consulted this group of
people outside the procedure writing workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher tested also how decisional ambidexterity could be adapted
to the process management perspective of the new quality management
system in addition to complementary methods and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rethinking-evaluation-of-concepts&#34;&gt;Rethinking evaluation of concepts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several projects hosted in BU’s respective R&amp;amp;T departments struggled to
beyond TRL6, i.e. the gate beyond which the Product Development
engineering should take over. All BUs had a history of numerous product
innovation, technology development, and most had been successful before
delimiting an up-stream activity (R&amp;amp;T, Innovation or Advanced Concepts).
Of course, many other projects had failed or led to high risks taking
when developing products for clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have stressed earlier, TRL assessments consider environment being
fixed, so entering the evaluation is made for a given target with its
integration assumptions. Several discussions were oriented on how the
environment could be shaped to create a generative fit, as they agreed
it couldn’t be so deterministic for some technologies and products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following three meetings, one of the R&amp;amp;T managers reported he had
several TRL6 technologies waiting to handover to product development and
industrialisation. He had organized several meetings with stakeholders,
but industrialisation and operations wouldn’t show up; after several
attempts, projects went further with the support of a salesman. Such
initiatives led to tensions between departments despite having verbal
and signed agreement following the organized meetings (email and signing
sheets).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, he proposed to create an interface for such meetings. The
idea of having management device to channel interactions was
acknowledged crucial. They made the parallel with brainstormings without
a proper coach: rules and isolated brainwriting give voice to all ideas.
An Excel spreadsheet was formalised to decide on concepts interest.
Criteria were defined and given a weight by BU stakeholders. The
objective was first to decide on the interest and value of concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the second underlying objective was to envision the possibility
of reviewing some criteria (with a poor value or ranking) in order to
identify what had to change in the BU to enable the decision:
engineering rules, client relationship, use cases, suppliers, technical
feasibility, manufacturability, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They managed to emphasize the cruciality of discussing what makes
decisions for R&amp;amp;T and innovation concepts to better work out the
articulation with exploitation regime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, decisional ambidexterity applied heuristics developed
during the meetings allowed reconnecting innovation streams with the
gaps created by traditional models of ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-augmented-proof-of-concept&#34;&gt;The augmented Proof of Concept&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During one of the meetings, they also took the opportunity to discuss
the Hypoxia Protection project. The several practices of opening the
project were presented such as discussing digital and physical mock-ups
with stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point was to try to test the idea of revisiting the traditional
proof of concept as defined in a TRL assessment. A prototype presented
to stakeholders to check pre-defined criteria could lead to a
standstill. So, they debated over how they could discuss the evolution
of criteria thus enabling other concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do so, the researcher proposed to work on what an engineering model
is. He took an external example (aircraft engine) which can be described
with simple equations at a certain order in functional analysis. He
insisted on specifying assumptions and impacts on engineering rules,
interfaces between sub-systems and organization mirroring. Consequently,
they could discuss how simple variations on equation parameters could
radically engineering rules and organization. For instance, one can
shift from a turbojet to a turbofan by playing on inlet cross section,
and shift even to open rotor turbofans by making the cross section
infinite. The first shift has a strong impact on mechanical gear and
shaft system. The second shift changes the physics altogether, since
part of the engine is unducted, so propellers’ equations have to be
integrated. Such simple tricks in the model handling ripple out through
an engineering organization as well as for an entire business unit and
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    The discussions with R&amp;amp;T managers revealed their interest but also the
difficulty to transpose to their BU and engineering the method. Indeed,
formalizing their practice hasn’t been done systematically across the
group and over the years. However, it also leaves some slack as well as
risks and opportunities to innovate around the non-totally-explicit
models of engineering. Such setting gives room for high levels of
reconfigurability but with threats of leaving interdependencies and
fixations in a blind spot.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-if-to-articulate-strategic-intent-and-organization-design&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;What If?&amp;rdquo; to articulate strategic intent and organization design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the researcher discussed hacking to value emergent strategies.
One R&amp;amp;T manager was very receptive and presented us his way of designing
his strategy. His business unit has been facing market share losses and
difficulties in opening new markets because of lowering entry barriers
(known technology) and regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New growth opportunities had to be found and these would be out of the
aircraft industry. Sticking to the history of technology transfers and
genericity to different systems integration, he developed alternatives.
The methodology formalizing technology roadmaps definition and creation
was used to identify hackable parameters. Indeed, he acknowledged
presenting to his managing directors highly uncertain Net Present Value
calculations and business models. However, his presentations aimed at
showing how they could become true or less uncertain by identifying
means of action to uncover the share of unknown. Another representative
from another BU, shared a history of business plans requested by his
local financial director who systematically requested them. He used
these models to show the absurdity of such planning per se, and twisted
to identify what had to be redesigned internally or in the environment
to enable the business cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting’s participants acknowledged such practices. In some way or
another, they had performed similar hacking in their own fashion and
with variations. For instance, one relied on formalized business plans
for his financial director not only to &amp;ldquo;cheat&amp;rdquo; and gain his approval,
but also to point at where the effort should be put to make these cases
come true. As for the previous modelling effort for engineering and
organizing, they stressed the difficulty in transposing across BUs. The
R&amp;amp;T managers were more keen in having a set of heuristics and method to
adapt and apply them to their specific practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no &lt;em&gt;one best way&lt;/em&gt; so it encouraged the researcher to find
generic enough. We didn’t take the time to introduce decisional
ambidexterity as it has been formalized here in the thesis’ manuscript
or in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-lemasson2018/&#34;&gt;our publication&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The meetings held with R&amp;amp;T managers from the French BUs were rich in
debate to discuss management issues. During these meetings and the
evolving agendas, we tried to test some declinations of decisional
ambidexterity before its actual formalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see that they came with their own practices and tricks to overcome
limitations of traditional models of ambidexterity. However, they report
on the difficulties to have a systematic way of playing on fixations
effects and interdependencies to value their project’s portfolio. In
other words, it encourages to work on a &lt;em&gt;baseline&lt;/em&gt; that would help them
to reconciliate the tensions between the models organizational
ambidexterity and exploration projects.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis-decisional-ambidexterity-enhancing-process-management&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis: decisional ambidexterity enhancing process management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this chapter, we have presented how the researcher contributed to the
quality management system through the &lt;em&gt;Design &amp;amp; Develop&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt;
processes. We tried to accommodate decisional ambidexterity within the
processual perspective and it reveals some difficulties circumvented by
the introduction of the notion of &lt;em&gt;governance&lt;/em&gt; for road-mapping
activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussions during workshops with the R&amp;amp;T managers from French BUs
reveal also the complexity for them to implement approaches extending
limitations of traditional models of ambidexterity. They recognize the
results of the thesis, they identify with patterns of decisional
ambidexterity, but still struggle to implement or develop their own
&lt;em&gt;technology of organizing&lt;/em&gt;. The disentanglement of fixations effects and
interdependencies is complex and perhaps even chaotic. However, the
interactive meetings proposed in the procedure to discuss and design
decisions opened some possibilities, as some colleagues had implemented
similar practices or were about to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work trying to collect and propose means of formalizing decisional
ambidexterity is not finished despite having tested ideas of
implementation. The logics appear quite normal to them, as it was also
recognized by the former CEO and discussed for the Multi-BU committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter closes our work at Zodiac Aerospace and our testing of the
decisional ambidexterity supporting its validation as an extension of
models of ambidexterity. As shown here, it provides means of action to
avoid the limitations we had extensively discussed in previous chapters
when starting the PhD journey. The following chapters will discuss what
we have achieved so far before concluding this thesis.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Cooper2007&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cooper, By Robert G. 2007. “Managing Technology Development Projects.”
&lt;em&gt;Stage-Gate&lt;/em&gt; 35 (1): 67–76.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Galbraith1971&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galbraith, Jay R. 1971. “Matrix organization designs How to combine
functional and project forms.” &lt;em&gt;Business Horizons&lt;/em&gt; 14 (1): 29–40.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/0007-6813(71)90037-1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/0007-6813(71)90037-1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Mankins2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mankins, John C. 2009. “Technology readiness assessments: A
retrospective.” &lt;em&gt;Acta Astronautica&lt;/em&gt; 65 (9): 1216–23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what the box is, to think out of it and it in comparison to &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
