<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PhD Dissertation | Mario LE GLATIN</title>
    <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PhD Dissertation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>PhD Dissertation</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this document (wiki), I will present my PhD Dissertation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Work in progress&amp;hellip;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/chapter2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/chapter2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this document (wiki), I will present my PhD Dissertation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Work in progress&amp;hellip;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/chapter3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this document (wiki), I will present my PhD Dissertation. Updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Work in progress&amp;hellip;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&amp;hellip;] organizational adaptation requires both exploitation and
exploration to achieve persistent success.&lt;/em&gt; (March

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;, 205)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizing collective action has taken different structures and used different means to channel its effervescence. Over the last decades with increasing interest on innovation management, several models have been
prescribed in order to support firm’s innovation. An overwhelming
concern for exploration (Wilden et al. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Wilden2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;) and its
means have been the centre of attention to counter limitations of
exploitation such as path-dependence, bounded rationality, cognitive
biases and other myopic behaviours.&lt;br&gt;
Designing an ambidextrous organization has become mainstream for
managers. Academics have studied the topic in-depth through several
units of analysis to understand how it can contribute to innovation and
firm’s competitive advantage. It has given ideas for implementations,
and contingencies to be aware of, but has spiralled around the paradoxes
of balancing exploration and exploitation (Birkinshaw and Gupta

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;; O’Reilly and Tushman

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-OReilly2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;; Benner and Tushman 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Benner2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;).
However, organization design and allocation of resources to sustain two
separate regimes aimed originally at organizational learning (March

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;). The drift towards innovation necessarily have
encountered other practices such as exploration project management. Is
the original perspective on learning and adaptation compatible with
innovation management?&lt;br&gt;
Moving beyond problem-solving, adding uncertainties and more
significantly addressing the unknown are the signature of innovation
management. Novelty is generated and managed through an arsenal of
practices and methods that can be seen in marketing, strategic analysis,
design reasoning and theory (Le Masson, Hatchuel, and Weil

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeMasson2017a&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;). These practices are enclosed within
projects (Lenfle 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/a&gt;) or
portfolios(Maniak and Midler 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Maniak2014b&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, ambidexterity promotes a separation between exploration and
exploitation and it is more generally discussed for organizational
dimensions of time and structure supporting a regime and the other.
Consequently, the unknown occupies a different place and is related to
in different ways when seen from innovation management through
exploration projects or seen from organizational ambidexterity and its
foundations. Over time, and with evolution of practices and constructs
in literature, the separation of regimes could now be in conflict with
generative processes driving the exploration and exploitation of the
unknown.&lt;br&gt;
Ambiguities on the meaning of ambidexterity, exploration and
exploitation have been spotted and extensively discussed in (Gupta,
Smith, and Shalley 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gupta2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;). Having a common definition
of these constructs appears critical. At the light of what ambidexterity
has become over the years for organization studies, performance and
innovation, (Birkinshaw and Gupta 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;) stress
the discomfort caused by how exploration and exploitation are considered
with respect to ambidexterity, and the seminal model on organizational
learning and adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On several occasions in seminars and at conferences I have had
debates with colleagues about &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;how the notion
of ambidexterity might be reconciled with March’s (1991) view that
exploration and exploitation are mutually incompatible&lt;/span&gt;. My
response is quite straightforward. March (1991) provided a theory to
explain his observation that exploration and exploitation represent
self-reinforcing patterns of learning. I agree with this observation.
However, I don’t believe he is saying that it is impossible for
organizations to overcome these self-reinforcing patterns; he is just
saying that it is extremely difficult. This is where ambidexterity
comes in. Essentially, ambidexterity provides a normative perspective
on how organizations function. It says that managers are making
choices and trade-offs among competing objectives, and when they do
their job well they override the organization’s tendency to go down
the path of least resistance. For example, they might actively push
one objective ahead of the other for a limited time, or they might
find creative ways of delivering on two objectives at the same time&lt;/em&gt;
(Birkinshaw and Gupta 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;, 293)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlined extract highlights the potential divergence and necessity
to reconsider the separation between exploration and exploitation, its
meaning and how it can be conditioned one another. Indeed, both should
be performed, they bear different mindsets that are not sustainable on
their own for the firm, but should be kept separate and balanced in
sequence or in parallel. Cross-contamination between exploration and
exploitation jeopardizes firm’s performance and potentially underlying
forces driven by innovation pushing the performance frontier drawn by
both regimes. Given new practices of innovation management driving
exploration regime, we should also help clarifying where the unknown
lies and its impact with respect to the dichotomy encouraged by
ambidexterity.&lt;br&gt;
Our PhD manuscript starts with this perspective: designing an
ambidextrous organization will separate exploration from exploitation
activities through different means. If the firm is not able to sustain
the innovation effort to explore and exploit, who is to blame? Should we
consider the firm is not doing it well enough? Or should it be the model
of segregating exploration from exploitation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such questions are legitimated by the issues and ambiguities raised in
the literature in recent years, and we propose to come back to the
origins of such model of ambidexterity, and the dichotomy
exploration/exploitation. Starting of again with the seminal article
(March 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;) will allow confronting the original
perspective of organizational learning and adaptation with the
contemporary issues of innovation management. This literature has also
created a place for exploration engines: exploration project management
(Lenfle 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/a&gt;) for instance put the emphasis on
managing the unknown, generative processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We suggest testing original foundations and hypotheses to discuss the
validity of the ambidexterity models given new practices of innovation.
For instance, such exploration projects develop requirements,
engineering capabilities that are new to established and mirrored
organizations (Colfer and Baldwin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Colfer2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;).
Project-based organizations supporting new product development will face
several challenges such as decomposition and integration (Sosa and Mihm

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Sosa2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/a&gt;), but as interdependencies are reconfigured with
innovative design, dynamically mirroring product engineering with the
organization becomes critical to sustain learning and adaptation in the
long run. In other words, the unknown brought by exploration projects
and generative processes can be at odds with the assumptions made in
implementing ambidexterity.&lt;br&gt;
The PhD journey was hosted by Zodiac Aerospace offering an industrial
context to study their concern for organizational ambidexterity and
their innovation practice. This conglomerate of SMEs built over more
than a century has been the grounds for numerous designs, products and
technologies that have largely contributed to the structure of the
aviation industry. With raising uncertainties on the future of the
market, designs, technologies and qualification/certification
requirements, and the pressure to maintain and optimize legacy products,
ZA designed an ambidextrous organization. However, they have had
difficulties in the implementation and several exploration project
raised controversies for business units and top management. Since not
all projects could be considered as failures, with also a concern on the
notion of failure and performance (Elmquist and Le Masson

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Elmquist2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;), we were in a position to discuss the
prescribed model of management and actual practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several case studies were identified to study their practice, its course
of action and try to understand it given literature models of
ambidexterity and managing the unknown. These cases were proposed by
managers and engineers who had open management issues with their
projects.&lt;br&gt;
In this PhD thesis, we will then closely study the implementation of an
ambidextrous organization and its impact on sustained innovation. The
development in management of exploration project, of the unknown and
generative processes will also bring a new light on the original purpose
of separating exploration and exploitation: organizational learning and
adaptation. The organization design with the underlying &lt;em&gt;mirroring
hypothesis&lt;/em&gt; will necessarily be challenged as project dynamics will
interfere with intra-organizational boundaries, inter-organizations and
inevitably with strategic management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sections below provide a starter to the manuscript. First, we
explain the industrial request specifying the nature and preliminary
formulation of the management issue faced by the Chief Technical and
Innovation Officer of Zodiac Aerospace. Second, we further detail our
opening research questions which will guide us through the literature
review (part
&lt;a href=&#34;#part:literature&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;part:literature&#34;&gt;[part:literature]&lt;/a&gt;,
p.). Third, in the last section, the synopsis is pictured showing the
overall structure of the PhD thesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-industrial-request-zodiac-aerospace-struggling-with-exploration-projects-and-ambidexterity&#34;&gt;An industrial request: Zodiac Aerospace struggling with exploration projects and ambidexterity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conglomerate-of-smes-and-a-group-holding&#34;&gt;Conglomerate of SMEs and a group holding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thesis was conducted at the Technical &amp;amp; Innovation Direction of
Zodiac Aerospace (ZSA, holding). Established in 1896, this large
industrial group of 75 entities designs, develops and manufactures
aeronautical equipment for aircraft/helicopters manufacturer and
airlines. These are scattered across 100 facilities across the globe and
mainly centralized in Europe and North America. In the last couple of
decades, some facilities were established in cost-competitive countries
for the serial production of some entities.&lt;br&gt;
The group of SMEs where each of them with a few hundreds employees each,
equating to a total of 35,000, have their own responsibility and
performance logic. A light group holding of 200 employees with several
support functions have the challenge to manage the sometimes competing
SMEs due to the market structures and build up synergies targeted by the
executive committee.&lt;br&gt;
The management directives are cascaded down to the pool of business
units grouped in so-called &amp;ldquo;divisions&amp;rdquo; and branches with a Master Plan
(&lt;em&gt;Hoshin Kanri&lt;/em&gt; planning) synthesizing the strategy. However this broad
strategic plan is largely adjusted by the individual business units as
their autonomy is driven by operational concerns faced locally in their
line of business. The group holding controls the BUs through several
reporting channels, the major one being Profit &amp;amp; Losses; so beyond the
control dimension, the corporate staff serves as the flag holder of the
Zodiac Aerospace brand, representing BUs for key accounts and suppliers
at the top management level, in addition to external functions:
institutions, certification authority, research councils and public
funding schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-entrepreneurial-history-closely-linked-to-the-historical-roots-of-the-aircraft-industry&#34;&gt;An entrepreneurial history closely linked to the historical roots of the aircraft industry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1896, the history of ZA has developed numerous innovations at the
time when the aviation industry was building up in Europe and in North
America. These largely contributed to aircraft safety, aircraft
components and later to systems and cabin equipment. Today as the market
has largely settled and rationalized with safety and certification
frameworks, several novelties and radical improvements have also reached
the market thanks to long-term partnerships with aircraft manufacturers
and airlines.&lt;br&gt;
However, BUs are looking for new growth catalysts as they face growing
uncertainties on future aircraft architectures and kick-off date. In
parallel, the world fleet continues growing but mainly for legacy
aircraft with occasional marginal improvements, and a symmetric requests
for substantial decrease in (re-)development costs. A macro-economic
side-effect is the growing concentration of equipment and system
manufacturers: main competitor of ZA (B/E Aerospace, very similar
structure and market footprint) was acquired by Rockwell Collins
(equivalent of Thales group) who is currently being acquired by United
Technologies Corporation. Along the same dynamic, ZA has been very
recently acquired by Safran group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;increasing-uncertainties-and-novel-unknowns-for-intrainter-bu-exploration-projects&#34;&gt;Increasing uncertainties and novel unknowns for intra/inter-BU exploration projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After splitting the former Zodiac group in 2007, between Zodiac
Aerospace and Marine &amp;amp; Pool Activities, the current corporate team has
largely developed its intervention starting off with counselling and
support in order to back up the performance of exploitation activities
(Quality, Cost and Delay) but also value exploration and competencies
regeneration for future prospects: expert network, scientific and
technical council (ZSTC), expert review (technical audit for NPD),
creation of an R&amp;amp;T function, evaluation of technology maturity level
(Technology Readiness Level), creation of technology/production road
maps (TRM/PRM) challenged by top management, lobbying and external
funding, transverse future technologies, and intellectual property.&lt;br&gt;
Given raising uncertainties on exploitation certainties such as aircraft
architecture and integration, or new program, and airline demanding
frequent changes, several exploratory projects and sometimes key
programs have gained visibility for the corporate teams. Overall, ZA has
been developing organizational ambidexterity locally in business units
and at the corporate level.&lt;br&gt;
The Technical and Innovation Direction along with the Executive
Committee are in a position to try out management innovations with
respect to these projects (intra/inter BU) that appear to regenerate
organizations in a large internal pool of agents, tools, competencies,
processes and organizational structures. The challenge for the
Innovation Direction was to overcome the limitations of the market-pull
dynamic of aircraft manufacturers and airlines. Several techno-push
projects had been identified by BUs and top management, these were
promoted and steered through a committee called &amp;ldquo;Multi-BU&amp;rdquo;. For more
&amp;ldquo;short-term concerns&amp;rdquo; associated with the anticipation of user and
client needs, two special teams where created near assembly lines of
Airbus and Boeing. The aim of these teams is to capture potential future
needs, deal with a portion of the technical support addressed to their
BUs of origin, formulate new concepts and tests these with airlines and
aircraft manufacturers.&lt;br&gt;
Projects were launched using these platforms, among several other R&amp;amp;T
topics within each BU, and they raised technical barriers, issues
associated with institutional barriers (certification, client/user
desirability), and collaboration between BUs. Overall, they have caused
difficulties in transitioning between exploration and exploitation. Some
of them have been considered as (partial) successes, others as failures,
questioning what makes innovation performance. But given the demanding
constraints of exploitation in the aircraft industry, and the mirroring
by BUs and their internal organizations, the projects’ trajectories
question the organizational fit, boundaries and their capability to
sustain such potential innovations.&lt;br&gt;
This organizational context, individual histories of entrepreneurship
and SMEs’ collective history, framed by a strong &lt;em&gt;dominant design&lt;/em&gt;, we
wonder what is the managerial perspective regarding intra/inter-BU
projects, and the first questions that come to mind would be the
following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the benefits of organizational ambidexterity for
exploration projects within a conglomerate of SMEs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is the innovation effort challenging the performance frontier
set by exploration and exploitation balance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the implications of organization design for exploration
project management?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is the corporate and local management dealing with these
potentially conflicting trends (exploration project management and
ambidexterity)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These questions were originally raised in the early stages of the PhD
journey. They touched upon a critical idea: is Zodiac Aerospace not good
enough to develop an ambidextrous organization? As it has been stressed
in our preliminary introduction to the literature, we have some
arguments to believe that perhaps ZA could actually be applying the
models appropriately. So, it is rather an invitation to reconsider the
underlying assumptions and implications of ambidexterity, and separation
of exploration from exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-invitation-from-literature-ambidexterity-revisited-by-innovation-management-evolutions&#34;&gt;An invitation from literature: ambidexterity revisited by innovation management evolutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organizational-ambidexterity---separating-and-balancing-exploration-and-exploitation&#34;&gt;Organizational ambidexterity - separating and balancing exploration and exploitation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zodiac Aerospace has been developing an ambidextrous organization with
several means: dedicated departments to exploration (e.g. R&amp;amp;T,
innovation, design, advanced concepts) within BUs, autonomous team,
group-level initiatives to foster exploration, committees discussing and
deciding on exploration project management at the light of strategy,
corporate leadership and sponsorship.&lt;br&gt;
The BUs have been gradually establishing project-based organizations to
support the delivery of legacy products/services and NPD based on
customer demands. Along with the rationalization trend of the market,
major customers such as aircraft manufacturers and airlines have been
prescribing specific ways to manage programs and projects along with
equipment qualification and certification. BUs require maintaining their
knowledge, competencies over long periods of time to satisfy clients
along the value chain during the lifetime of the products and the
aircraft (from a few years to several decades). Exploitation performance
is thus achieved in reinforcing these routines with a spirit of
continuous improvement (March 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br&gt;
Yet, as threats of uncertainties and unknown are seen for the future of
the ecosystem, several innovative projects try to anticipate and shape
what ought to be designed for the future aircraft platforms or airline
retrofits to keep up with the competitive advantage. Consequently, they
require building creative dynamic capabilities (Nonaka et al.

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Nonaka2014&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;), and regenerative dynamic capabilities
(Ambrosini, Bowman, and Collier 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Ambrosini2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;) to sustain
repeatable patterns of innovation inspired by the historical
entrepreneurial spirit of BUs. These patterns largely contribute to
exploration regime. The literature (Birkinshaw and Gupta

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;; Gupta, Smith, and Shalley

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gupta2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;) has stressed it may not be on the same continuum
of exploitation, but perhaps in an another dimension. However, it is
recognized these should coexist and be balanced; which reinforces the
idea of separation between the two: non-conditioning of both regimes.&lt;br&gt;
It becomes then critical to understand how dynamic capabilities, fed by
innovation practices, can contribute to shifting the performance
frontier set by exploration and exploitation to solve efficiently the
problem worked out by agents in the firm. How is organizational learning
and adaptation actually sustained? Key representatives of the
ambidexterity literature (Birkinshaw and Gupta

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;; O’Reilly and Tushman

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-OReilly2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;; Benner and Tushman 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Benner2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;)
have questioned the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; inviting more qualitative research and
micro-foundational approaches. Indeed, innovation-driven exploration
will rely on numerous practices trying to shape the unknown and
generative processes that may be stretching beyond the seminal
problem-solving defined by James March.&lt;br&gt;
For instance, the challenge of building these capabilities will have a
stake in the strategic intent and organization design that is directly
linked to the decisions (Birkinshaw and Gupta

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;) made along the project management and
design steps taken in the radical innovation process. It also
potentially contributes to redefining problems to be solved by agents in
the firm, thus repeatedly updating (March 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;) model.
More precisely, in terms of problem-formulation, engineering design
efforts mobilized in the exploration regime will necessarily reveal and
challenge interdependencies from technical standpoint but also from an
organizational perspective (Colfer and Baldwin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Colfer2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;).
Aiming for the unknown to reformulate problems goes however beyond
search-based model of exploration may compromise what exploitation is
capable of performing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;managing-the-unknown-for-organization-studies&#34;&gt;Managing the unknown for organization studies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These limitations encourage us to consider the management and design of
underlying dynamic capabilities and organizational fit to support these
exploration, or simply innovative projects as they glide across the
conglomerate. It channels then the PhD journey through another
literature field mainly concerned by project management and managing the
unknown. Overall, it could be considered as an encapsulation of
practices in another regime of collective action differing from
organization studies.&lt;br&gt;
With the development of project management and other contemporary
approaches to innovation management, the attention and locus of
innovation is relocated at a meso-level: not centred on the individuals
and not necessarily seen managed at the organizational level.
Project-based management (Galbraith 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Galbraith2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;; Turner

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Turner2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;) and other organic views that could be traced
back to (Burns and Stalker 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Burns1961&#34;&gt;1961&lt;/a&gt;) bring another
perspective. Calls have been made in major journals on challenges the
field should address (Sydow, Lindkvist, and Defillippi

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Sydow2004&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/a&gt;; Bakker et al. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Bakker2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;;
Söderlund, Hobbs, and Ahola 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Soderlund2014&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;; Söderlund and
Müller 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Soderlund2014a&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;). Projects have been studied for
being a flexible and convenient vehicle for exploration and innovation
practices (Midler, Killen, and Kock 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Midler2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;), innovation
management can be historically linked to project management (Lenfle and
Loch 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;; Davies, Manning,
and Söderlund 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Davies2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;). However, putting aside the
normative view of project management (e.g. Project Management
Institute), the nature of exploration project management and the
encapsulation of generative processes (e.g. Design Thinking, creative
problems-solving, C-K theory, etc.) raises numerous questions on
organizational ties compared the host firm, the risk of spin-off ad-hoc
patterns. These contingencies are crucial for a conglomerate of SMEs
where organization design reflects engineering design and its
constraints (Colfer and Baldwin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Colfer2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br&gt;
So, the contributions of the project management literature encourages us
to study the perspective and impact of portfolio and program management
for exploration, for organization design and strategy (Gemünden, Lehner,
and Kock 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gemunden2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;; Hobday 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hobday2000&#34;&gt;2000&lt;/a&gt;).
More generally, it is another way of discussing organizational
ambidexterity, and its coexistence in a firm such as Zodiac Aerospace.
For instance, these projects re-discuss aircraft equipment and systems
technical constraints, as well as corresponding BUs’ organizational
boundaries. We must also stress here the pressures related to the
dominant designs, the lock-ins, and path-dependence associated to these
products in the market and how the BUs are organized internally given a
mirror hypothesis. The crucial issue being how the corporate team of ZA
(Group Innovation Direction, CTO, ZSTC along with the ExCom) steers,
organizes, manages these projects as they tend to revise individually
not only the design/engineering dimension of the products, but the
underlying organizations and ecosystems (environment, institutions)
whilst playing within the group strategy and market footprint.
Exploration projects consequently moderate the organizational learning,
design and adaptation brought initially by the separation of exploration
and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;preliminary-research-questions&#34;&gt;Preliminary Research questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zodiac Aerospace practice of innovation, organization design, strategic
management and engineering bring new questions to be answered given this
preliminary literature review at the light of conditions imposed by the
industrial context. This early formulation of our research questions
will guide through the literature review (part
&lt;a href=&#34;#part:literature&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;part:literature&#34;&gt;[part:literature]&lt;/a&gt;,
p.). We invite the reader to consult the identified research gap and
associated research questions in chapter
&lt;a href=&#34;#chap:rquest&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;chap:rquest&#34;&gt;[chap:rquest]&lt;/a&gt;
(p.). Further advice on reading is given in the &lt;em&gt;Reading tips&lt;/em&gt; box on
p., the synopsis is presented in the following page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the implications of enforcing the non-conditioning of
exploration and exploitation for organizing ambidexterity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is organization ambidexterity understood from the perspective of
exploration project and project-based management?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How comparable is the foundational model of (March

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;) with today’s approaches to innovation
management?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the organization design and change associated to exploration
project management?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thesis-outline-and-synopsis&#34;&gt;Thesis outline and synopsis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;synopsis.png&#34; id=&#34;fig:synopsis&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Thesis’ synopsis&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;reading-tips-chapreadingtips&#34;&gt;Reading tips [chap:readingtips]&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;span-classsmallcapsreading-tipsspan-reading-tips&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;smallcaps&#34;&gt;Reading tips&lt;/span&gt; [reading-tips]&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage the reader to first consider the master table of content to
have a global picture of the thesis. The introduction gives a second
overview of the agenda of the thesis and opening questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, before each part a grey text box hold a summary of the upcoming
chapters with keywords and results and followed by a table of contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the literature review in part
&lt;a href=&#34;#part:literature&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;part:literature&#34;&gt;[part:literature]&lt;/a&gt;
(p.) ending with the research questions chapter
&lt;a href=&#34;#chap:rquest&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;chap:rquest&#34;&gt;[chap:rquest]&lt;/a&gt;
(p.) will help the reader understanding the research gap and the origins
of the anomaly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, we invite to look at the research trajectory conducted by the PhD
candidate, the research context, the anomaly detection method and the
cases’ description. See Part
&lt;a href=&#34;#part:methodo&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;part:methodo&#34;&gt;[part:methodo]&lt;/a&gt;,
p..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anomalies presented in Part
&lt;a href=&#34;#part:anomaly&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;part:anomaly&#34;&gt;[part:anomaly]&lt;/a&gt;
(p.) provide requirements for a new model (chapter
&lt;a href=&#34;#chap:anomalies_spec&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;chap:anomalies_spec&#34;&gt;[chap:anomalies_spec]&lt;/a&gt;,
p.) that is then presented and detailed in Part
&lt;a href=&#34;#part:modelling&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;part:modelling&#34;&gt;[part:modelling]&lt;/a&gt;
(p.). It allows us finally to provide foundations for legitimate
researcher’s intervention, see Part
&lt;a href=&#34;#part:intervention&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;part:intervention&#34;&gt;[part:intervention]&lt;/a&gt;
(p.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note to the reader:&lt;/strong&gt; You will probably notice that starting off with
the methodology sections, we will make reference to a character simply
named &lt;em&gt;The Researcher&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The PhD Candidate&lt;/em&gt;. This choice was made
because the methodology was written first and &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; was quickly referred
to as being part of the research management, as if he were an
instrument. When reaching the model testing and associated
interventions, you may feel that the narrator, &lt;em&gt;We&lt;/em&gt;, gets closer to the
&lt;em&gt;The Researcher&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references-bibliography&#34;&gt;References [bibliography]&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Ambrosini2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambrosini, Véronique, Cliff Bowman, and Nardine Collier. 2009. “Dynamic
Capabilities: An Exploration of How Firms Renew their Resource Base.”
&lt;em&gt;British Journal of Management&lt;/em&gt; 20 (SUPP. 1): S9–S24.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8551.2008.00610.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8551.2008.00610.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Bakker2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bakker, Rene M., Robert J. DeFillippi, Andreas Schwab, and Jörg Sydow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Temporary Organizing: Promises, Processes, Problems.”
&lt;em&gt;Organization Studies&lt;/em&gt; 37 (12): 1703–19.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840616655982&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840616655982&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Benner2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benner, Mary J, and Michael L Tushman. 2015. “Reflections on the 2013
Decade Award–&amp;ldquo;Exploitation, Exploration, and Process Management: The
Productivity Dilemma Revisited&amp;rdquo; Ten Years Later.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management
Review&lt;/em&gt; 40 (4): 497–514. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2015.0042&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2015.0042&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birkinshaw, Julian, and Kamini Gupta. 2013. “Clarifying the distinctive
contribution of ambidexterity to the field of organization studies.”
&lt;em&gt;The Academy of Management Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; 27 (4): 287–98.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Burns1961&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burns, Tom, and G. M Stalker. 1961. “The Management of Innovation.”
Tavistock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Colfer2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colfer, Lyra J., and Carliss Y. Baldwin. 2016. “The mirroring
hypothesis: Theory, evidence, and exceptions.” &lt;em&gt;Industrial and Corporate
Change&lt;/em&gt; 25 (5): 709–38. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/icc/dtw027&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/icc/dtw027&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Davies2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davies, Andrew, Stephan Manning, and Jonas Söderlund. 2018. “When
neighboring disciplines fail to learn from each other: The case of
innovation and project management research.” &lt;em&gt;Research Policy&lt;/em&gt; 47 (5):
965–79. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2018.03.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2018.03.002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Elmquist2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elmquist, Maria, and Pascal Le Masson. 2009. “The value of a ’failed’
R&amp;amp;D project: An emerging evaluation framework for building innovative
capabilities.” &lt;em&gt;R and D Management&lt;/em&gt; 39 (2): 136–52.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9310.2009.00546.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9310.2009.00546.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Galbraith2010&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galbraith, Jay R. 2010. “The Multi-Dimensional and Reconfigurable
Organization.” &lt;em&gt;Organizational Dynamics&lt;/em&gt; 39 (2): 115–25.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.orgdyn.2010.02.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.orgdyn.2010.02.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gemunden2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gemünden, Hans Georg, Patrick Lehner, and Alexander Kock. 2018. “The
project-oriented organization and its contribution to innovation.”
&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 36 (1): 147–60.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2017.07.009&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2017.07.009&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gupta2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gupta, Anil K, Ken G Smith, and Christina E Shalley. 2006. “The
Interplay Between Exploration and Exploitation.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management
Journal&lt;/em&gt; 49 (4): 693–706. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amj.2006.22083026&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amj.2006.22083026&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hobday2000&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobday, Mike. 2000. “The project-based organisation: an ideal form for
managing complex products and systems?” &lt;em&gt;Research Policy&lt;/em&gt; 29 (7-8):
871–93. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0048-7333(00)00110-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0048-7333(00)00110-4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeMasson2017a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Masson, Pascal, Armand Hatchuel, and Benoit Weil. 2017. “Design
theories, creativity and innovation.” In &lt;em&gt;The Elgar Companion to
Innovation and Knowledge Creation&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Harald Bathelt, Patrick
Cohendet, Sebastian Henn, and Laurent Simon, 275–306. Edward Elgar
Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4337/9781782548522.00026&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4337/9781782548522.00026&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lenfle2008&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenfle, Sylvain. 2008. “Exploration and project management.”
&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 26 (5): 469–78.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2008.05.017&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2008.05.017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lenfle2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2016. “Floating in Space? On the Strangeness of Exploratory
Projects.” &lt;em&gt;Project Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 47 (2): 15.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21584&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21584&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lenfle2010&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenfle, Sylvain, and Christoph Loch. 2010. “Lost Roots: How Project
Management Came to Emphasize Control over Flexibility and Novelty.”
&lt;em&gt;California Management Review&lt;/em&gt; 53 (1): 32–55.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1525/cmr.2010.53.1.32&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1525/cmr.2010.53.1.32&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lenfle2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2017. &lt;em&gt;Has Megaproject Management Lost Its Way?&lt;/em&gt; Edited by Bent
Flyvbjerg. Vol. 1. November 2015. Oxford University Press.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780198732242.013.2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780198732242.013.2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Maniak2014b&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maniak, Rémi, and Christophe Midler. 2014. “Multiproject lineage
management: Bridging project management and design-based innovation
strategy.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 32 (7):
1146–56. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.03.006&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.03.006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-March1991&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March, James G. 1991. “Exploration and exploitation in organizational
learning.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 2: 71–87.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Midler2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midler, Christophe, Catherine P. Killen, and Alexander Kock. 2016.
“Project and Innovation Management: Bridging Contemporary Trends in
Theory and Practice.” &lt;em&gt;Project Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 47 (2): 3–7.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21587&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21587&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Nonaka2014&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonaka, Ikujiro, Mitsuru Kodama, Ayano Hirose, and Florian Kohlbacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Dynamic fractal organizations for promoting knowledge-based
transformation - A new paradigm for organizational theory.” &lt;em&gt;European
Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 32 (1): 137–46.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.emj.2013.02.003&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.emj.2013.02.003&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-OReilly2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Reilly, C. A., and M. L. Tushman. 2013. “Organizational Ambidexterity:
Past, Present, and Future.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; 27 (4):
324–38. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amp.2013.0025&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amp.2013.0025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Sosa2008&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sosa, M, and Jürgen Mihm. 2008. “Organization design for new product
development.” In &lt;em&gt;Handbook of New Product Development …&lt;/em&gt;, 165–97.
Elsevier Ltd. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-7506-8552-8.50010-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-7506-8552-8.50010-4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Soderlund2014&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Söderlund, Jonas, Brian Hobbs, and Tuomas Ahola. 2014. “Project-based
and temporary organizing: Reconnecting and rediscovering.”
&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 32 (7): 1085–90.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.06.008&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.06.008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Soderlund2014a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Söderlund, Jonas, and Ralf Müller. 2014. “Project Management and
Organization Theory: IRNOP Meets PMJ.” &lt;em&gt;Project Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 45
(4): 2–6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21442&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21442&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Sydow2004&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sydow, Jörg, Lars Lindkvist, and Robert Defillippi. 2004. “Project-Based
Organizations, Embeddedness and Repositories of Knowledge: Editorial.”
&lt;em&gt;Organization Studies&lt;/em&gt; 25 (9): 1475–89.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840604048162&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840604048162&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Turner2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turner, J. Rodney. 2009. &lt;em&gt;The handbook of Project Based Management&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Wilden2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilden, Ralf, Jan Hohberger, Timothy M. Devinney, and Dovev Lavie. 2018.
“Revisiting James March (1991): Whither exploration and exploitation?”
&lt;em&gt;Strategic Organization&lt;/em&gt; 16 (3): 352–69.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1476127018765031&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1476127018765031&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1 - Literature review</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
