<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 6 - General conclusion and discussion | Mario LE GLATIN</title>
    <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part6/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Part 6 - General conclusion and discussion</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Part 6 - General conclusion and discussion</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part6/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 13 - Main contributions and results synthesis</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part6/chapter13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part6/chapter13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our PhD journey had started from a literature review questioning models
of ambidexterity at the light of the unknown. Innovation management puts
an emphasis on generating novelties, practicing innovative design, and
using methods who actively embrace the unknown. Since implementing an
ambidextrous organization has become rather common - and it was rooted
on the assumptions of (March 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;) model - academics
have recently notified the risk that the separation between exploration
and exploitation could bear numerous complexities requiring further
qualitative studies (Birkinshaw and Gupta 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;;
Gupta, Smith, and Shalley 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gupta2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;; Benner and Tushman

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Benner2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;; O’Reilly and Tushman 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-OReilly2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;).
Over the years and with developments in innovation management, the
unknown has conquered the grounds of ambidexterity and its problem-based
foundations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have addressed these open statements and calls for research by
revealing several projects in a conglomerate of SMEs, Zodiac Aerospace.
These cases were somehow at odds with predictions of ambidexterity
models. Indeed, exploration projects, which actively engage with the
unknown, stretch beyond what the non-mutual conditioning between
exploration/exploitation is capable of explaining. We have shown that
ambidexterity can effectively kill innovation as it enforces
organization design conformity and a reductive adaptation to exploit
explorations. In the case of ZA and its engineering and marketing
conditions, we explain such phenomenon by product/organization design
fixations and interdependencies that are partially ignored and left
unmanaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, we have proposed a model revisiting the foundations of
exploration/exploitation. With the help of design theories staging
generative processes, we were able to address the design of decisions,
leading to decision-making and coordination of collective action.
Decisional ambidexterity relies on the &lt;em&gt;mutual conditioning between
exploration and exploitation&lt;/em&gt; to generate alternatives and states of
nature laying the ground work for interactions on: the nature of
decisions, and models of thought ruling decisions, engineering and
organization design. Working out organization/product design fixations
and interdependencies, with the dynamic mirroring of engineering,
provides additional knowledge to elaborate on the potential decisions
framing collective action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ambidexterity re-developed in our model is placed back at a
behavioural level with decision-design seen as a &lt;em&gt;naturally&lt;/em&gt; managed and
interactive process perhaps even more salient than actual
decision-making (Christiansen and Varnes 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Christiansen2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;).
We were able to reinterpret the management anomalies of ZA with a better
understanding of organization design fixations and interdependencies
that were more or less managed and targeted in the management of
exploration project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, two other projects and the study of a management device
(Multi-BU Committee) enabled testing the model. We thus confirmed the
value of previously hidden variables and offered new predictions. We
then had opportunities to test in vivo decisional ambidexterity with
several heuristics and practices with an exploration project. Moreover,
we formalized some of them in the quality management system procedures
for Innovation and Development. These practices were also validated and
complemented by interactions with the community of R&amp;amp;T Managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the last stretch of the PhD journey allowed to touch upon
the organizational metabolism and how decisional ambidexterity could
sustain the associated generative interactions around decisions and
organizational change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this chapter, we come back on the main contributions of this PhD
thesis with respect to the literature we have surveyed from the
beginning and discussed during our modelling effort (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/&#34;&gt;part&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisional ambidexterity brings an extended view of decision-making by
actively managing the design of alternatives. It brings several decision
categories which reveals different action regimes and means of
coordinating collective action. Exploration project management can
consequently be revisited through this model. We propose to have
systematic ways to sustain innovation with a hacking philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisional ambidexterity offers a way of resurfacing organization and
product design fixations, as well as interdependencies. By doing so,
exploration projects can actively target learning, knowledge management,
and we could even say unknowledge management since we are concerned by
innovative design. Furthermore, the organizational mirroring of product
engineering is embedded through the decision-design process.
Consequently, the associated organizational change, competencies
evolution and generation, organization redesign are naturally mirrored
as potential categorized decisions are envisioned.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;decisional-ambidexterity-for-exploration-project-management&#34;&gt;Decisional ambidexterity for exploration project management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our modelling effort on ambidexterity an its organization started anew
with the foundational work of James March (March

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;). His original intent for organizational learning
and adaptation was based on problem-solving and the bounded rationality
of agents exploiting routines or exploring new ones. The balance of both
regimes was a starting point for a rich literature on ambidexterity in
organizational studies, strategic management as well as innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, the construct was transposed to different research fields in
management and prescribed in practice. However, innovation management
kept developing whilst showcasing generative processes and a keen
interest to managing the unknown. The valuable literature review of
(Wilden et al. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Wilden2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;) gives an overview of the
trajectory of the ambidexterity construct. Several key academics have
also made their own assessment on their contributions to the field
(Birkinshaw and Gupta 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;; Gupta, Smith, and
Shalley 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gupta2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;; O’Reilly and Tushman

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-OReilly2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;; Benner and Tushman 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Benner2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;).
They all come to the conclusion that the relationship between
exploration and exploitation requires deeper qualitative studies to
better understand the implementation of ambidexterity. Its
decision-making and managerial capabilities have remained blurry.
Placing exploration and exploitation on a same continuum or not could be
understood in different ways depending on units of analysis (Gupta,
Smith, and Shalley 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gupta2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;). Furthermore, innovation was
seen as a potential driver shifting the performance of exploration
and/or exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the light of these calls for research, we have studied how the models
of ambidexterity relying on the assumption of the &lt;em&gt;non-mutual
conditioning between exploration and exploitation&lt;/em&gt; would behave in the
unknown. The idea was to test whether or not this strong hypothesis
based on problem-solving would hold true in the unknown. Several units
of analysis were based on adaptation or interactionism provided
frameworks for management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prospects of exploration project management (Lenfle

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/a&gt;) was a good candidate to reconnect with
innovation management and the increasing projectification. Managing the
unknown is one of its main drivers and given an exploitation regime
ruled by a project-based organization, we identified in the literature
potential shortcomings for organizational learning (Lenfle

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) and change (Pollack 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Pollack2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;;
Hornstein 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hornstein2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the heavily constrained environment of Zodiac Aerospace, this
conglomerate of SMEs offered a rich research field to question the
validity domain of ambidexterity in the unknown. Several exploration
projects and practices were studied revealing anomalies and
opportunities to experiment with a reconciliating model of
ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;avoiding-killing-innovation-in-a-constrained-environment&#34;&gt;Avoiding killing innovation in a constrained environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have shown that ambidexterity, with its underlying model of
&lt;em&gt;non-mutual conditioning between exploration and exploitation&lt;/em&gt;, can
actually kill innovation. The cases reported by Zodiac Aerospace present
a wide range of exploration projects, relying on different generative
processes. Despite having the a priori required elements to transition
these projects, go to market or have business units take over
initiatives, they would be considered as failures with no tomorrow for
exploitation, learning, adaptation, competitive advantage. Some would
only score a few partial points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These anomalies of ambidexterity can only be understood by reconsidering
the frontier of problems and decisions in the unknown. Design theories
and reasoning bring a new language for decision-making,
problem-formulation and problem-solving. The model &lt;strong&gt;decisional
ambidexterity&lt;/strong&gt; provides a new understanding of generative processes,
environment cognition, organization design, as well as collective
action. It allows tracking decisions and their design along a project’s
trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have illustrated that an exploration project can succeed in
developing a new product, in a new market, and have several business
units taking a stake in the innovation process to regenerate their
organizations. A careful work of designing decisions and understanding
what makes the decision come true is required through design of the
states of nature: market, environmental constraints, norms, standards,
users’ acceptance, etc. These heuristics of decision-designers provide
them with means of action enabling the materialization of their
innovation effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hacking-philosophy-the-decision-designer&#34;&gt;Hacking philosophy: the decision-designer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The philosophy of designing decisions can be related to hacking. Indeed,
applying design theories to decision theories offers new degrees of
freedom on a highly normative model of action. The decision-designer
does what everyone does: we choose from readily accessible alternatives
induced by path-dependency and fixation effects, and if we have or
imagine the consequences, we may be willing to generate new alternatives
and scenarios where we would be as satisfied or even more satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this satisfactory level overcomes and twists bounded
rationality (Simon 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Simon1955&#34;&gt;1955&lt;/a&gt;). We would, in fact, extend
our rationality by engaging in actions embodying what is necessary to
realize designed decisions. Instead of choosing A or B given C or D, one
can optimize consequences given a certain belief, but one can also find
a generic solution fitting all outcomes and beliefs. Or one could even
totally aim for different comparable alternatives in another scenario.
One could finally aim for &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; comparable alternatives as we mix up
other value networks in different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimization, genericity, and wishful decision by hacking one or all
states of nature sets different courses of action for project
management. The hacking is performed given parameters identified in the
originally given exploitative situation. It helps rooting, nurturing and
making sense of the exploration stretch. Conditioning is no longer seen
as reductive, it is instead expansive when designing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These statements were tested and validated by practices, discussions,
and accepted in process management procedures. But, they still raise
numerous questions on a synthetic technology of organizing to channel
interactions on the design of decisions and commitment. The need is
perfectly natural: we are tricking probability theory with a
conditioning that in reality implies hacking. Uncertainty is increased
but we counter it with means of action reconfiguring relationships and
knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is rather stimulating to think of our modelling effort as a means to
reconnect the rational augmentation hoped by Herbert Simon with the
foolishness and Romantic views of leadership by James March. A conscious
and rational model of thought led by design theory and reasoning could
occupy this grey zone. In other words, our research results targeted the
relationship between rationality and foolishness in (March

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;, 209):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is argued that the link between rationality and conventional
knowledge keeps rational technologies reliable but inhibits creative
imagination. This characterization seems plausible, but it probably
underestimates the potential contribution of rational technologies to
foolishness and radical visions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this PhD thesis, we developed this bone of contention with the mutual
conditioning between exploration and exploitation. Decisional
ambidexterity, with its decision-design and decision-making in the
unknown, offers a means to rationalize and sustain foolishness in a way.
It cools down a romantic view of decision-making and collective action
in organizations, but we offer in return manageable risks and
opportunities sustaining imagination and creativity in markets (Bronk

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Bronk2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;decisional-ambidexterity-for-organizational-ambidexterity&#34;&gt;Decisional ambidexterity for organizational ambidexterity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research made a specific focus on the encapsulated fashion of
project management. It was a means to discuss managing the unknown with
a clear view of how collective action was coordinated and the
assumptions made from an organizational standpoint. Project management
was demonstrated to be historically linked to innovation management
(Davies, Manning, and Söderlund 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Davies2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;; Lenfle and Loch

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;). It gave us a baseline
to discuss the relationship between project-based and temporary
organization (Turner 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Turner2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;; Söderlund and Müller

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Soderlund2014a&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;; Sydow, Lindkvist, and Defillippi

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Sydow2004&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/a&gt;; Bakker et al. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Bakker2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) and
exploration projects (Lenfle 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;deconstruction&amp;rdquo; path taken from the model of
exploration/exploitation (March 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;), who took us to
discussions on organizational studies, leadership and strategic
management, is now taken backwards to reconnect the encapsulated way of
separating exploration and exploitation with organizational learning and
adaptation. The new perspectives on organization design in (Van de Ven,
Ganco, and Hinings 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-VandeVen2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;; Puranam

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Puranam2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;; Avital and Te’eni 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Avital2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;) and
change management (Pollack 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Pollack2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;; Hornstein

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hornstein2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;) bring additional perspectives on &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt;
projects could interfere. The cruciality of epistemic interdependencies
is flagged as they allow reconnecting with engineering design and its
mirroring hypothesis (Colfer and Baldwin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Colfer2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were interested in organizational learning and change prospects that
tend to be regenerative. This specific feature is given by the heavily
constrained environment of Zodiac Aerospace, with numerous design rules,
standards, norms, and business units mirroring market segments with
associated engineering for certified products. The ecosystem has rather
settled after numerous acquisitions and consolidations. Business Units
have their specific niches and playfields, and are grouped in divisions
and branches for an Executive Committee. Creating spin-offs appeared out
of the equation. It would force (re-)generative learning (Senge

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Senge1990&#34;&gt;1990&lt;/a&gt;) and mirrored organizational change to overcome
core rigidities and incompetencies (Leonard-Barton

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Leonard-Barton1992&#34;&gt;1992&lt;/a&gt;; Dougherty 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dougherty1995&#34;&gt;1995&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organizational-learning-articulated-by-explorationexploitation-mutual-conditioning&#34;&gt;Organizational learning articulated by exploration/exploitation mutual conditioning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have shown cases where learning was kept isolated from exploitation
because of non-mutual conditioning assumptions. Exploration projects had
however played an active role in cultivating learning and opening new
innovation fields. Some projects even relied on a clear hacking
philosophy of exploitation regime with preferences reversal for
instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning was also inhibited because of generative processes and project
management not systematically taking on board organization design and
environmental dimensions. Exploration would be conducted for an
&lt;em&gt;iso-exploitation&lt;/em&gt; regime and it would expect that operational
organizations would learn from exploration during hand-over. Despite
clever and prepared interactions for transitions, most projects would
not articulate (enough) the exploration-exploitation mutual
conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two cases and an intervention allowed however to better identify
learning mechanisms around problem-formulation, value space and open
discussions on future decisions. Decisional ambidexterity model played a
crucial role in forcing learning and shaping the unknown to enable
decisions-making. Means of actions can be derived and a sense of
direction is given for learning. Learning of engineering design rules
and absorption of new knowledge engage decision-designers in the
reconfiguration of organization’s knowledge management. This generative
learning around decision-design would then require new relationships to
be tied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organizational-adaptation-and-change-driven-by-unlocking-fixations-and-interdependencies&#34;&gt;Organizational adaptation and change driven by unlocking fixations and interdependencies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The studied exploration projects were all potential emergent strategies
from intra or inter BU perspectives. They addressed potential
competitive advantage and adaptation to the environment. However, we
have seen that organizational ambidexterity could potentially inhibit
their prospects. Decisional ambidexterity model surfaces the criticality
of organization design fixations and interdependencies to steer
exploration projects. Otherwise, projects may float and disconnect from
host organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two contrasted cases revealed the importance of problem formulation and
managing value around what business units are capable of deciding given
their engineering capabilities. Conceptualizing the mirroring hypothesis
(Colfer and Baldwin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Colfer2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;), through the design of
decisions and organization design knowledge, forces to merge change
management with project management. It encourages also to find means
(e.g. prototypes, management tools, decisions committees, business
models, etc.) bearing the reconfiguration of relationships and knowledge
through novel designed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have shown in the researcher’s intervention and other
contributions to Zodiac Aerospace, the categorization effort in concepts
and designed decisions offer handles on interdependencies and
organization design fixations. These channelled interactions with an
effort on engineering models and mirrored organizations. They triggered
side-projects and valued positively projects that would otherwise be
simply considered deviant. We insist again on the fact that exploration
is richer and more performant by referring to exploitation. It sustains
an elasticity and plasticity in the conditioning between
exploration/exploitation offering room for organizational metabolism to
thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis-decisional-ambidexterity-a-model-for-strategic-innovation-management&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis: decisional ambidexterity, a model for strategic innovation management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This penultimate chapter portraits our main results and contributions.
The management anomaly detection revealed and confirmed several
limitations of models of ambidexterity relying on the non-mutual
conditioning between exploration/exploitation. The separation can
effectively kill innovation instead of letting it positively shift the
performance frontier of both regimes. As innovation emerges from the
unknown, its management in exploration projects is the ground for
innovative design and strategic decisions/actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a constrained environment, extremely path-dependent context and
threatened by the unknown, exploration appears more performant and
sustainable in the long run if it is mutually conditioned by
exploitation. Decision-designers can actively play with different
decision categories where hacking is performed on exploitation
parameters generating alternatives and action roadmaps to accomplish
designed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisional ambidexterity allows reconciliating with the drift of
organizational ambidexterity. The initial foundations were on
problem-solving, but with organization studies and strategic management,
it overstretched towards innovation management. The construct changed in
nature up to the point that separating and balancing may no longer be
valid for innovative design practices and managing the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consequently provided a novel way of reconnecting to the behavioural
foundations of exploration &lt;em&gt;versus&lt;/em&gt; exploitation by working on their
mutual conditioning. It provided us means to sustain innovation efforts,
as well as organizational learning and adaptation. Resurfacing
organization and product design fixations and interdependencies allowed
articulating novelty and steer generativity to simultaneously drive
product development and organizational change.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Avital2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avital, Michel, and Dov Te’eni. 2009. “From generative fit to generative
capacity: exploring an emerging dimension of information systems design
and task performance.” &lt;em&gt;Information Systems Journal&lt;/em&gt; 19 (4): 345–67.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2575.2007.00291.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2575.2007.00291.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Bakker2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bakker, Rene M., Robert J. DeFillippi, Andreas Schwab, and Jörg Sydow.
2016. “Temporary Organizing: Promises, Processes, Problems.”
&lt;em&gt;Organization Studies&lt;/em&gt; 37 (12): 1703–19.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840616655982&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840616655982&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Benner2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benner, Mary J, and Michael L Tushman. 2015. “Reflections on the 2013
Decade Award–&amp;ldquo;Exploitation, Exploration, and Process Management: The
Productivity Dilemma Revisited&amp;rdquo; Ten Years Later.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management
Review&lt;/em&gt; 40 (4): 497–514. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2015.0042&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2015.0042&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birkinshaw, Julian, and Kamini Gupta. 2013. “Clarifying the distinctive
contribution of ambidexterity to the field of organization studies.”
&lt;em&gt;The Academy of Management Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; 27 (4): 287–98.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Bronk2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bronk, Richard. 2009. “Imagination and creativity in markets.” In &lt;em&gt;The
Romantic Economist: Imagination in Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 196–224. Cambridge
University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Christiansen2007&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christiansen, John K., and Claus J. Varnes. 2007. “Making decisions on
innovation: Meetings or networks?” &lt;em&gt;Creativity and Innovation
Management&lt;/em&gt; 16 (3): 282–98.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8691.2007.00441.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8691.2007.00441.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Colfer2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colfer, Lyra J., and Carliss Y. Baldwin. 2016. “The mirroring
hypothesis: Theory, evidence, and exceptions.” &lt;em&gt;Industrial and Corporate
Change&lt;/em&gt; 25 (5): 709–38. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/icc/dtw027&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/icc/dtw027&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Davies2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davies, Andrew, Stephan Manning, and Jonas Söderlund. 2018. “When
neighboring disciplines fail to learn from each other: The case of
innovation and project management research.” &lt;em&gt;Research Policy&lt;/em&gt; 47 (5):
965–79. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2018.03.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2018.03.002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Dougherty1995&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dougherty, Deborah. 1995. “Managing your core incompetencies for
corporate venturing.” &lt;em&gt;Entrepreneurship: Theory and Practice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gupta2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gupta, Anil K, Ken G Smith, and Christina E Shalley. 2006. “The
Interplay Between Exploration and Exploitation.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management
Journal&lt;/em&gt; 49 (4): 693–706. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amj.2006.22083026&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amj.2006.22083026&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hornstein2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hornstein, Henry A. 2015. “The integration of project management and
organizational change management is now a necessity.” &lt;em&gt;International
Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 33 (2): 291–98.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.08.005&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.08.005&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lenfle2008&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenfle, Sylvain. 2008. “Exploration and project management.”
&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 26 (5): 469–78.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2008.05.017&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2008.05.017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lenfle2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2016. “Floating in Space? On the Strangeness of Exploratory
Projects.” &lt;em&gt;Project Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 47 (2): 15.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21584&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21584&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lenfle2010&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenfle, Sylvain, and Christoph Loch. 2010. “Lost Roots: How Project
Management Came to Emphasize Control over Flexibility and Novelty.”
&lt;em&gt;California Management Review&lt;/em&gt; 53 (1): 32–55.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1525/cmr.2010.53.1.32&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1525/cmr.2010.53.1.32&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lenfle2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2017. &lt;em&gt;Has Megaproject Management Lost Its Way?&lt;/em&gt; Edited by Bent
Flyvbjerg. Vol. 1. November 2015. Oxford University Press.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780198732242.013.2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780198732242.013.2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Leonard-Barton1992&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leonard-Barton, Dorothy. 1992. “Core capabilities and core rigidities: A
paradox in managing new product development.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic Management
Journal&lt;/em&gt; 13 (1 S): 111–25. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.4250131009&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.4250131009&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-March1991&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March, James G. 1991. “Exploration and exploitation in organizational
learning.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 2: 71–87.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-March2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March, James G. 2006. “Rationality, foolishness, and adaptive
intelligence.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 27 (3): 201–14.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.515&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.515&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-OReilly2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Reilly, C. A., and M. L. Tushman. 2013. “Organizational Ambidexterity:
Past, Present, and Future.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; 27 (4):
324–38. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amp.2013.0025&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amp.2013.0025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Pollack2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pollack, Julien. 2017. “Change Management as an Organizational and
Project Capability.” In &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Handbook of Organizational Project
Management&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Shankar Sankaran, Ralf Muller, and Nathalie
Drouin, 236–49. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316662243.021&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316662243.021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Puranam2012&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puranam, Phanish. 2012. “A Future for the Science of Organization
Design.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organization Design&lt;/em&gt; 1 (1): 18.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7146/jod.6337&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.7146/jod.6337&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Senge1990&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senge, Peter. 1990. “Leaders’ new role: building learning
organizations.” &lt;em&gt;MIT Sloan Management Review&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Simon1955&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon, Herbert A. 1955. “A Behavioral Model of Rational Choice.” &lt;em&gt;The
Quarterly Journal of Economics&lt;/em&gt; 69 (1): 99.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/1884852&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/1884852&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Soderlund2014a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Söderlund, Jonas, and Ralf Müller. 2014. “Project Management and
Organization Theory: IRNOP Meets PMJ.” &lt;em&gt;Project Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 45
(4): 2–6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21442&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21442&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Sydow2004&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sydow, Jörg, Lars Lindkvist, and Robert Defillippi. 2004. “Project-Based
Organizations, Embeddedness and Repositories of Knowledge: Editorial.”
&lt;em&gt;Organization Studies&lt;/em&gt; 25 (9): 1475–89.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840604048162&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840604048162&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Turner2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turner, J. Rodney. 2009. &lt;em&gt;The handbook of Project Based Management&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-VandeVen2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van de Ven, Andrew H., Martin Ganco, and C. R. (BOB) Hinings. 2013.
“Returning to the Frontier of Contingency Theory of Organizational and
Institutional Designs.” &lt;em&gt;The Academy of Management Annals&lt;/em&gt; 7 (1):
393–440. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/19416520.2013.774981&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/19416520.2013.774981&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Wilden2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilden, Ralf, Jan Hohberger, Timothy M. Devinney, and Dovev Lavie. 2018.
“Revisiting James March (1991): Whither exploration and exploitation?”
&lt;em&gt;Strategic Organization&lt;/em&gt; 16 (3): 352–69.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1476127018765031&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1476127018765031&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 14 - Discussion and perspectives for decisional ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part6/chapter14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part6/chapter14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this final chapter, we open up our conclusion for discussions on our
model of decisional ambidexterity and research perspectives. We have so
far reworked the conditioning between exploration and exploitation. This
modulation allows reconnecting models of ambidexterity with managing the
unknown. It holds true that exploration and exploitation should be
mutually conditioned in a constrained environment with rules, norms,
regulations, path dependency sensitive to potential threats of
disruption. It avoids deteriorating both regimes. It actually supports a
sustainable generativity, organizational change and design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developed model of decisional ambidexterity tries to reconnect
decision theories with design theories. We have shown how the unknown
could be integrated. With the rising projectification of firms and the
economy, exploration projects heavily discuss organizational learning
and adaptation. Organizational ambidexterity and design implemented by
top management should then be reviewed at the light of meso-level
analyses at work in projects driven by decision-design and the
unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, designing decisions, from the standpoint of cognitive
psychology and even behavioural economics, can be seen as paradoxical.
For decision-making on one hand, research agendas have studied and
modelled the influence of biases and heuristics (Tversky and Kahneman

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Tversky1974&#34;&gt;1974&lt;/a&gt;; Kahneman and Tversky

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Kahneman1979a&#34;&gt;1979&lt;/a&gt;; Kahneman 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Kahneman2011&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;).
Moreover, different dispositional variables, such as stress or positive
emotions and other conditioning settings can be added to measure their
influence (Cassotti et al. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Cassotti2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, psychology of creativity has been driven by how
individuals and groups generate ideas. Instead of decision biases, they
would discuss fixation effects and its inhibitory control (Cassotti et
al. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Cassotti2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) on generativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two research streams stand on different grounds. They rely on
different perspectives of rationality and use different experimental
protocols. How could we provide a general model of generation of
alternatives, their selection and commitment? How should experiments be
conducted to grasp design during decision tasks? Like decisional
ambidexterity providing a &amp;ldquo;unifying&amp;rdquo; framework, we would wonder about a
unified theory of generativity and choice. Or at least, we are curious
about pushing both models towards a common asymptote where uncertainty
becomes unknown and where the unknown becomes uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have considered hacking practices for decision-designers. All &lt;em&gt;silent
designers&lt;/em&gt; in organizations (Dumas and Mintzberg 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dumas1989&#34;&gt;1989&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dumas1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;) could then offer new means of collective action
for corporate entrepreneurship and radical innovation (O’Connor

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-OConnor2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;). Not only is institutionalizing innovation
necessary to recognize the phenomena and avoiding ineffective risk
taking, but it can also be sustained with &lt;em&gt;technologies of organizing&lt;/em&gt;.
The importance of valuation tools and methods when designing decisions
would be critical to manage exploration projects but also for
organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of an &lt;em&gt;Organizational Design Thinking&lt;/em&gt; would be quite
stimulating. Common design thinking methodology will be fixated by users
and a given ontology of operations in the ecosystem. Tackling users
pains and building empathy helps generating concepts where users can
easily adopt, interact with and open new perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could we imagine a decision-design methodology where the purpose is to
promote concepts that systematically address what will federate
organization around a common purpose? It would be a sort of positive
&lt;em&gt;no-man’s land&lt;/em&gt; that drives learning and change, instead of fighting for
primacy or against inertia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The valuation methods would be critical to target the cracks between
organizations and to generate such concepts targeting organizational
constraints and drivers. The Lower Deck project would appear as a
suitable example by contrast with the Connected Cabin (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter10/&#34;&gt;chapter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, our concern for valuation tools and organizational design
thinking brings us to discuss a renewed organization design: &lt;em&gt;generative
organization design&lt;/em&gt;. In the literature, we have pointed at several
authors inviting to rethink this research topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modelling effort concretized into decisional ambidexterity took
organization design as knowledge to generate new concepts and keep an
eye on mirroring dynamics. There would not be any target organization
design since we focus on engineering design and decisions. For open
innovation, problem formulation and solving will be driven through a
decision-design practice. Partnering with users, suppliers, integrators
and even competitors would have a different twist. Separate and
interconnected agendas could support different decision categories
engaged with the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If designed decisions drive organization re-design, what would be the
managerial action in such context? What is the governance of such
distributed and generative innovation function?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Firstly, the decisional ambidexterity model developed in our thesis and
in two articles (Le Masson et al. &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeMasson2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;; Le Glatin,
Le Masson, and Weil &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;) raises several questions
and perspectives on how the frontier can be bridged between cognitive
psychology for decision-making and creativity. The theoretical
implications are critical for both fields when pushing their models to a
common asymptote of unknown/uncertainty. It questions also
experimentation means to think of decisions upon generated and given
choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the spirit of hacking we have promoted around decisions,
interdependencies and organization/product design fixations effects,
encourages to rethink valuation methods and methodology to drive
exploration project management in a cluster of firms. An &lt;em&gt;Organizational
Design Thinking&lt;/em&gt; would help formalizing methods specifically targeting
organizational learning and adaptation around concepts carefully
designed based on existing exploitation regimes in organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we reconsider the concept of generative organization design with
the reconfigurability driven by innovative design in engineering
projects. We discuss also how the engineering design practice can embed
the concern to overcome and manage organization design fixations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bridge-between-decision-and-generativity&#34;&gt;A bridge between decision and generativity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When facing a decision task, alternatives are given to the
decision-maker. However, we have brought forward that in the course of
action, rational choice of theory has several limitations (Le Glatin, Le
Masson, and Weil 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;). One could be &lt;em&gt;irrational&lt;/em&gt;
with respect to several paradoxes that can be embraced in prospect
theory for instance (Kahneman and Tversky 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Kahneman1979a&#34;&gt;1979&lt;/a&gt;).
Reversing preferences in time or willingly complexifies the
understanding of decision-making (Slovic 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Slovic1995&#34;&gt;1995&lt;/a&gt;;
Camerer, Loewenstein, and Rabin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Camerer2004&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/a&gt;; Machina

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Machina1989&#34;&gt;1989&lt;/a&gt;; Chabris, Laibson, and Schuldt

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Chabris2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decision theories stemming and extending the works of Abraham Wald
(Wald 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Wald1949&#34;&gt;1949&lt;/a&gt;; Savage 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Savage1954&#34;&gt;1954&lt;/a&gt;; Giocoli

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Giocoli2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;; Fourcade and Khurana

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Fourcade2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;), inconsistency or intransitivity are
violations of rationality. A simple way of accepting such violation is
the integration of new information in time. Otherwise, considering that
the decision-maker generates new decisions and actions, to gain
information given a bounded problem, unsettles rational theories of
choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bounding-and-unbounding-problems&#34;&gt;Bounding and unbounding problems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rational theories of choice, operational research and refinements
brought by cognitive psychology have taken a rationally bounded
perspective on agents. A problem would be predefined, the agent will
struggle to oversee the full landscape and will follow the &lt;em&gt;path of
least resistance&lt;/em&gt; and be biased. However, the perspectives from
creativity theory or generativity theory (Epstein et al.

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Epstein1984&#34;&gt;1984&lt;/a&gt;; Epstein 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Epstein1990&#34;&gt;1990&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Epstein1999&#34;&gt;1999&lt;/a&gt;) tend to unbound problems or at least
reformulate them. New decisions can be designed and engaged given
problem parameters; it was the case for pigeons solving their problem.
In a more ill-defined setting, design can not only optimize, find
generic solutions or recombine, it can also revamp altogether the
problem at stake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question for us would be to understand what are the parameters that
would trigger the need to design instead of simply deciding. Is it
comparable to risk aversion/seeking behaviours? The major difference is
when designing, an active interaction is engaged with the environment
instead of a passive one expecting for the states of nature to reveal.
The decision-designer would hope to generate new knowledge and tie new
relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue is with the very construction of probabilities. Imprecision
and fuzzy sets could be a first patch. Unfortunately, they do not model
the reconfiguration and complete revaluation of alternatives and states
of nature. Even if a theoretical effort is required for theories of
behaviour, extending for instance prospect theory with design reasoning,
we could also turn towards experimentation’s means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;differences-in-experimental-protocols&#34;&gt;Differences in experimental protocols&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our interest would be in the inhibitors and triggers for designing
decisions. Some situations could be intolerable for decision-making,
perhaps they could support the generation of other alternatives
countering a priori consequences. Moral judgement and ethical behaviour
could be an exciting approach to unlock the deliberate will to design
decisions instead of deciding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, the trolley problem extensively studied by Judith Thomson
(Thomson 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Thomson1976&#34;&gt;1976&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Thomson1985&#34;&gt;1985&lt;/a&gt;,

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Thomson2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/a&gt;) could be an interesting baseline to discuss
the design of new alternatives and what could trigger it. This problem
also concerns autonomous driving (Bonnefon, Shariff, and Rahwan

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Bonnefon2015&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;). The matter is given in an iso-environment
for the car, whereas it could be perhaps even more stimulating to think
of autonomous cars actively protecting pedestrians (i.e. not just with
shock absorbers, sensors to detect the variety of obstacles and
pedestrians and deciding).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difficulty in approaching experimentation at the frontier of
decision and creativity is the protocol and briefs given to the
decider/designer. It may totally inhibit one or the other whereas we
would be more curious about the comings and goings between the two.
Since the &lt;em&gt;Centre de Gestion Scientifique&lt;/em&gt; has a partnership with the
&lt;em&gt;LabPsyDé&lt;/em&gt; of Descartes University, we already had several discussions
on these topics with Anaëlle Camarda and Matthieu Cassotti. We had some
ideas for moral judgement, studying the anchoring effects of Kahneman
and Tversky with respect to design, but also biases for negative
conditioning and asking for information like in Wason’s experiment
(Wason 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Wason1960&#34;&gt;1960&lt;/a&gt;; Houdé and Moutier

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Houde1996&#34;&gt;1996&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reexplaining-behaviours-biases-heuristics-and-hacking&#34;&gt;Reexplaining behaviours: biases, heuristics and hacking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, designing decisions in the unknown encourages the decider
to interact and interfere with his beliefs and states of nature. Biases
and heuristics could contribute to the dominant design and fixation
effects. However, decision hacking with genericity and wishful decisions
reveal another behaviour providing a more positive and pro-active
feature of rationality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the increasing number of practices promoted in start-up
environment, we wonder how we could study in more detail the behaviours
associated with effectuation (Sarasvathy 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Sarasvathy2001&#34;&gt;2001&lt;/a&gt;;
Agogué, Lundqvist, and Middleton 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Agogue2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;), lean start-up
(Ries 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Ries2011a&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;; Blank 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Blank2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;), growth
hacking, incompleteness by design (Garud, Jain, and Tuertscher

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Garud2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/a&gt;) and platform strategies (Gawer and Cusumano

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gawer2014&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;). The practices could easily be explained with
decision-design and they could also benefit from research on cognitive
psychology around the heuristics developed to make and design decisions
in entrepreneurship and early-stage decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These comments are also valid for finance in venture capitalism and
private equity. From early-stage to A/B/C/D rounds, investments are also
promising grounds to understand the logics of decisions, information
gathering and influence on strategy through corporate governance bodies.
Hopefully, some answers will be found in the PhD results of Laure-Anne
Parpaleix (&lt;em&gt;Centre Gestion Scientifique&lt;/em&gt;, Mines ParisTech, and CIFRE
contract with BPI France).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organizational-design-thinking-and-management-devices&#34;&gt;Organizational Design Thinking and management devices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model of decisional ambidexterity offers a valuable basis to track
and explain projects. It can also be used to derive means of actions and
valuation practices. However, it would be interesting to reconnect with
existing methodologies and management tools providing valuation for
decision-making and action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods like platform engineering and Design Thinking were referred to
in two case studies. The first has a strong logic on economic evaluation
with modularity benefits (Sanchez and Mahoney 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Sanchez1996&#34;&gt;1996&lt;/a&gt;).
The second builds on user empathy and generative practices incorporating
such knowledge. We have revealed that both were minored by outdated
models of ambidexterity. However, it would encourage to &lt;em&gt;engineer&lt;/em&gt;
heuristics and valuation methods in order to steer their generativity
countering the limitations of organizational ambidexterity. In the
philosophy of hacking, we would prefer thinking of Judo or Aikido moves
where light imbalances are turned into an advantage. It echoes the
&lt;em&gt;phronesis&lt;/em&gt; (Nonaka, Hirose, and Takeda 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Nonaka2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;), and
&lt;em&gt;sensing, seizing and reconfiguring&lt;/em&gt; of (Teece 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Teece2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;).
This economic vigilance would use organization design fixation effects
and valuation tools to guide Design Thinking and platform architecture.
This vigilance would consequently guide exploration project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;from-user-pains-and-needs-to-recombination-of-organizational-routines&#34;&gt;From user pains and needs to recombination of organizational routines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The divergent and convergent phases, with multiple feedback loops of
Design Thinking could also be driven by organizational design. We have
shown that their fixations can be hard to overcome because of external
biases, so it is worth endogenizing such constraints to generate new
alternatives and concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, the Design Thinking cases, by comparison with the later
Lower Deck project, show the importance of problem formulation, concept
positioning, decision enablers and value space. These elements were part
of the &lt;em&gt;innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; descriptor. The Lower Deck
project formulated a concept that would overcome several limitations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUs will struggle to see the value of working around a common
purpose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUs will takeover the full project for primacy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUs engineering and marketing departments may not able to value
learning and adaptation to a whole new environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUs will prefer waiting for the clients to manifest new use cases
and new ecosystems interdependencies, instead of proposing new ones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lower Deck built upon the lessons and attempts of previous projects,
where it was a design feature or enabler for other functional
objectives. However, by managing its value temporarily in a empty space
unoccupied by BUs, the concept managed to create sufficient attraction
for business units to federate along a common purpose of learning and
recombining their engineering routines. Indeed, constraining
certification and market demand were shaped in a way that organizational
barriers can be lowered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, an &lt;em&gt;Organizational Design Thinking&lt;/em&gt; would specifically
target what organizations can’t do on their own. However, it is not a
simple technology to be outsourced and integrated. The Connected Cabin
project highlighted these limitations. Instead, the concepts aim for
reconfiguring interdependencies between BUs, engineering rules and
interfaces, as well as the ecosystem. It is not driven by organization
pains, but it would focus on existing organization design and routines.
One could then search for &lt;em&gt;cracks&lt;/em&gt; left by interdependencies and design
systematically what BUs can’t do by themselves. We would be thrilled to
study these areas with Lisa Carlgren (Chalmers University) and Katharina
Hölzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;valuation-methods-innovation-potential&#34;&gt;Valuation methods: innovation potential&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A means to drive the generation of concepts and potential decisions
could also around valuation methods. The mutual-conditioning between
exploration and exploitation would inspire us to look simply on existing
tools and devices. Relying on &lt;em&gt;net present value&lt;/em&gt; calculations, business
plans and real options could offer numerous opportunities for designing
new alternatives and concepts corresponding to hacked valuation methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if several scenarios are presented for a business plan
(e.g. pessimistic, nominal and optimistic), one could design
alternatives offering them complementary background and comparison. But,
the designed decisions could help to think of what should be done for
the most favourable scenario. This design practice forces to interact
differently with the formalism expected from valuation methods. Problems
are inverted. In that perspective, we hope the PhD works of Agathe
Gillain (&lt;em&gt;Centre de Gestion Scientifique&lt;/em&gt;, CIFRE contract at Airbus)
will provide some answers on the economic performance of R&amp;amp;D investments
with respect to learning strategies for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the members of the R&amp;amp;T community had reported developing a
selection tools for concepts. Not only would it filter them based on
criteria agreed with stakeholders, but they also planned in having a
derived scoring that would warn decision-makers to reformulate some
concept’s acceptance. In other words, besides filtering, some concepts
would trigger to imagine of different states of nature and criteria to
accept them. Consequently, it forces stakeholders to review their
department’s capabilities, knowledge and relationships across
interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, our perspective on valuation is that decisional
ambidexterity and the hacking philosophy promoted with decision-design
in the unknown, could support exploration project management. What is
even more exciting is that we would use exploitation frameworks to
articulate the exploration regime and generative processes. The distance
between the two regimes could be measured through this clever
conditioning with performance criteria traditionally used. It would
avoid isolation between the two as they would use a common language and
management tools but have a different relationship to these artefacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intervention for Hypoxia Protection project revealed the usefulness
and generativity of such heuristics applied to product conformity
matrices (e.g. house of quality) and technical feasibility and
performance (e.g. physical measures). In the sociology and ethnography
literature, we would also look for echoes of this dual relationship with
management devices for exploitation nurturing exploration and preparing
its acceptance. It could offer new actions means for marketing as the
level unknow heavily contests existing relationships. For instance, the
works of Liliana Doganova (Centre for the Sociology of Innovation, Mines
ParisTech) on the performativity of valuation devices could be revisited
with generativity practices. This concern for exploration project
valuation could also be refined in the future with the ongoing works of
Svenja Sommer, Kathrin Möslein and Sylvain Lenfle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;generative-organization-design-and-governance&#34;&gt;Generative organization design and governance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this final section, we will address organization design and
governance based on the previous discussions. The cognition, interaction
and valuation conveyed in decisional ambidexterity opened stimulating
areas to reflect on. Earlier in the manuscript, we had taken a keen
interest on organization design and its practice. The conglomerate of
SMEs, Zodiac Aerospace, had stressed this dimension for engineering,
marketing, market arrangements and group strategic decision-making.
Since, the field is willing to renew itself (Barry

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Barry2011&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;; Van de Ven, Ganco, and Hinings

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-VandeVen2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;), we propose to discuss its relationship with
generative processes at work for the Innovation function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The influence of managing as design (Boland and Collopy

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Boland2004&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/a&gt;), as discussed in our literature review, can be
bring a different viewpoint on organization design (Romme

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Romme2003&#34;&gt;2003&lt;/a&gt;). The place given to generative processes
scattered across the firm, like the existence of &lt;em&gt;silent designers&lt;/em&gt;
(Dumas and Mintzberg 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dumas1989&#34;&gt;1989&lt;/a&gt;; Dumas

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dumas1994&#34;&gt;1994&lt;/a&gt;), can easily allow us to think of design-driven
organizations. It doesn’t necessarily mean that the firm focuses on
design services, nor that design methodologies are institutionalized
such as firms having embraced Design Thinking, C-K Theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we would rather be leaning towards a weaker form of design
reasoning distributed across the firm, cultivated by the mutual
conditioning between exploration and exploitation. In other words, we
would &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; organize collective action for
a target organization design. We would instead prefer offering the
management tools and managerial philosophy through a specific governance
for innovation. The organization will design &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt; through clearly
managed devices, decision-design and a overarching governance body
overlooking this fractal organization (Nonaka et al.

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Nonaka2014&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;governance-of-innovation-function---problem-re-formulation&#34;&gt;Governance of Innovation function - problem re-formulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a simple rule and heuristic constantly challenging and designing
decisions could be used as a pattern to generate organization designs in
non-deterministic fashion. Problems are constantly reformulated and
solved but without relying specifically on leadership or top management
as suggested by (Lakhani, Lifshitz-Assaf, and Tushman

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lakhani2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A culture of design and decision would be formalized through the dual
relationship of mutual-conditioning of exploration/exploitation regimes.
Re-articulating the decisions and problems vertically, among internal
stakeholders but also with the &lt;em&gt;exterior&lt;/em&gt;, raises questions on the
nature of innovation function’s governance. The writings for the ZAOS
&lt;em&gt;Innovate&lt;/em&gt; process addressed such heuristics around the overly famous
innovation funnel. We realized that beyond the institutionalization of
the innovation function (O’Connor 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-OConnor2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) and
associated practices reported by R&amp;amp;T managers and in projects, having a
governance body for innovation could emphasize the strategic importance
of concepts and their associated decision-design scoping. The Multi-BU
committee could have been a corporate example. Problems being
reformulated and solved by managing the unknown would require to
re-engineer interdependencies echoing its organization design
mirroring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would encourage to continue these discussions with Dominique Laousse,
Head of Foresight and Innovative Group at SNCF. He recently defended his
PhD at the &lt;em&gt;Centre de Gestion Scientifique&lt;/em&gt; under the supervision of
Sophie Hooge and Armand Hatchuel. Looking back on the deployment of the
innovation function at SNCF, he proposes a staged analysis: from
institutionalization, to industrialization (with innovative design
projects derived from C-K theory - DKCP) and up to organization and
governance. This governance topic reflects also the works of Blanche
Segrestin, Kevin Levillain and Armand Hatchuel on purpose-driven
companies. Some teachings could possibly be drawn from the ongoing PhD
thesis of Jeremy Levêque on firms’ &lt;em&gt;mission drift&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;governance-of-innovation-function---design-oriented-organization&#34;&gt;Governance of Innovation function - design-oriented organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This extreme reconfigurability organized around a new relationship to
decision-making by decision-design could perhaps preliminary
perspectives to the multi-dimensional organizations (Galbraith

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Galbraith2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;). However, there is no target organization
design managed and prescribed. Local action through projects, designed
decisions and a governance body would sustain new relationships with the
environment. This generativity theory of organizing (Van de Ven, Ganco,
and Hinings 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-VandeVen2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;), clearly endogenizes change
management in project management (Pollack 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Pollack2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it places the unknown at the heart of management. Managers
transfer, solve, and formulate problems that those who report to them
can’t solve given their knowledge and relationships. A governance body,
dedicated to the unknown through decision-design, would manage its
cognition of the environment and strategic health check-up. These
perspectives were foreshadowed in the works of Henri Fayol (Fayol

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Fayol1916&#34;&gt;1916&lt;/a&gt;). It is worth pointing out that many would only
retain the control and regulation roles of Fayol’s management principles
(Turner and Keegan 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Turner2001&#34;&gt;2001&lt;/a&gt;; Hodgson

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hodgson2004&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/a&gt;; Olin and Wickenberg 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Olin2001&#34;&gt;2001&lt;/a&gt;),
whereas he would also insist on strategic knowledge management,
relationships with the ecosystem and scientific work (Hatchuel and
Segrestin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;; Hatchuel, Le Masson, and Weil

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2002a&#34;&gt;2002&lt;/a&gt;). These practices and heuristics would enact
a design-oriented organization (Hatchuel, Weil, and Le Masson

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;) giving a different flavour to the &lt;em&gt;generative
fit&lt;/em&gt; (Avital and Te’eni 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Avital2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;). Finally, these
concerns would encourage to reconsider the place of entrepreneurship and
innovation within the organizations with emergent strategies synonymous
with design (Drucker 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Drucker1985&#34;&gt;1985&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis-decisional-ambidexterity-a-model-contributing-to-perspectives-opened-in-literature&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis: decisional ambidexterity, a model contributing to perspectives opened in literature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this final chapter, we have opened the discussions towards extensions
of our work. We proposed to do so by articulating them with key readings
already solicited in our literature view. Several stimulation
perspectives are offered to connect this thesis work with ongoing
research and historical writings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started with the cognitive psychology and behavioural concern for our
model of decisional ambidexterity. The decision-design needed to extend
decision-making in the unknown calls for future research on theoretical
models, mathematical foundations discussing the definition of
probabilities. A complex task is also ahead of us to experiment and
study the comings and goings between designing and deciding. Some leads
around moral judgement could be a starter for our prospects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of &lt;em&gt;Organization Design Thinking&lt;/em&gt; equipped with relevant
value management tools would also be a stimulating area of research. We
would extend Design Thinking methodologies to interactively foster
generativity around exploitation and organization design fixations.
Exploration projects would target what business units are not able to
do. These organizations would then find a common purpose for working
together. Furthermore, using common language of exploitation and its
limitations could be used in favour of exploration projects and value
management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, the previous perspectives encourage to avoid
thinking of Organization Design as a practice aiming for an organization
target. Instead, the role of generativity in projects quickly challenges
potential strategic decisions requiring more than institutionalization:
a governance body dedicated to the innovation function. Problem
reformulation would be nurtured by the mutual conditioning between
exploration and exploitation. It would orientate the whole organization
altogether towards design: a generative organization design. Governance
would embrace strategy design, intrapreneurship and organization’s
regenerative capabilities through the overarching vigilance of
decision-design.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Agogue2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agogué, Marine, Mats Lundqvist, and Karen Williams Middleton. 2015.
“Mindful Deviation through Combining Causation and Effectuation: A
Design Theory-Based Study of Technology Entrepreneurship.” &lt;em&gt;Creativity
and Innovation Management&lt;/em&gt; 24 (4): 629–44.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/caim.12134&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/caim.12134&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Avital2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avital, Michel, and Dov Te’eni. 2009. “From generative fit to generative
capacity: exploring an emerging dimension of information systems design
and task performance.” &lt;em&gt;Information Systems Journal&lt;/em&gt; 19 (4): 345–67.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2575.2007.00291.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2575.2007.00291.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Barry2011&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barry, David. 2011. “Re-designing organization design.” In &lt;em&gt;Designing
Business and Management&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Sabine Junginger and Jürgen Faust,
81–92. Bloomsbury Academic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Blank2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blank, Steve. 2013. “Why the Lean Start Up Changes Everything.” &lt;em&gt;Harvard
Business Review&lt;/em&gt; 91 (5): 64. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/Agile.2012.18&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/Agile.2012.18&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Boland2004&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boland, J, and Fred Collopy. 2004. &lt;em&gt;Managing as design&lt;/em&gt;. Stanford, CA:
Stanford Business Books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Bonnefon2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonnefon, J.-F., Azim Shariff, and Iyad Rahwan. 2016. “The social
dilemma of autonomous vehicles.” &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; 352 (6293): 1573–6.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaf2654&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaf2654&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Camerer2004&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camerer, Colin, George Loewenstein, and Matthew Rabin. 2004. “Behavioral
Economics: Past, Present, Future.” &lt;em&gt;Advances in Behavioral Economics&lt;/em&gt;,
2–51. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/citeulike-article-id:568162&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/citeulike-article-id:568162&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Cassotti2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassotti, Mathieu, Marine Agogué, Anaëlle Camarda, Olivier Houdé, and
Grégoire Borst. 2016. “Inhibitory Control as a Core Process of Creative
Problem Solving and Idea Generation from Childhood to Adulthood.” &lt;em&gt;New
Directions for Child and Adolescent Development&lt;/em&gt; 2016 (151): 61–72.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/cad.20153&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/cad.20153&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Cassotti2012&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassotti, Mathieu, Marianne Habib, Nicolas Poirel, Ania Aïte, Olivier
Houdé, and Sylvain Moutier. 2012. “Positive emotional context eliminates
the framing effect in decision-making.” &lt;em&gt;Emotion&lt;/em&gt; 12 (5): 926–31.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/a0026788&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/a0026788&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Chabris2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chabris, Christopher F., David I. Laibson, and Jonathon P. Schuldt.
2006. “Intertemporal choice.” &lt;em&gt;The New Palgrave Dictionary of
Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 1–11. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1746-1049.2009.00080.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1746-1049.2009.00080.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Drucker1985&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drucker, Peter. 1985. &lt;em&gt;Innovation and Entrepreneurship&lt;/em&gt;. 2015th ed. New
York, USA: Routledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Dumas1994&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dumas, Angela. 1994. “Building Totems:Metaphor-Making in Product
Development.” &lt;em&gt;Design Management Journal (Former Series)&lt;/em&gt; 5 (1): 71–82.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1948-7169.1994.tb00620.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1948-7169.1994.tb00620.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Dumas1989&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dumas, Angela, and Henry Mintzberg. 1989. “Managing Design Designing
Management.” &lt;em&gt;Design Management Journal (Former Series)&lt;/em&gt; 1 (1): 37–43.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1948-7169.1989.tb00519.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1948-7169.1989.tb00519.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Dumas1991&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 1991. “Managing the Form, Function, and Fit of Design.” &lt;em&gt;Design
Management Journal (Former Series)&lt;/em&gt; 2 (3): 26–31.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1948-7169.1991.tb00573.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1948-7169.1991.tb00573.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Epstein1984&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein, R, C E Kirshnit, R P Lanza, and L C Rubin. 1984. “Insight in
the pigeon: antecedents and determinants of an intelligent performance.”
&lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; 308 (5954): 61–62. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/308061a0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/308061a0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Epstein1990&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein, Robert. 1990. “Generativity Theory and Creativity.” In
&lt;em&gt;Theories of Creativity&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Mark A. Runco and Robert S. Albert,
116–40. Sage Publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Epstein1999&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 1999. “Generativity Theory.” In &lt;em&gt;Encyclopedia of Creativity&lt;/em&gt;,
759–66. Washington, DC, USA: Academic Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Fayol1916&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fayol, Henri. 1916. &lt;em&gt;Administration Industrielle et Générale&lt;/em&gt;. Edited by
ÉDI-GESTION &amp;amp; ANDESE. Luc MARCO.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://f.hypotheses.org/wp-content/blogs.dir/1931/files/2016/09/Fayol-1916.pdf&#34;&gt;https://f.hypotheses.org/wp-content/blogs.dir/1931/files/2016/09/Fayol-1916.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Fourcade2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourcade, Marion, and Rakesh Khurana. 2013. “From social control to
financial economics: the linked ecologies of economics and business in
twentieth century America.” &lt;em&gt;Theory and Society&lt;/em&gt; 42 (2): 121–59.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11186-012-9187-3&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11186-012-9187-3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Galbraith2010&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galbraith, Jay R. 2010. “The Multi-Dimensional and Reconfigurable
Organization.” &lt;em&gt;Organizational Dynamics&lt;/em&gt; 39 (2): 115–25.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.orgdyn.2010.02.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.orgdyn.2010.02.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Garud2008&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garud, Raghu, Sanjay Jain, and Philipp Tuertscher. 2008. “Incomplete by
Design and Designing for Incompleteness.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Studies&lt;/em&gt; 29 (3):
351–71. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840607088018&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840607088018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gawer2014&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawer, Annabelle, and Michael Cusumano. 2014. “Platforms and
Innovation.” In &lt;em&gt;The Oxford Handbook of Innovation Management&lt;/em&gt;, 1–23.
April 2018. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199694945.013.014&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199694945.013.014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Giocoli2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giocoli, Nicola. 2013. “From Wald to Savage: Homo Economicus Becomes a
Bayesian Statistician.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of the History of the Behavioral
Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 49 (1): 63–95. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/jhbs.21579&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/jhbs.21579&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hatchuel2002a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatchuel, Armand, Pascal Le Masson, and Benoît Weil. 2002. “From
knowledge management to design-oriented organisations Introduction :
knowledge management.” &lt;em&gt;International Social Science Journal&lt;/em&gt; 54 (171):
25–37. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/1468-2451.00356&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/1468-2451.00356&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hatchuel2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatchuel, Armand, and Blanche Segrestin. 2018. “A century old and still
visionary: Fayol’s innovative theory of management.” &lt;em&gt;European
Management Review&lt;/em&gt; Special Is (June): 14.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/emre.12292&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/emre.12292&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hatchuel2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatchuel, Armand, Benoît Weil, and Pascal Le Masson. 2006. “Building
innovation capabilities. The development of design-oriented
organizations.” In &lt;em&gt;Innovation, Learning and Macro Institutional Change:
Patterns of Knowledge Changes&lt;/em&gt;, edited by J T Hage, 1–26. Oxford,
England: Oxford University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hodgson2004&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hodgson, Damian E. 2004. “Project Work: The Legacy of Bureaucratic
Control in the Post-Bureaucratic Organization.” &lt;em&gt;Organization&lt;/em&gt; 11 (1):
81–100. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1350508404039659&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1350508404039659&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Houde1996&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Houdé, Olivier, and Sylvain Moutier. 1996. “Deductive reasoning and
experimental inhibition training: The case of the matching bias.”
&lt;em&gt;Cahiers de Psychologie Cognitive/Current Psychology of Cognition&lt;/em&gt; 15
(4): 409–34.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Kahneman2011&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kahneman, Daniel. 2011. &lt;em&gt;Thinking, fast and slow&lt;/em&gt;. London, England:
Penguin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Kahneman1979a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kahneman, Daniel, and Amos Tversky. 1979. “Prospect Theory: An Analysis
of Decision under Risk.” &lt;em&gt;Econometrica&lt;/em&gt; 47 (2): 263.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/1914185&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/1914185&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lakhani2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lakhani, Karim R., Hila Lifshitz-Assaf, and Michael Tushman. 2013. “Open
Innovation and Organizational Boundaries: The Impact of Task
Decomposition and Knowledge Distribution on the Locus of Innovation.” In
&lt;em&gt;Handbook of Economic Organization&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Anna Grandori, 355–82. 1.
Cheltenham, UK: Edward Elgar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Glatin, Mario, Pascal Le Masson, and Benoît Weil. 2017. “Generative
action and preference reversal in exploratory project management.” &lt;em&gt;CERN
IdeaSquare Journal of Experimental Innovation&lt;/em&gt; 1 (2): 39–46.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeMasson2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Masson, Pascal, Armand Hatchuel, Mario Le Glatin, and Benoit Weil.
2018. “Designing Decisions in the Unknown: A Generative Model.”
&lt;em&gt;European Management Review&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/emre.12289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/emre.12289&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Machina1989&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machina, Mark J. 1989. “Dynamic Consistency and Non-Expected Utility
Models of Choice Under Uncertainty.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Literature&lt;/em&gt; 27
(4): 1622–68.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Nonaka2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonaka, Ikujiro, Ayano Hirose, and Yusaku Takeda. 2016.
“‘Meso’-Foundations of Dynamic Capabilities: Team-Level Synthesis and
Distributed Leadership as the Source of Dynamic Creativity.” &lt;em&gt;Global
Strategy Journal&lt;/em&gt; 6 (3): 168–82. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/gsj.1125&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/gsj.1125&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Nonaka2014&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonaka, Ikujiro, Mitsuru Kodama, Ayano Hirose, and Florian Kohlbacher.
2014. “Dynamic fractal organizations for promoting knowledge-based
transformation - A new paradigm for organizational theory.” &lt;em&gt;European
Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 32 (1): 137–46.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.emj.2013.02.003&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.emj.2013.02.003&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-OConnor2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Connor, Gina Colarelli. 2016. “Institutionalizing corporate
entrepreneurship as the firm’s innovation function: reflections from a
longitudinal research program.” In &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Research on Corporate
Entrepreneurship&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Shaker Zahra, Donald Neubaum, and James
Hayton, 145–74. Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar Publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Olin2001&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olin, Tommy, and Jan Wickenberg. 2001. “Rule Breaking in New Product
Development - Crime or Necessity?” &lt;em&gt;Creativity and Innovation
Management&lt;/em&gt; 10 (1): 15–25. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-8691.00187&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-8691.00187&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Pollack2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pollack, Julien. 2017. “Change Management as an Organizational and
Project Capability.” In &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Handbook of Organizational Project
Management&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Shankar Sankaran, Ralf Muller, and Nathalie
Drouin, 236–49. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316662243.021&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316662243.021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Ries2011a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ries, Eric. 2011. &lt;em&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/23&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/23&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Romme2003&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romme, A. Georges L. 2003. “Making a Difference: Organization as Design
Making a Difference.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 14 (5): 558–73.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.14.5.558.16769&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.14.5.558.16769&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Sanchez1996&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanchez, Ron, and Joseph T. Mahoney. 1996. “Modularity, Flexibility, and
Knowledge Management in Product and Organization Design.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic
Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 17: 63–76.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781107415324.004&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781107415324.004&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Sarasvathy2001&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarasvathy, Saras D. 2001. “Causation and effectuation: Toward a
theoretical shift from economic inevitability to entrepreneurial
contingency.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management Review&lt;/em&gt; 26 (2): 243–63.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Savage1954&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savage, Leonard. 1954. &lt;em&gt;The foundations of statistics&lt;/em&gt;. 2. New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Slovic1995&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slovic, Paul. 1995. “The construction of preference.” &lt;em&gt;American
Psychologist&lt;/em&gt; 50 (5): 364–71.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X.50.5.364&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X.50.5.364&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Teece2007&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teece, David J. 2007. “Explicating dynamic capabilities: the nature and
microfoundations of (sustainable) enterprise performance.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic
Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 28 (13): 1319–50. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.640&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.640&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Thomson1976&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomson, Judith Jarvis. 1976. “Killing, Letting Die, and the Trolley
Problem.” Edited by Sherwood J. B. Sugden. &lt;em&gt;Monist&lt;/em&gt; 59 (2): 204–17.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5840/monist197659224&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5840/monist197659224&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Thomson1985&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 1985. “The Trolley Problem.” &lt;em&gt;The Yale Law Journal&lt;/em&gt; 94 (6): 1395.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/796133&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/796133&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Thomson2008&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2008. “Turning the Trolley.” &lt;em&gt;Philosophy &amp;amp; Public Affairs&lt;/em&gt; 36 (4):
359–74. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1088-4963.2008.00144.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1088-4963.2008.00144.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Turner2001&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turner, J. Rodney, and Anne Keegan. 2001. “Mechanisms of governance in
the project-based organization: Roles of the broker and steward.”
&lt;em&gt;European Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 19 (3): 254–67.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0263-2373(01)00022-6&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0263-2373(01)00022-6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Tversky1974&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tversky, Amos, and Daniel Kahneman. 1974. “Judgment under Uncertainty:
Heuristics and Biases.” &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; 185 (4157): 1124–31.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-VandeVen2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van de Ven, Andrew H., Martin Ganco, and C. R. (BOB) Hinings. 2013.
“Returning to the Frontier of Contingency Theory of Organizational and
Institutional Designs.” &lt;em&gt;The Academy of Management Annals&lt;/em&gt; 7 (1):
393–440. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/19416520.2013.774981&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/19416520.2013.774981&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Wald1949&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wald, Abraham. 1949. “Statistical Decision Functions.” &lt;em&gt;Annals of
Mathematical Statistics&lt;/em&gt; 20 (2): 165–205.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1214/aoms/1177730030&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1214/aoms/1177730030&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Wason1960&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wason, P. C. 1960. “On the failure to eliminate hypotheses in a
conceptual task.” &lt;em&gt;Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 12 (3):
129–40. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/17470216008416717&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/17470216008416717&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
