<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 4 - Modelling and testing decisional ambidexterity | Mario LE GLATIN</title>
    <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Part 4 - Modelling and testing decisional ambidexterity</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Part 4 - Modelling and testing decisional ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10 - Test cases: the Lower Deck and the Connected Cabin</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everyone who designs devises a course of action aimed at changing
existing situations into preferred ones.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Herbert A. Simon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have established a new model to reconcile the original construct of
ambidexterity with the evolutions innovation management. By revisiting
the canonical model of decision-making with design theory, decisional
ambidexterity allows us to endogenize the unknown within a technology of
organizing collective action to metabolize innovation across the firm.
The performance is supported by the interactions between
decision-designers revealing interdependencies and their
reconfiguration. The value management unfolds as the project trajectory
may be manoeuvred away from technical, organizational and environmental
fixations. Exploitation dimensions are used to sustain a generative and
grounded exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model was first built on a simple agent-based foundation, and since
we tasked ourselves several requirements defined in contrast with
anomalies, we made use of the mirroring hypothesis to discuss the
necessary organizational change. This transformational process we
propose to link with organizational metabolism, is an embodiment of the
recombination of routines or regenerative dynamic capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it reflects the generative learning expected by (temporary)
project-based organization and its boundaries with permanent
organization. Otherwise, project will float across the organization.
Consequently, we propose to test our model of mutual conditioning
between exploration and exploitation. To do so, we use two case studies
conducted at Zodiac Aerospace. We extend the preliminary testing and
understanding gained in the two previous chapter when defining our
model. The anomalies became understandable as the model of decisional
ambidexterity gives a larger framework to make sense of decisions and
concepts that are otherwise labelled as absurd or irrational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first project stems from the Design Case studies hosted by ADT we
have analysed in the anomaly detection chapter. As explained, in the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#lower-deck&#34;&gt;case presentation&lt;/a&gt;, the project was launched after ADT manager
decided to further conceptualize the recurrent idea of using aircraft’s
lower deck. It was also notified by the researcher in 2016 when
presenting his first analysis of the design thinking cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second project originates from two members of the ZSTC with a
history of entrepreneurship and innovation. They had reasons to launch a
project on aircraft connectivity given their experience on
telecommunications, satellites, antennae and onboard computers. It was
set as a proper MBU project justifying its value proposal to the ExCom
(see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#connected-cabin&#34;&gt;case presentation&lt;/a&gt;).
Both cases are comparable in the sense they were sponsored by the ExCom,
offered budget and internal/external network support to find answers,
contour their ill-defined problems and test the concepts (on slides,
digital mock-ups and physical proof of concepts). We use the same
analytical lens and descriptors introduced in our methodological
chapters enhanced with the logics of decisional ambidexterity (decision
categories, learning, organization design). Comparing these two cases
will allow testing further our model by gaining an understanding that is
missed with models of non-mutual conditioning between exploration and
exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first section, we present the Lower Deck project, its trajectory
and present the several patterns phased with decisional ambidexterity.
In the second section, we discuss the Connected Cabin project, which,
despite benefitting from an equivalent context and support, fails to
sustain a decisional ambidexterity. The project unfortunately regresses
towards biases of traditional models of ambidexterity, hence killing its
innovation potential of attraction. These two case studies give us a
richer understanding of what decisional ambidexterity can achieve in
reconciliating logics of exploration project management with a renewed
organizational learning and adaptation rooted in generative logics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lower-deck-from-design-feature-to-value-space&#34;&gt;Lower Deck: from design feature to value space&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trajectory-of-the-project&#34;&gt;Trajectory of the project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As presented in our case presentation (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#lower-deck&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;), the project of Lower
Deck started due to the accumulation of concepts generated in several
projects over two years at ADT. Among them, many had the recurrent idea
of using the aircraft’s lower deck. A first provisional patent
application process was started mid-2014 (see patent no.
US20170233058A1). Late 2015, the patent was made public and made quite
an impact with numerous critics coming from specialized blogs, magazines
and newspapers&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The Design Thinking case studies started in 2015 and
what continued over 2016 also made use of the lower deck in various
ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher had identified the pivotal role of this a priori
underused aircraft area to enable concepts that cross over BU
boundaries. In parallel, ZA’s CEO, during an interview conducted in May
2018 by the PhD candidate, told the concept had already been discussed
during ExCom meetings previous to the project formalization. The case
seemed justified to them as they had insights on the declining freight
market: an increasing empty space in the lower deck was then available.
Finally, a project was kicked off and took the concept on its own
mid-2016 and directly managed by ADT manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several dimensions were addressed simultaneously. Firstly, an underlying
mechanical stress study was conducted: the CTO contracted an engineering
consultancy firm to evaluate the technical and safety feasibility of
using the lower deck for passengers seating and other airline ancillary
revenues. Secondly, the support of group business development directors
in charge of airlines accounts offered a way to engage talks with key
airline representatives (&lt;em&gt;interpreters&lt;/em&gt; (Verganti and Dell’Era

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Verganti2014&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;)). It was the occasion to probe airlines
interest and gradually contour client value. Thirdly, later 2016/early
2017, the VP of Strategy (ADT manager’s director) contracted another
consultancy firm to dig into the ticket pricing model (yield management)
and airlines operation cycles in order to economically value lower
deck’s use cases but also find time frames when the aircraft lower deck
could be modified without disrupting aircraft’s operations. Finally, a
last study was contracted internally with two business units familiar
with tailored aircraft modification (VIP, movies, medical care, etc.)
for a preliminary design and engineering specification to adapt the
lower deck for the different use cases. Early 2018, a new patent
application was made with more critical claims specifying the value of
the concept refined over time (see patent no. WO2018037268A9). And the
global concept was finally revealed to the public with Airbus as a
sponsor and co-designer during Aircraft Interior Exposition in April
2018. A partnership agreement was signed between Airbus and Zodiac
Aerospace to develop the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is rather surprising in this project trajectory is the fact that
the lower deck feature was first used in several concepts and
systematically discarded by BUs who participated to previous projects
(including those supported by Design Thinking practice). Concepts were
discarded despite having justified user and client value, and having
raised some technical difficulties through complimentary meetings with
engineers and designers. However, once the lower deck was turned into a
proper value space looking for use cases, it gained much more momentum,
specially from business unit managers. They indeed requested to host the
project in their branch of activity.
The figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:LWDTraj&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:LWDTraj&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;
below gives a synthetic view of the project trajectory including the
previous Design Thinking cases. Given the decisional ambidexterity model
we can specify the nature of decisions designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;problem-inversion-of-design-thinking-cases&#34;&gt;Problem inversion of Design Thinking cases&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we can see that some decisions started from an enhanced
optimization, moved towards hacking several choices extending concepts
in between or outside BUs boundaries. Some of these were triggered by
user input and &lt;em&gt;What If?&lt;/em&gt; scenarios. The Lower Deck feature was one of
them ($d^*$). However, once the concepts are selected, ranked, sponsored
and promoted to BUs, the generative effort is reduced to an
optimization: finding the best fit for BUs without changing engineering
capabilities, or at best marginally by incrementally modifying existing
products (new requirement). The issue is also that this optimization and
biased adaptation is mirrored by underlying interdependencies and
fixations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, using a waste chute and sorting mechanisms in the lower
deck could be developed by Zodiac Inserts who developed the trash
compactor (a trolley locked into the galley area). The latter
corresponds to a given certification and qualification process. Zodiac
Galley could also have considered the product development given its
specialty on panels and fixtures withstanding stress and loads, as well
as water and electrical circuitry integration (also another
certification/qualification process). Finally Zodiac Cargo, who develops
containers would be appropriate to develop the relevant container lodged
in the lower deck providing the sorting and extraction of waste. It is a
potential multi-BU project which always calls for another requirement
partly mastered by another BU. It could be developed by each BU
individually as technologies are similar or at reach. The incentive to
work together would only come if they had a real client demand and/or a
change in certification and qualification. Moreover, the concept
requires reconsidering airline operations and purchasing policy, so
training and change of practice is required in the sales pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the induced organizational and environmental phenomena were
not really addressed in the Lower Deck project premises. The problem was
turned inside out to make the choice hacking more visible. So, instead
of forcing the BU congruence, it gave a whole new flavour to the
innovation potential of attraction as described in Table
&lt;a href=&#34;#table:LWDtab&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;table:LWDtab&#34;&gt;[table:LWDtab]&lt;/a&gt;
below. Meetings held with the ExCom insisted heavily on the technical
advantage that should be designed, since they were rather confident on
the client value and market attractivity. The discussions were oriented
to ensure the development of a turnkey solution as well as competitive
advantage against the footprint of aircraft manufacturers. In other
words, they shifted the concept towards having an empty shell. The value
space guaranteed its technical feasibility, with the prospect of a
separate qualification and certification process. Consequently, BUs
could articulate their products in this new space, without worrying
about their engineering and organization design fixations, and focus on
regenerating their products for this new value space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regenerative-capability-through-design-formulation&#34;&gt;Regenerative capability through design formulation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lower Deck became rather modular and generic for several BUs who
needed to develop new design capability to fit requirements evolution.
It encouraged the adaptation to the newly designed environment. Instead
of forcing the fit to each specific BUs, the problem inversion, allowed
attracting them to provide use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisional ambidexterity reveals the importance of project management
and corporate entrepreneurship interactions steering the project
trajectory where the novel value is not forced onto an a priori
independent BU, but rather on formulating a concept design that attracts
them to grow. It moves them away from their fixations by creating
&lt;em&gt;generative fit&lt;/em&gt; (Avital and Te’eni 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Avital2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;), thus
supporting the regenerative capability expected from them. The
organization design was not clearly discussed during project meetings,
but the decisional ambidexterity allows us to formulate the idea that
product engineering embedded how interdependencies could be unlocked.
Otherwise, a non-mutual conditioning would focus only on numerous other
explanations: leader as champion, acculturation to the lower deck
prospect. Perhaps yes, but it does not make it manageable and does not
give much directions to guide collective action and engineering design
practice.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-from-a-feature-to-value-space-inversing-the-lower-deck-problem&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/LWDTraj.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;From a feature to value space: inversing the lower deck problem&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/LWDTraj.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    From a feature to value space: inversing the lower deck problem
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;decisional-ambidexterity-analysis&#34;&gt;Decisional ambidexterity analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Non-mutual conditioning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mutual conditioning extended model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lower deck exploration could be fully conducted separately to create a new business unit.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lower deck business case is tightly articulated around the unlocking of underlying interdependencies that were not addressed in previous projects. It allows preparing exploitation and coordinate BUs around a host concept and value space.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non applicable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The conceptualization builds upon limitations raised by BUs. Demonstrate value through actionable knowledge on how to exploit the concept (technical and use cases propositions). BUs don’t have to worry for the engineering of what could be common to other BUs, as the concept already determined those interdependencies.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non applicable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The environment is managed with concept tested among potential clients, engineering qualification and certification to ensure passenger and cabin crew safety. The environment is shaped to welcome BUs future engineering effort. ExCom sponsored the engineering effort, qualification/certification constraints, and ensured the concept would crystallize and secure the market creation (technological advantage).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The new BU or spin-off is a possibility, &lt;strong&gt;but&lt;/strong&gt; pending discussions consider encouraging the regeneration of the cargo and container BU.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The organization design is integrated in the conceptual exploration as interdependencies and fixations ingrained in BUs are unlocked. BUs do not see it as a an &lt;em&gt;add-on&lt;/em&gt; to their existing products, but rather as a value space to project onto. The Lower Deck may be integrated by a BU (cargo and container) hosting the contributions of other BUs combined with engineering capabilities for aircraft modification BU. Relationships are now built around the knowledge of enabling the cargo area for a multitude of use cases.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;connected-cabin-project-mode-and-proof-of-concept&#34;&gt;Connected Cabin: project mode and proof of concept?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trajectory-of-the-project-1&#34;&gt;Trajectory of the project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was initiated by two members of the ZSTC (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#connected-cabin&#34;&gt;case presentation&lt;/a&gt;) who started testing the idea of addressing the trending topic of Big
Data and Aircraft Connectivity. The topic had already triggered the
development of in-flight connectivity with satellite antennae and ground
antennae, including the ongoing product development by Zodiac Data
Systems specialized in providing tele-measurement devices for testing
and monitoring. In September 2016, the first summit dedicated to
aircraft connectivity, &lt;em&gt;Smart Plane&lt;/em&gt;, was hosted in parallel as a
chapter of the major &lt;em&gt;World Satellite Business Week&lt;/em&gt; in Paris. The
topics were gradually gaining importance in the industrial ecosystem.
However, already in late 2015, during a ZSTC meeting, the two members
pitched the idea on how Zodiac Aerospace, as a group, could set a foot
on this emergent market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As pictured in figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:IconnzTraj&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:IconnzTraj&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;
below, they originally presented the idea of creating connectivity
platform providing value-added service for predictive maintenance and
airline operations. The claim was grounded on the fact that Zodiac
Aerospace was a legitimate player to provide such integrated solution as
the group covers the full extent of the cabin and several other key
equipment in the aircraft systems. Their knowledge on tele-transmission
with the products developed within Zodiac Inflight Innovations (fast
growing player in the inflight entertainment market) allowed them to
consider connectivity solutions between equipment so far isolated and
managed by independent systems. The concept would thus overcome
rigidities for airline operations and consequently passenger
discontent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several meetings were held with the ExCom in order to have full support
of top management so that middle management would allocate resources in
order to demonstrate the value proposal and business case of such
project. The discussions were complex and frustrating as the board of
directors was asking for what would make Zodiac Aerospace legitimate
beyond market footprint. They were asking for a technology
differentiator, something that would ensure the market niche&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. For
instance, the CEO would have preferred to have Zodiac Data Systems to
develop a technology (antenna, computer, etc.). In the end, the board
was gradually convinced that the key was to be able to manage an
ecosystem of industrial players rather than the hardware by making a
direct comparison to Apple iPhone’s development. They allocated budget
to the project so that BUs could allocate time to their engineers and
managers. The former CEO also communicated to investors on the project’s
kick-off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after late 2016, a whole project team was tasked by the ExCom to
build a demonstrator for the following Aircraft Interior Exposition
(AIX, April 2017). The design effort was driven towards making a
&lt;em&gt;Minimum Viable Product&lt;/em&gt;: a scenario was drawn with several pieces of
equipment showing the benefits of cabin connectivity for airline
operations and passenger experience. The proof of concept embodied in a
full scale mock-up was modelled to show integration capabilities and
synergies. Numerous workshops were held in different location to stage
gate the project and track the progress of sub-projects around the
connectivity backbone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During an internal show with airlines organized by of one the major
cabin BU in California, they had the occasion to probe some potential
clients to provide feedback to the ongoing demonstrator design. It was
also used to narrow down the questionnaire used during AIX. The
exposition was a success, leading airlines executives came to visit and
experience the product along with ZA’s top management. Several critical
comments came regarding known preoccupations in the market: data
ownership, intellectual property, compatibility and standardization
among industrial players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is quite impressive is AIX aftermath. Every BUs complimented each
other, went back to their businesses. And several emails exchanged
between project’s members, including R&amp;amp;T, Marketing and Engineering
managers of respective BUs, revealed how perplex they were on the
project’s termination. They wouldn’t understand why the ExCom and other
BUs wouldn’t continue with the project. Several other factors can be
taken into account: e.g. change of priorities for ExCom concerned with
Safran’s acquisition (but it didn’t slow nor stop the lower deck
project), and European funded projects on small connectivity technology
block at BU-level but reduced scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regression-to-the-mean&#34;&gt;Regression to the mean&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast with the lower deck project, and given the similar context,
the project’s gained momentum raises the question of how efficient the
project’s output was. Of course, pure continuity of the project cannot
be always requested, but the takeaways are scarce. The major one still
keeping a system thinking on the value chain can be seen for Zodiac
Catering Equipment, but they already had an agenda on passenger
experience, cabin crew and airline/caterer operations before the
project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:IconnzTraj&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:IconnzTraj&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;
shows how the genericity and platform concept was originally pushed
forward in a newly managed environment. Decisional ambidexterity quickly
reveals that there was some regression to the mean (Kahneman

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Kahneman2011&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;) or concept shifting towards a reference point
(Heath, Larrick, and Wu 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Heath1999&#34;&gt;1999&lt;/a&gt;). This drift is
unfortunately stuck due to organization fixation and interdependencies
relatively to their product engineering and market segmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;proof-of-concept-to-trigger-a-full-scale-multi-bu-project&#34;&gt;Proof of concept to trigger a full-scale multi-BU project?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we also stress in table
&lt;a href=&#34;#table:Iconnztab&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;table:Iconnztab&#34;&gt;[table:Iconnztab]&lt;/a&gt;,
the organization design was left aside and uncontrolled. So, each
respective BU would work on recombining their engineering routines to
think of the new platform for cabin connectivity. The proof of concept
targeted the added requirement of using a communication bus and protocol
(wired or wireless). The decisional ambidexterity highlights the need
for an organization-design-oriented proof of concept supporting the
original intent and sustaining the regeneration of capabilities among
BU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, the CTO notified the researcher that the project was in
&amp;ldquo;project mode&amp;rdquo;. This comment clearly criticizes the limitations of
encapsulation and its tendency for not considering enough change
management and organizational learning and design. Decisional
ambidexterity can also be used to discuss the proof of concept activity
embodied by the physical demonstrator, scenario/storytelling, and
associated prototyping activities to embody the scenario/storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It allows indeed to formalise choice hacking, environment management,
design of states of nature, designing by referring to BU
(organizational) fixation effects. In the Connected Cabin demonstrator
prototype, we can actually extrapolate what else could have been done to
sustain the original concept. For instance, beyond the hardware add-one
for existing products, exploiting the constraints of the connectivity
topic could have been explored: bandwidth allocation and use, protocol,
confidentiality and property. The hardware is of course important, but
it corresponds to a retrofit activity, and it is made possible only
after crossing qualification/certification/acceptation barriers. These
are high-level and system constraints but they can easily shadow
engineering ideas. Decisional ambidexterity proposes to generate and
segregate alternatives to identify such control variables and actions to
realize concepts.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-from-platform-management-and-ecosystem-reorganization-to-added-function&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/IconnzTraj.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;From platform management and ecosystem reorganization to added function&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/IconnzTraj.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    From platform management and ecosystem reorganization to added function
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;decisional-ambidexterity-analysis-1&#34;&gt;Decisional ambidexterity analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Non-mutual conditioning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mutual conditioning extended model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exploration is conducted by a temporary team relying on delegated resources.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exploration initially targets a new platform approach for cabin equipment exploited in ZA. The equipment connectivity and associated system is used as an input to pool data in a centralized core system.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The purpose of the project drifts as the project’s main output becomes a proof of concept for AIX 2017.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hacking all choices to wish for a new industrial ecosystem organized around ZA integration capabilities. New connectivity solution, services for airline operations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The demonstrator and prototyping activities do not overcome fixations and locked interdependencies.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Original intent is to act as a platform leader for the ZA equipment and competition. Request from ExCom to have a key technological advantage to secure the new market.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The project gradually moves away from the concern of articulating the technology with BUs engineering capabilities as the proof of concept mainly emphasizes the need for an added connectivity feature to all pieces of equipment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Original project’s mission was to federate a service platform for connectivity with BUs benefiting from added-value equipment enhanced by data. BUs would then need to regenerate their capabilities for&lt;em&gt;servitization&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis-a-reconciliatory-model-for-ambidexterity&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis: a reconciliatory model for ambidexterity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this model testing chapter, we have presented two comparable cases
steered by the ExCom in the form of multi-BU projects. The mutual
conditioning between exploration and exploitation in our model of
decisional ambidexterity allows understanding the logics of generative
processes and its innovation potential of attraction. They had similar
coordination mechanisms as they were encapsulated into projects but the
actions engaged to make a case for the proof of concept bended the
project trajectory and organizational change in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organization metabolism would not be activated given some constraints on
engineering capabilities, standards and regulations as well as market
segmentation. The literature models of non-mutual conditioning would
indeed explain some patterns in the two cases. Consequently, we can
formulate the result that the collective action of decision-designers
requires to be organized on multiple levels with the appropriate
heuristics and technology of organization. The common purpose, or task
formulation, frames also the capabilities of the project, its reach and
potential of attraction across organizations. We then back up the
validity of our model of decisional ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lower Deck project had a strong emphasis on securing the concept feasibility and
market access, the virtual mock-ups was rather a means to formalize,
update the concept’s model and communicate. However, in the Connected
Cabin project, the demonstrator became almost an end in itself up to a
point the designed generic decisions where gradually biased by strong
organizational fixations and locked interdependencies. It reduced the
wishful platform engineering to simply adding a function requirement to
each equipment. The one-stop shop for all aircraft equipment
manufacturers was reduced to an isolated add-on feature for existing and
fixated BU-engineered equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two presented cases had similar management sponsorship, and corporate entrepreneurship spirit. They
reveal the subtleties of decisional ambidexterity and the nature of
generative effort, its management to avoid the limitations of
organizational ambidexterity. The interactions with designed decisions,
designed artefacts and steering committees appears key to manoeuvre the
project’s trajectory but also regenerate capabilities among BUs to
support the project-based management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/&#34;&gt;following part&lt;/a&gt;,
we will address the contributions made by the researcher. Several
opportunities were seized to test &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; decisional ambidexterity and
further proof of validation were provided by interactions with peers
within Zodiac Aerospace.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Avital2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avital, Michel, and Dov Te’eni. 2009. “From generative fit to generative
capacity: exploring an emerging dimension of information systems design
and task performance.” &lt;em&gt;Information Systems Journal&lt;/em&gt; 19 (4): 345–67.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2575.2007.00291.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2575.2007.00291.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Heath1999&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heath, Chip, Richard P. Larrick, and George Wu. 1999. “Goals as
Reference Points.” &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 38 (1): 79–109.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1006/cogp.1998.0708&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1006/cogp.1998.0708&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Kahneman2011&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kahneman, Daniel. 2011. &lt;em&gt;Thinking, fast and slow&lt;/em&gt;. London, England:
Penguin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Verganti2014&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verganti, Roberto, and Claudio Dell’Era. 2014. “Design-Driven
Innovation.” In &lt;em&gt;The Oxford Handbook of Innovation Management&lt;/em&gt;, 1–28.
April 2018. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199694945.013.006&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199694945.013.006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance see DailyMail Online brief on December 8, 2015: &lt;em&gt;Just
when you thought they couldn’t get any more seats on board:
Aerospace company designs lower-deck cabin with vending machines and
display screens instead of windows&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this information was drawn from Multi-BU meeting minutes and CEO’s
interview conducted on May 7, 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8 - Modelling and testing decisional ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laws should only provide a basis for self-fulfilment.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Paul Klee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this first modelling chapter, in the same fashion as described in the
beginning of our literature review, we propose to come back to a
canonical model that requires to be enhanced by generative processes.
James March in his seminal paper had consciously declared the boundaries
of his model (March 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;); yet these very same edges
are heavily challenged by the evolutions of innovation management which
have gone beyond the perimeters of the ambidexterity models relying on
the non-mutual conditioning between exploration/exploitation. Generative
processes such as design practices taking place for radical innovation,
ripple throughout decision-making, collective action, coordination
mechanisms and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the management anomaly specifications and the mirroring
requirements needed to design a new model, we propose to synthesize the
article published in the European Management Review (Le Masson et al.

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeMasson2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;) (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-lemasson2018/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;). The developed model allows clarifying the heuristics associated
with &lt;strong&gt;decisional ambidexterity&lt;/strong&gt; (Le Glatin, Le Masson, and Weil

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;) (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-leglatin2017a/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;). Furthermore, it gives some grounds on the designing of decisions and to set a new frame for collective action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss which extensions are made on the traditional assumptions on
problem-solving and rational theory of choice thanks to the teachings in
design theory. We can then revisit some stimulating constructs
previously identified in our literature review discussing the
performance of the decision design relating to the &lt;em&gt;innovation potential
of attraction&lt;/em&gt; and underlying useful methods and heuristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All along the modelling effort in the following section, we make several
references to the previous detected anomalies. We do so in order to
explain how the new model allows gaining new insights. We also refer to
the gap-filling between former models and the new as we also tasked
ourselves to keep coherence and a sense of continuity when coming from
the known to the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We start by coming back to the original model of (March
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;) with its foundations in problem-solving and
choice of alternatives. We extend the canonical framework of
decision-making into the unknown with the support of C-K design theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we discuss the performance of the decisions designed and made. It
invites to think beyond traditional expected utility theories of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first partial representation of the model is pictured in &lt;a href=&#34;#model-synthesis&#34;&gt;table&lt;/a&gt; gives a comparison with the synthetic model of non-mutual
conditioning between exploration and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;designing-decisions-decisional-ambidexterity-for-organizational-metabolism&#34;&gt;Designing decisions: decisional ambidexterity for organizational metabolism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the introduction and premises of our literature review (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter1/&#34;&gt;chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;, we presented the trajectory of the agent-based model of James
March, creating the construct of exploration and exploitation to sustain
organization learning and fighting for supremacy (March

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;). The starting point being problem-based - and
consequently decision-making by adding a pinch of uncertainty - allows
considering the bounded rationality of agents limited in their daily
routines, and requiring exploration, i.e. search-based patterns looking
out for overlooked alternatives already present in their decision
space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue of the decision creation is rather left aside by only
promoting the garbage-can decision model and foolishness as a means to
improve the generation of novelty, beyond pure selection issues. Without
discarding altogether a potential contribution from foolishness and
irrationality, starting from the canonical model of decision theory such
as (Wald 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Wald1945a&#34;&gt;1945&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Wald1949&#34;&gt;1949&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; where an
agent picks up an alternative among those offered to her, consequences
$X$ are known depending on the outcome of the states of nature $\Theta$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The (statistical) decisions ($d:s\in \Theta \rightarrow x\in X$,
$d\in D$) are calculated based on costs of consequences
($c:x\in X \rightarrow y\in\mathbb{R}^+$) and the states of nature
weighted by degrees of probability $\mu$. The theory predicts the
existence of an optimal choice minimizing costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using design theory, such as C-K theory (Hatchuel and Weil

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;), for its generality can be used onto the
canonical model $(D,\Theta,c,\mu)$ which can be complemented by
statistical learning $L$ drawn from previous experiences and sampling
$(D,\Theta,c,\mu,L)$. We also address the issue of simultaneous problem
formulation and solving, conceptualized in need-solution pairs (Hippel
and Krogh 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-VonHippel2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) who encouraged the use of design
theory to identify and generate these pairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mobilizing-design-theory-for-decision-paradigm&#34;&gt;Mobilizing design theory for decision paradigm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dominant design stemming from the decision problem is the optimum
choice in the acknowledged set of choices, beliefs, states of nature and
cost function. Using C-K theory gives a starting point formulated by a
model of knowledge that can be considered as the state of the art, and
the decision broken down into the given environment $\Theta$ and optimal
decision maximising expected utility $d_{MEU}$ (minimizing costs). We
then have a first branch on the concept space, and a first knowledge
sub-space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, the Wald’s model gives it own parameters that can be hacked
by design. The set of decisions $D$ and the states of nature $\Theta$
can be then re-designed. Generativity, like in the experiment where
pigeons generate new action to solve a problem (Epstein et al.

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Epstein1984&#34;&gt;1984&lt;/a&gt;; Epstein 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Epstein1990&#34;&gt;1990&lt;/a&gt;), will play
on the generation of new decisions, as well as altering the states of
nature. It differs from trial and error in the way that it deals with
novelty, ill-defined problems, by matching stimuli and actual
transformation of the behaviour required to deal with (generated) new
situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a very simple way, we are interested in managing the operators
$D \rightarrow D^{* } $, which generates and reconfigures decisions, and
$\Theta \rightarrow \Theta^*$ which integrates new states of nature,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;changes the world’s description, semantics and changes the posture of
the decision-maker with respect to these states. The cost function $c$,
and beliefs $\mu$ will subsequently have to be redefined or simply
extended to the new range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to the figure show in the literature review (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter1/#shifting-the-performance-frontier-with-innovation&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;), copied
below, we push the model beyond the Pareto front. As the operators
generate new possibilities, revisiting performance criteria which are
the tip of the iceberg of the transformations of $D$ and $\Theta$.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-schematics-of-behaviours&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/explorationregimes.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Schematics of behaviours&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/explorationregimes.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Schematics of behaviours
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-decision-categories&#34;&gt;New decision categories&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, beyond the optimum decision $d_{MEU}$, the decision-designer
can try to push the optimization even further for a given chosen state
of nature $\theta_i \in \Theta$. We have then a **new wishful decision by optimization** ($d_{opt}$). It could be a simple functional improvement added for one feature that could be constrained otherwise by the realization of one outcome in the spectrum of consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimizing makes the assumption that a lot of parameters have been
identified and locked, so that gap to be explore between what is
boundedly known and what is yet to be known is clear. It could be
considered as the simplest and predictive form of transitioning between
exploration and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the uncertainty associated to the considered states of nature
$\Theta$, the decision-designer can study the envelop of available
alternatives $D$ so that he can add a new decision which minimizes costs
for all contingencies: &lt;strong&gt;new wishful decision by genericity&lt;/strong&gt; ($d^{gen}$).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Business Class seat, we can label some of their decisions aiming
at developing a platform for a modular product line. The exploration of
existing possibilities (benchmark) and the generation of new
alternatives both encompass a new wishful decision by genericity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also argue that when the client program selected the explored
product design, the exploitation regime performs a regression towards
optimizing as if the preliminary platform design would be robust enough
for a full development and uncertainty reduction. Some knowledge areas
had indeed not been fully uncovered. So, in a &lt;em&gt;post mortem&lt;/em&gt; analysis, we
have a better understanding of what could have been managed differently
to maintain the exploration and exploitation effort and their mutual
conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now switching to the design heuristics, instead of leaving $\Theta$
fixated, we can work on redesigning the states of nature.
Thirdly, we can try to change a single state of nature in order to force
the redesign of decisions. Considering an unknown (i.e. out of the
domain) state of nature that may have a devastating impact on
consequences can be one way. Or one could simply just slightly shift a
not very likely state of nature. The idea of the &lt;em&gt;What If?&lt;/em&gt; scenario in
Design Thinking methodology addresses this perspective. However, one can
also target the most certain knowledge which hides fixation effects; it
tackles the &lt;em&gt;sure thing principle&lt;/em&gt; (Savage 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Savage1954&#34;&gt;1954&lt;/a&gt;, 21).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the same fashion, deliberately reversing preferences can force
the design or the concern for an unknown state of nature which may
favour the reversal; as discussed in our paper (Le Glatin, Le Masson,
and Weil 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;), also in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-leglatin2017a/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are then designing a &lt;strong&gt;new wishful decision by best choice hacking&lt;/strong&gt;
($d^{alt}$). For example, if the decision problem was to choose between
known several technologies and associated performance, one could try
reversing the order and try to design a situation where it would work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Icing Conditions Detection case can be interpreted in that way since
considering an unknown safety regulation evolution was to be shaped by
the R&amp;amp;T manager to justify the new performance of the technology in the
new spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploration effectively relies on exploitation constraints to generate
new alternatives. It could be also considered as coming &lt;em&gt;out of the
blue&lt;/em&gt;, in a serendipitous way, as an externality or as need-solution
pair (Hippel and Krogh 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-VonHippel2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;). But at least, the
model allows linking them back to the dominant designed decision, since
we can play on the decision space and states of nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we can reproduce systematically all pieces of certain
knowledge. By doing so, we explore the full extent of fixation effects
considered on knowledge usually requested or made implicit in
decision-making. So we end up with a &lt;strong&gt;new wishful decision by all
choices hacking&lt;/strong&gt; ($d^{*}$).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Design Thinking cases, shifting the concepts in aircraft areas,
where BUs are not dealing with the design brief, falls into the category
of all choices hacking. Clearly, it highlights that the exploration has
gone out of the boundaries of what classical search-based model would
have delivered. Such hacking insists on the fact that exploitation won’t
be conducted nor balanced by ignoring the new created interplay.
Frontier between product designs can be totally re-discussed to shape
the new environment (e.g. lower deck, integration between equipment in
galley area, passengers loading their luggage, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Overall, the different decision categories one can design, offers a new
mapping for the decision-maker to envision the course of action. By
becoming a decision-designer, the design reasoning on alternatives
allows, not only understanding the consequences of avoiding the
conditioning between exploration and exploitation, but also to envision
the efforts required in terms of knowledge management. Consequently, it
enables starting to reconciliate the risks of floating of exploration
project management with the organizational learning originally hoped
with (March &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;) model.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;knowledge-value&#34;&gt;Knowledge value&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The different decisions categories, by simply relying on Wald’s
canonical decision model, show the extension $D$ and $\Theta$ spaces.
The transformation operated by design theory comes with consequences on
the value $c$, beliefs $\mu$ and learning $L$. These are redefined by
composition of $D \rightarrow D^{* }$ and/or
$\Theta \rightarrow \Theta^{* }$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most stimulating feature from a standard statistical probability
view is that adding a new decision, or new state of nature, flattens
existing probability distributions. In other words, we &lt;strong&gt;increase global
uncertainty&lt;/strong&gt;. And we do it so that it is even more accentuated that it
could perturb a search-based model since we are extending the spaces we
are relying on. From a rational choice theory, it is, of course,
unacceptable but the operators in between the old and the new spaces
take in the possibility of design, it is not an externality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Icing Conditions Detection project, when they reversed their
preferences for a highly uncertain technology, they opened a new
environment to be shaped. The potential risk was reallocated, raising
uncertainties but also made former alternatives less interesting despite
being more certain in a different setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning can be organized for such purpose. Seen from the development
engineering department, the prototype tested on aircraft is not to be
considered as a traditional exploitation. Instead, it should be seen as
an &lt;em&gt;exploitation exploration&lt;/em&gt; where the unfinished engineering work
offers the opportunity to acknowledge and reconfigure engineering rules
around the new technology and system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consequently endogenize the unknown by design. Not only are we are
building up awareness but also we are anticipating it by systematically
designing and prospectively managing unknown decisions and states of
nature. We are in line with the idea of bringing vigilance (Oury and
Schmidt 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Oury1983&#34;&gt;1983&lt;/a&gt;), opportunism (Lumineau and Verbeke

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lumineau2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;), reliability (Sutcliffe and Christianson

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Sutcliffe2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;) to the front seat, by turning the
decision-maker into a decision-designer. The underlying assumptions have
been weakened to leave room for design theory to unveil its potential on
its sister theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of &lt;em&gt;phronesis&lt;/em&gt; (Nonaka, Hirose, and Takeda

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Nonaka2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;), which we discussed in the literature review,
could be then further substantiated with the way a manager makes and
design decisions. It is a means of organizing collective action:
creating simple coordination mechanisms around certain knowledge that
can tweaked collectively by stakeholders, mobilizing (silent) designers
around problems that can be systematically ill-defined by themselves,
and simply overseeing the course of action with other reference points
given by the decisional mapping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the BC class seat platform project, the early stages of concept
selection and generation with BU stakeholders were an actual case of
blending the exploration with the exploitation constraints. However,
this effort was biased when the project was transferred to program
management as if fit for development. Instead, it could have been the
occasion to continue exploitation knowing and managing learning for a
continuing and parallel exploration. This awareness is however only
realized in the aftermath and not along the transition nor the
exploitation project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    This decisional ambidexterity consequently also gives an &lt;strong&gt;extended risk
assessment&lt;/strong&gt; register, richer than traditional practices seen in project
management. But, in the same fashion we did, we could manipulate the
risk register which is used, transferred and adapted in between projects
as a representation of the dominant decision design framing (a priori)
collective action in project’s trajectory. The modelled technology of
ambidexterity can give room to the stretching caused by encapsulated
generative processes and still letting them be managed.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance-of-decision-design&#34;&gt;Performance of decision design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The described approach of simply applying a generativity theory to a
foundational canonical model puts the emphasis on the transformation
operators rather than on the dichotomy of exploration and exploitation
regimes. These operators offer a systematic way of exploring given
exploitation references. The dichotomy and non-mutual conditioning are
left aside by a constant articulation of interdependencies of
exploration and exploitation. So, it is not the set of elements and
their nature that counts, but rather the relationship engaged between
them that is to be managed. In that regard, we move beyond duality of
the regimes (Farjoun 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Farjoun2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    The performance of both exploration and exploitation will be dependent
on the quality of the generative operators. It implies the collective
effort of designing the fit of decisions, and identifying, acknowledging
and managing fixations effects and underlying interdependencies. It is
crucial to &lt;em&gt;measure&lt;/em&gt; and characterize the distance between what
exploitation can achieve on its own path and the different explored and
designed decisions can otherwise. Learning and adaptation take a
different twist with the cognitive fit and design fixation effects.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;beyond-the-fit-moving-and-designing-target&#34;&gt;Beyond the fit: moving and designing target&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paradoxes of opposing two competing objectives becomes rather
secondary or even transparent, by adopting the design and elucidation of
interdependencies between decisions and states of nature. All the ties
justifying exploration can be derived from exploitation, and conversely
the exploitation can be justified by a reference enlarged by
exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The constant generative search is rooted in exploitation, and
exploitation is inversely valued through exploration. The pattern is
similar to the novelty-search algorithm (Nguyen, Yosinski, and Clune

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Nguyen2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;; Cully et al. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Cully2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;) designed
for robots to improve their resilience, but we improve such heuristics
by considering that the problem is also re-formulated, as if the
underlying algebra was reconfigured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, not only has the robot a performance objective (reaching a
given point in space), the novelty-search algorithm will generate new
movements in two dimensions without knowing the terrain. But, it will
only operate with the possible actuators available and their performance
range. It is also crucial to reconsider the actuators framing the range
and nature of alternatives. This is what we achieve with our
operators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conditioning exploration by exploitation, can be considered actually
quite natural but let us remember that numerous design and creativity
methods encourage to liberate constraints and be careful with brief
formulation. &lt;em&gt;Thinking out of the box&lt;/em&gt; also requires starting by
defining the box itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the icing conditions detection project, opposing the technology
alternatives imposes to value them against a given system, integration
and regulations. Reversing the preferences, encourages to reconfigure
the value framework: new system, new integration constraints and new
regulations. The problem reformulation is built upon an exploitation
constraint and target on the move. Consequently, a fraction of the
project management is driven towards ensuring the target is managed to
satisfy preferences reversal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overcoming-biases-and-fixation-effects&#34;&gt;Overcoming biases and fixation effects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performance of exploration will be seen through the generativity of
the design practices. These will be valued relatively to reference
points which can be previously generated decisions or potential
decisions. But as the end game is to be able to decide and organize
collective action for these, it would be even more practical to set the
reference on exploration points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have discussed exploitation and &lt;em&gt;weak&lt;/em&gt; exploration natural
reliability, path dependency, can not only be biased due to bounded
rationality but also can be fixated due to lack of understanding of
environment awareness, system thinking and organizational design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newly generated concepts may be indeed challenging epistemic
interdependencies which will have to be carefully managed when these are
revealed by directly concerned decision-makers. It is then preferable to
have them actively dealing with the (re)-design practice of these
interdependencies and their rationality that was contextually
established and fixated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As James March partly addressed it (see quotation below (March

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;, 209)), he gave a few hints on how the produce of
exploration, be it foolish or not, would eventually become rational and
exploited could be used as a basis for exploration. We believe that our
model allows elucidating this mutual conditioning and how to exploit it
for exploration and vice-versa. This complement to the separation
between exploration and exploitation had been omitted in the original
model (March 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;) as noted in our literature review.
It underlines the natural interaction between what makes exploration and
exploitation. However, it doesn’t imply necessarily a continuum nor
orthogonality, but rather multiple relationships to be surfaced and
managed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is argued that the link between rationality and conventional
knowledge keeps rational technologies reliable but inhibits creative
imagination. This characterization seems plausible, but it probably
underestimates the potential contribution of rational technologies to
foolishness and radical visions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Design Thinking cases, an external observer, unfamiliar with the
history of aircraft cabin equipment and stringent standards &amp;amp;
regulations, could easily consider product designs, interfaces and usage
totally foolish. Different value networks taken from other user
experience (passenger, cabin crew) will confront to rationally developed
products and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anchoring the exploration to exploitation provides a playground to
relieve constraints faced by dominant designs, promoting new
interactions with users, or even hacking altogether how things are done
and envision a new environment (e.g. lower deck, passenger boarding).
However, the learning associated with the defixation is to be further
explained as it unlocks several interdependencies that are not
self-evident when just showcasing concepts or prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performance is discussed in different ways and through action
engaged in the decision-design process. Adaption model is left close
enough to optimizing decision and richer exploration can be achieved by
challenging beliefs, preferences order and states of nature.
Interactions can be managed around these parameters. And the
encapsulation can be tracked and positioned with respect to learning
challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, not only the distance is generated away from a dominant design,
fixation points and ingrained interdependencies, but it is also key to
enable the constant transformational dialog between these two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance of decision design is then substantiated through the
heuristics presented earlier and the necessity of interacting through
them. It will target multiple parameters in engineering design and
constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;model-synthesis&#34;&gt;Model synthesis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, the figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:modelADM&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:modelADM&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;
represents, with C-K formalism, the different designed decision
categories and the knowledge used. We specify the different &lt;strong&gt;wishful
decisions&lt;/strong&gt; and the enabling knowledge hacked to design new decisions
and new states of nature.
Following customs in C-K theory, the dominant design is left on the left
of the concept tree where we have put the wishful decision by
optimization ($d_{opt}$). A variation to the optimization can be then to
design by considering a wishful decision by genericity ($d^{gen}$). It
considers as many states of nature possible by defining an envelop of
consequences that the decision should be ready to address. Then, hacking
the states of nature, opens a new branch with two new designed decisions
categories: wishful decision by best choice hacking and all choices
hacking. The first tackles what could be the dominant, what is more
obvious, the sure thing principle. The second shifts the decision
problem in a new environment.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-ambidextrous-decision-making-by-deciding-into-the-unknown-with-design&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/modelADM.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ambidextrous decision-making by deciding into the unknown with design&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/modelADM.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Ambidextrous decision-making by deciding into the unknown with design
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The table
&lt;a href=&#34;#table:modelADMtab&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;table:modelADMtab&#34;&gt;[table:modelADMtab]&lt;/a&gt;,
brings the comparison between the newly designed model of mutual
conditioning of exploration/exploitation and the former derived from the
literature. Several items have to be further specified given the chosen
descriptors used for the anomaly detection. We have discussed the
fixation effects and necessary anchoring to exploitation parameters
facilitating the management of exploration. The mutual conditioning
between exploration and exploitation will channel learning, dealing with
interdependencies. Therefore, it will also require looking beyond the
cognitive dimension of decision-designing. Organization design, the
mirroring dynamic as well as action modes organizing &lt;em&gt;decisional
ambidexterity&lt;/em&gt; will have to be taken into account to fully cover the
anomalies identified with all descriptors.
These incomplete model features presented in the following table will be
discussed in the [following chapter]
(https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter9/).
The organizational metabolism can then be discussed in more detail to
sustain organizational change and learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Non-mutual conditioning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mutual conditioning extended model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1. Not necessarily on the same continuum, exploration and exploitation call for two dissociate action regimes.&lt;br&gt;2. Balancing is left as a paradox at different levels of analysis: structure (centralization, distribution), time and individuals.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1. Exploration and exploitation are mutually used to support extended decision-making. &lt;br&gt;2. The balancing paradox is dealt by design operators valuing mutual benefits of exploration and exploitation. It is organized through interactive decision-design practices. &lt;br&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;To be completed. See next chapter&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3. The nature of generative processes supporting exploration appears quite free, random and sometimes even foolishness-based. &lt;br&gt;3. Generativity of the product development may not be sustained by (temporary) organizations (floating issue).&lt;br&gt;4. The performance and reference are light structured: reduced to a selection issue or sometimes to complex interactionist phenomenon.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3. Generative processes target the exploration/exploitation bone of contention and associated decision-making.&lt;br&gt;4. Generativity is articulated around design fixations and interdependencies for better interactive value management with other (silent) decision-designer.&lt;br&gt;5. Performance is repositioned on the transformative feature of decision-design where its criteria are redefined. &lt;br&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;To be completed. See next chapter&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6. One-way interaction: Environment to Organization.&lt;br&gt;7. The environment structures the response, nature and distribution of generative processes.&lt;br&gt;8. The environment is used to augment the product development requirements.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6. The environment is managed through decision-design.&lt;br&gt;7. The decision-design addresses environment-induced fixations.&lt;br&gt;8. The environment awareness developed through decision-design targets also (potential) interdependencies and future exploitation features. &lt;br&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;To be completed. See next chapter&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9. Organization design is pre-conceived or uncontrolled. &lt;br&gt;10. Organization design creates gaps for managing generative processes and the dynamics of their organizational ties.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See next chapter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis-designing-decisions-for-cognitive-ambidexterity&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis: designing decisions for cognitive ambidexterity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We have used the requirements listed in the previous chapter after
detecting and specifying the anomalies in several cases. We have then
proposed to start anew by coming back to the beginning of our literature
review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The canonical model of decision theory (Wald &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Wald1949&#34;&gt;1949&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Wald1945a&#34;&gt;1945&lt;/a&gt;) is mobilized to consider the problems-solving
with uncertainty described in the seminal paper (March
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;). As we had repeatedly tested the edges of the
literature models of non-mutual conditioning between exploration and
exploitation, we have used the teachings of design theory to extend
decision theory into the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It allowed specifying different decision categories and heuristics
playing with decision problem parameters and formulation. The model
proposed an &lt;strong&gt;extended risk management&lt;/strong&gt; as the uncertainty is increased
by design but at the same time uses exploitation core specified by
fixation effects, biases of bounded rationality and interdependencies to
ground exploration and manage its generativity and value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also made reference to the previous anomalies and made sense of
them with the help of the decision ambidexterity. They fall into several
designed decision categories in the unknown and they let clarifying what
has been missed or what was in the blind spot of models of
ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following chapter complements the gaps left in the model’s
description as we had specified several organizational descriptors to
detect the anomalies. We will define further decisional ambidexterity
with our concern for strategic management and organizational learning
and change.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Cully2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cully, Antoine, Jeff Clune, Danesh Tarapore, and Jean-Baptiste Mouret.
2015. “Robots that can adapt like animals.” &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; 521 (7553): 503–7.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/nature14422&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/nature14422&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Epstein1984&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein, R, C E Kirshnit, R P Lanza, and L C Rubin. 1984. “Insight in
the pigeon: antecedents and determinants of an intelligent performance.”
&lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; 308 (5954): 61–62. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/308061a0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/308061a0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Epstein1990&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epstein, Robert. 1990. “Generativity Theory and Creativity.” In
&lt;em&gt;Theories of Creativity&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Mark A. Runco and Robert S. Albert,
116–40. Sage Publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Farjoun2010&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farjoun, Moshe. 2010. “Beyond dualism: Stability and change as a
duality.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management Review&lt;/em&gt; 35 (2): 202–25.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/AMR.2010.48463331&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/AMR.2010.48463331&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Fourcade2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourcade, Marion, and Rakesh Khurana. 2013. “From social control to
financial economics: the linked ecologies of economics and business in
twentieth century America.” &lt;em&gt;Theory and Society&lt;/em&gt; 42 (2): 121–59.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11186-012-9187-3&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11186-012-9187-3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Giocoli2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giocoli, Nicola. 2013. “From Wald to Savage: Homo Economicus Becomes a
Bayesian Statistician.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of the History of the Behavioral
Sciences&lt;/em&gt; 49 (1): 63–95. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/jhbs.21579&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/jhbs.21579&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hatchuel2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatchuel, Armand, and Benoit Weil. 2009. “C-K design theory: An advanced
formulation.” &lt;em&gt;Research in Engineering Design&lt;/em&gt; 19 (4): 181–92.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00163-008-0043-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00163-008-0043-4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-VonHippel2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hippel, Eric von, and Georg von Krogh. 2016. “CROSSROADS—Identifying
Viable ‘Need–Solution Pairs’: Problem Solving Without Problem
Formulation.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 27 (1): 207–21.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/doi:10.1287/orsc.2015.1023&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/doi:10.1287/orsc.2015.1023&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Glatin, Mario, Pascal Le Masson, and Benoît Weil. 2017. “Generative
action and preference reversal in exploratory project management.” &lt;em&gt;CERN
IdeaSquare Journal of Experimental Innovation&lt;/em&gt; 1 (2): 39–46.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeMasson2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Masson, Pascal, Armand Hatchuel, Mario Le Glatin, and Benoit Weil.
2018. “Designing Decisions in the Unknown: A Generative Model.”
&lt;em&gt;European Management Review&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/emre.12289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/emre.12289&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lumineau2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lumineau, Fabrice, and Alain Verbeke. 2016. “Let’s give opportunism the
proper back seat.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management Review&lt;/em&gt; 41 (4): 739–41.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2015.0410&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2015.0410&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-March1991&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March, James G. 1991. “Exploration and exploitation in organizational
learning.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 2: 71–87.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-March2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March, James G. 2006. “Rationality, foolishness, and adaptive
intelligence.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 27 (3): 201–14.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.515&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.515&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Nguyen2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nguyen, AM, J Yosinski, and J Clune. 2015. “Innovation engines:
Automated creativity and improved stochastic optimization via deep
learning.” &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2015 on Genetic&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2754703&#34;&gt;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2754703&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Nonaka2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonaka, Ikujiro, Ayano Hirose, and Yusaku Takeda. 2016.
“‘Meso’-Foundations of Dynamic Capabilities: Team-Level Synthesis and
Distributed Leadership as the Source of Dynamic Creativity.” &lt;em&gt;Global
Strategy Journal&lt;/em&gt; 6 (3): 168–82. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/gsj.1125&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/gsj.1125&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Oury1983&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oury, Jean-Marc, and Christian Schmidt. 1983. &lt;em&gt;Economie politique de la
vigilance&lt;/em&gt;. Paris: Calmann-Lévy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Raiffa1968&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raiffa, H. 1968. &lt;em&gt;Decision Analysis: Introductory Lectures on Choices
Under Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;. Mcgraw-Hill College.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Savage1954&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savage, Leonard. 1954. &lt;em&gt;The foundations of statistics&lt;/em&gt;. 2. New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Sutcliffe2012&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sutcliffe, Kathleen M., and Marlys K. Christianson. 2012. “Managing the
Unexpected.” In &lt;em&gt;The Oxford Handbook of Positive Organizational
Scholarship&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199734610.013.0064&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199734610.013.0064&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Wald1945a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wald, Abraham. 1945. “Statistical Decision Functions Which Minimize the
Maximum Risk.” &lt;em&gt;The Annals of Mathematics&lt;/em&gt; 46 (2): 265.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/1969022&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/1969022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Wald1949&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 1949. “Statistical Decision Functions.” &lt;em&gt;Annals of Mathematical
Statistics&lt;/em&gt; 20 (2): 165–205. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1214/aoms/1177730030&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1214/aoms/1177730030&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is considered as foundational for decision-theory, as (Savage

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Savage1954&#34;&gt;1954&lt;/a&gt;) derived his model from it, as well as the
management variant of (Raiffa 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Raiffa1968&#34;&gt;1968&lt;/a&gt;). In (Giocoli

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Giocoli2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;), the model’s trajectory over time is drawn
showing the structuring role of Bayesian probability theory, as well
as its diffusion in management education (Fourcade and Khurana

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Fourcade2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Organizing and testing decisional ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The more any quantitative social indicator is used for social
decision-making, the more subject it will be to corruption pressures and
the more apt it will be to distort and corrupt the social processes it
is intended to monitor.&lt;/em&gt; (Campbell 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Campbell1979&#34;&gt;1979&lt;/a&gt;, 85)
&lt;strong&gt;Donald T. Campbell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this second modelling chapter, we have to fill in the gaps for the
model requirements we have defined for ourselves at the end of the

&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/chapter6/&#34;&gt;anomaly detection chapter&lt;/a&gt;. The definition and specification of decisional ambidexterity in
the previous chapter addressed some of the descriptors used earlier in
our methodological approach. The organizational dimension was not fully
discussed as we have mainly stressed the decision-designing to revisit
the mutual conditioning between exploration and exploitation in order to
start anew with organizational ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recalling our review on project based management, interactionism and
organization design, we will build upon limitations previously
identified to complete our decisional ambidexterity model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    First, we discuss the question of simultaneity where (exploration)
project management should consider also the change management (Pollack
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Pollack2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;; Hornstein &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hornstein2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;). It will
enable us to take into account the mirroring hypothesis (Colfer and
Baldwin &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Colfer2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) and its dynamics as fixation effects
and interdependencies are seen in engineering design and organizational
dimensions. Second, we will come back to concept organizational
metabolism (Hatchuel, Weil, and Le Masson &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;;
Segrestin et al. &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Segrestin2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;) allowing overcoming the
iterations of traditional double bind of structure and processes.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-dichotomy-simultaneity&#34;&gt;Beyond dichotomy: simultaneity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The different cases presented in the anomaly detection chapter revealed
several tensions associated with the encapsulation of generative
processes and their potential free-floating across organizations (Lenfle

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lenfle2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;). Decisional ambidexterity allows focusing on
the micro-foundations of exploration/exploitation dichotomy: revisiting
the decision-making by considering decision-design permits touching upon
one of the key aspects of coordination and collective action organizing
for innovation. The way action is engaged, the way decisions are made,
and the way organization members network (Christiansen and Varnes

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Christiansen2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;) can be captured through the
decision-design in the C-K formalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transformation, due to exploration, or the one faced in exploitation
because of the unexpected, can imply an active role for
decision-designers as they play on states of nature, the degrees of
beliefs and the cost functions will be redefined. Consequently, at the
project management level depending on the framing imposed to the
decision-design and the underlying engineering brief, the
interdependencies can be controlled or even avoided depending on the
aimed independence level. The latter will contribute to the innovation
potential of attraction at the organizational level: how business units
will host, support, redesign their organizations or recombine their
capabilities for such projects. As we remember, we are not interested in
spin-off and other ad-hoc phenomena, we want the organization to
regenerate itself &amp;ldquo;within its boundaries&amp;rdquo; by relying on its
organizational metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    We start discussing the implications of decisional ambidexterity for
project management, as it will design decisions at the project level
that can quickly address several interdependencies reaching out for
permanent organizations. Then, the mirroring hypothesis gives an idea of
the relationships behind revisited design rules and interdependencies
and their organization. Modularity/genericity is an answer corresponding
to one decision category but doesn’t allow getting a full picture.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-management-product-or-organizational-change&#34;&gt;Project management: product or organizational change?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;uncertaintyunknown-buffer-to-manage-the-ecosystem-relationship&#34;&gt;Uncertainty/Unknown buffer to manage the ecosystem relationship&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had specified that the project-based organization was probably an
efficient way of organizing the firm to face uncertainties. Projects can
be seen as uncertainty buffers (Davies, Manning, and Söderlund

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Davies2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;, 971):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;integrate cross-functional resources and knowledge to cope with high
uncertainty, complexity and change&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we remember that when pushing this form into the unknown
reveals several difficulties that are exacerbated in cases where the
organization’s identity and boundaries are tied by market rigidities
tightly linked to product engineering. Zodiac Aerospace is a proper
example of such pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Icing Conditions Detection case was a vehicle to shape the unknown,
an example of decisional ambidexterity, by playing on preferences’ order
to value the unknown and manage the ecosystem. It built its own autonomy
through public funding and legitimation with key industrial players. It
allowed more flexibility compared to a traditional exploration that
would have been fully hosted by an engineering or product development
department with a functional form. Just like in the two other cases
analysed previously, the projects were sponsored by middle and top
management, sometimes even having a key isolated position from other
routines. It gives freedom to operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship to the environment and the ways projects engage with it
relocates organizational adaptation and learning at the project level in
a temporary organization, whereas organizational ambidexterity would
have a tendency to materialise it in a permanent organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    In a sense, enforcing institutionalization (O’Connor
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-OConnor2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) of innovation function or organizational
ambidexterity could be dangerous for the firm’s cohesion and coherent
action. Specially, if it is not sustained by clear managerial action and
engineering at the project level that clearly embeds the change
management and adaptation to the environment. Decisional ambidexterity
allows then reconciliating this change of locus.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-vehicle-for-change-which-manageable-parameters&#34;&gt;A vehicle for change: which manageable parameters?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The necessity of change appears as the interdependencies have shifted
(Stan and Puranam 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Stan2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;). It is deep down what makes
management a reality. Organizing collective action is necessary only at
the wake of novelty forcing a transformational experience.
If the project brings some novelty through decisional ambidexterity it
will rely on existing interdependencies (exploitation) to generate new
alternatives. The mutual conditioning is required to surface and manage
interdependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When discussing the interface between design and manufacturing
activities in (Adler 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Adler1995&#34;&gt;1995&lt;/a&gt;), the author targets the
cruciality of coordination mechanisms around interdependencies defined
by the new product development. Mutual adjustment and interaction models
will vary depending on the analysability of product/process fit. It is
key to be able to reflect the organizational change required for the
engineering interdependencies as they will be directly used as
springboards to articulate the mutual conditioning between exploration
and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As new decisions are designed along projects trajectories, they can
phase out compared to established organizations. It forces to conform
the project to the host and permanent organization. It can even
(implicitly) consider that the host or integrating BU would not change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Design Thinking projects, as well as the BC seat platform, when
transferring the designed products and made decisions, they faced the
exploitation regime in permanent organizations with established
engineering design rules. The learning and organizational change was not
on the menu of the project nor handover with the redesign of
decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, ADT did try to refine designs, but it was rather an
optimization effort instead of playing on states of nature to envision
the required change in engineering constraints, product interfaces,
standards, regulations, market segmentation, business models, etc. For
the seat platform, the learning and design rules evolution came after
relying on late and repeated mechanical tests which confirmed previously
discussed but underestimated numerical simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    In order to embed the organizational change management within project
management (Pollack &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Pollack2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;; Hornstein
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hornstein2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;), we must then clarify how the engineering
interdependencies and fixation effects are dealt with at the
organizational level. In (Stjerne and Svejenova
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Stjerne2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;), the work at the boundaries of temporary
organizations lets overcoming the dialectics of temporary and permanent
organizing. It brings a multi-level perspective we propose to channel
through decision design: decisional ambidexterity.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mirroring-hypothesis-a-static-view&#34;&gt;Mirroring hypothesis: a static view&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had identified in the literature the mirroring hypothesis (Colfer and
Baldwin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Colfer2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;). We could a priori use decisional
ambidexterity in exploration project management that considers existing
product design architecture as a starting point. It would involve a
number of design rules reflecting the managerial technology. Behind the
scenes, sensemaking interprets and adapts to make actual practice
(Christiansen and Varnes 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Christiansen2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;) giving some
flexibility to the rules. So the (partial) mirroring is obtained through
established technologies of organizing which can have different levels
of independence, hence clustering the sub-organizations for product
sub-systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;modularity&#34;&gt;Modularity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modularity and loosed coupling (Sanchez and Mahoney

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Sanchez1996&#34;&gt;1996&lt;/a&gt;) can then be the purpose of decision-design in
order to be able to adapt easily and reached strategic flexibility.
Instead of being seen as an adaptation to the environment turbulences,
it could also be actively co-designed from the product engineering
perspective. Having such approach to modularity could also be envisioned
temporarily before reintegration (Siggelkow and Levinthal

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Siggelkow2003&#34;&gt;2003&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the BC seat platform project, the aim was to define an architecture
and organize modularity. However, such effort was not reached and
practices of exploitation took over. The existing interdependencies as
well as evolving standards with the modularity choices taken were not
made clear to stakeholders to redefine its mirroring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform engineering, or designing a &lt;em&gt;wishful decision by genericity&lt;/em&gt;,
is an exploration effort as per which exploitation constraints and
parameters can be built upon to define new design rules, and
consequently organize engineering departments, manufacturing as well as
supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Therefore, in the knowledge space defined in our C-K modelling of
decisional ambidexterity, it would be useful to add the organizational
partial mirroring of interdependencies as these will require to be
transformed due to the product engineering practice. These are decision
parameters that can be resurfaced and explicitly related to organization
design.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;stress-testing-absorbing-uncertaintyunknown&#34;&gt;Stress testing: absorbing uncertainty/unknown?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The perspective of modularity and genericity, which is one of the
decisions $d^{gen}$ in our model, brings the possibility of managing
double unknown situations (Kokshagina et al.

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Kokshagina2016a&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) specially through adapted portfolio
management. In a similar way, (Hooge et al. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hooge2014&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;), and
closer to our concern for decision-design, they showcase the anomaly of
willing designing a generic technology to bridge a gap between distant
fields and technologies, by opposition to the common evolutionary
strategies. Difficulties are raised regarding the sophisticated
organizational patterns, and capacity to reuse and connect existing
technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, when considering how the mirroring of interdependencies
enacted by members of the organization, the knowledge mobilised in
decision-design will require a precise understanding of the levels of
independence between elements, boundaries and purpose of each group of
other decision-designers involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Genericity and modularity will allow absorbing uncertainty quite easily,
but once the unknown slips through sub-systems, their
inter-relationships are heavily discussed. Decisional-ambidexterity
should then be able to specify and support these dynamics. In that
sense, the mirroring hypothesis is too static and perhaps only looking
at robustness and adaptive flexibility as the unknown is usually seen as
exogenous.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;endogenizing-the-unknown-dynamically-designing-projects-and-organizations&#34;&gt;Endogenizing the unknown: dynamically designing projects and organizations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisional ambidexterity encourages then to fully endogenize the unknown
into project management to address how it can be shaped into
organizations through the dynamics of interdependencies mirroring
exploitation product engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then propose to make organization design part of the decision-design
model with underlying interdependencies and fixation effects. It will
help specifying the nature of decisions covering contingencies that may
lie in the intricacies of interdependencies. These should effectively be
redesigned depending on the generativity of processes used to propose
new alternatives. The latter being one of the issues at stake revealed
by the biases induced by organizational ambidexterity and its model of
non-mutual conditioning against innovation initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model of &lt;strong&gt;decisional ambidexterity&lt;/strong&gt; for mutual conditioning
between exploration and exploitation focuses now on decision-designing
as well as organization. Consequently, this &lt;strong&gt;technology of organizing&lt;/strong&gt;
that simultaneously aims at supporting innovation project management and
change management, will spread out and ripple through established
processes and structures and hence contributing to the &lt;strong&gt;metabolism of
an innovative organization&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    We first discuss organization design in the unknown and how to overcome
organization design fixations. Generative learning sustained through
decision design can support disentanglement of interdependencies and
fixations. Then, we introduce the necessity to overtake the duality of
structure and processes. We focus on how decisional ambidexterity can
sustain organizational metabolism.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organization-design-in-the-unknown-and-against-organizational-fixation&#34;&gt;Organization design in the unknown and against organizational fixation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organization design requires to be thought differently at the light of
decisional ambidexterity, as we force to bring the unknown and its
management at the level of projects and interactions around
decision-making, now decision-designing. The potential of transformation
and attraction, channelled through extended decision spaces, gives a new
flavour to the organization design features specially for
interdependencies and fixations effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-unknown-organization-design&#34;&gt;The unknown organization design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difficulty for standard organization design is when considering
unknown information of unknown value, as the necessity to establish
relationships between agents is hard to justify (Puranam, Raveendran,
and Knudsen 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Puranam2012a&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;). And it is not only by having
people together that they will be able to solve new problems, let aside
formulating new problems themselves. When trying to foresee the future
of organization design when facing the unknown, the importance of having
a new method for normative field becomes critical (Puranam

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Puranam2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;). The methodology developed over several
decades in design theory and reasoning can fortuitously support such
initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By considering the importance of action, interaction and decision in
organizations, we can centralize such key phenomena into organization
design. The contributions of (silent) decision-designers continuously
referring to exploitation will help valuing exploration and vice-versa.
The multiple interactions required to make sense of decisions, product
design and engineering design rules become quite attractive for
organizational studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Design Thinking projects, concepts wouldn’t fit BUs or even
multi-BU prospects. Engineering rules had to change, product lines and
BUs respective boundaries were contested through the designed and
selected concepts by ADT, group VP of Strategy and Business Development,
and during multi-BU workshops. The confrontation and adaptation would
only rely on a separation of exploration/exploitation regimes.
Generative processes were guided by product design objectives, as well
as environment perspectives (user value and empathy) but failed to
address the potential organization redesign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Placing the unknown right at the centre of organization design can
probably overcome caveats of simple solutions or adjustments that only
have a concern for: balance of hierarchical control, individual autonomy
and spontaneous cooperation (Keidel 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Keidel1994&#34;&gt;1994&lt;/a&gt;). A
&lt;strong&gt;technology of organizing&lt;/strong&gt; could then substantiate the &lt;em&gt;generative
learning&lt;/em&gt; (Senge 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Senge1990&#34;&gt;1990&lt;/a&gt;) by deriving from the decisional
ambidexterity model. Such device could help have a better understanding
of required organization design and its &lt;em&gt;generative fit&lt;/em&gt; (Avital and
Te’eni 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Avital2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;; Van de Ven, Ganco, and Hinings

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-VandeVen2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning can then be overseen in our model as it will have to be challenged as interdependencies will be unlocked, reinforced or reconfigured depending on how the decision-designers explore exploitation and exploit exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;managing-interdependencies-and-organization-fixation-effects&#34;&gt;Managing interdependencies and organization fixation effects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of meta-organizations (Gulati, Puranam, and Tushman

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gulati2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;) and also open-innovation, rethinking of
organization design can not be seen as fully transposed to problem/task
decomposition by leadership (Lakhani, Lifshitz-Assaf, and Tushman

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lakhani2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;). We have seen that the identity of
organization can be so strong due to engineering and regulations, that
problem formulation in exploration project management can escape from
the attraction of organization competence. So, trying to keeping it
together, and build new coherence through the transformation triggered
by design activities, requires to shift the locus of change down to the
micro-level of interdependencies and fixation effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Icing Conditions detection, the BU manager ended up having a
valuable exploration project recognized in the industrial ecosystem but
at odds with the organization. Again, we have a case where the
exploration was driven by several expansive decisions changing the game
but the interdependencies with systems engineering mastered with the
business have to be reworked. The transferred unfinished but flight
tested product should be seen as a learning device rather than fit for
development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixation effects could be associated to the state-of-art in product
development, and the gradual convergence towards a common consensus,
which may be biased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    The constitution of new path will have to emerge through the
interactions created by discussing the value of designed decisions and
concepts anchored to dominant design. These interactions will support
the organization change that is required to support new business
development (Simon and Tellier &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Simon2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;): resources and
development of capabilities mobilized around a project. It confirms the
networking dimension that can be organized around alleged decision
meetings (Christiansen and Varnes &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Christiansen2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;).
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sustaining-metabolisms-regenerating-the-organization&#34;&gt;Sustaining metabolisms: regenerating the organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As discussed in the anomalies specification (chapter
&lt;a href=&#34;#chap:anomalies_spec&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;chap:anomalies_spec&#34;&gt;[chap:anomalies_spec]&lt;/a&gt;),
embedding change management within project management calls for
phenomena rippling across structures and processes, as we propose to do
with centrality of action, decision and design for organizing. The
biological metaphor of metabolisms allows targeting &amp;ldquo;processes&amp;rdquo; that are
tied by the double bind of structure and processes. It puts the emphasis
on the &lt;em&gt;actionable knowledge&lt;/em&gt; and relationships (Segrestin et al.

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Segrestin2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;), instead of separating management of
structure and process. The constructs of regenerative capabilities and
recombination of routines in organization can be then further
substantiated with decisional ambidexterity and organizational
metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;regenerative-dynamic-capabilities&#34;&gt;Regenerative dynamic capabilities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difficulty associated with the innovation function distributed
across projects (Gemünden, Lehner, and Kock 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gemunden2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;)
goes to the distributed nature of capabilities. Making the sum won’t be
representative of the overall capabilities available in underlying host
functional departments. However, by considering they will be organizing
their trajectory around decision-design with supplying departments,
other business units, as well as external players, can create a pivotal
force for stakeholders to understand in which direction change should
occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the BC seat platform project, in the early stages of defining the
extent and features of genericity, several stakeholders took part in
designing concepts, even marginally, but also to designing what had to
be decided. The sense made out of those meetings, and its contribution
to generating alternatives, represents a capability to regenerate seat
engineering. Unfortunately, a similar effort was not sustained when
switching from exploration to exploitation due to a strong divide
enforced by ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As teams and organization will cope with these different temporalities,
first locally at the project level, and then at the program level (Simon
and Tellier 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Simon2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;), it gives us confidence on the value
of our model. Temporary-organizing will reach a meta-equilibrium during
when designing-decisions, as they make sense and rethink the new
coordination mechanisms supporting the new product development. We
contribute then to the idea of having regenerative capabilities
(Ambrosini, Bowman, and Collier 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Ambrosini2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;, S15)
supported by decisional ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;recombining-routines&#34;&gt;Recombining routines&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a similar way, the idea of recombining routines (Cohendet and Simon

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Cohendet2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) fostered by a single project, can be the
occasion to rethink product design rules that have been fixated for some
time. In their case, they specify the importance of meetings held,
prototypes and proof of concepts that were tailored and managed by
project manager to make a case for a radical product concept, at odds
with exploitation regime. Resurfacing interdependencies and design
fixation with such practices can be a means to make tacit the designing
of decisions and learning mechanisms that can be mapped with C-K theory
as we did in the previous chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is also stimulating here is that, innovation management does
necessarily have to supported by additional routines. Within a set of
routines, they can be reconfigured to create &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; value, as if the
scales and units changed in nature. It is what we tried to picture with
the Pareto front and reaching out for alternatives (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter1/#shifting-the-performance-frontier-with-innovation&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Design Thinking cases, some concepts actually implied recombining
routines across business units who were traditionally segregated by the
market and engineering standards. Focusing on the product and design
rules would only force adaptation, whereas the obstacle was rather on
elevating interactions on the how and its legitimacy for users, but also
the remaining effort: change in sales pitch, market channel, one-time
qualification, evolving standards and certification forms, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it would be such contextuality that could be associated with
contextual ambidexterity but detailed in its interaction modes
(Birkinshaw and Gupta 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;). It would now make
more sense with the limitations on the nature and dichotomy of
exploration/exploitation regimes discussed in the very same paper and in
(Gupta, Smith, and Shalley 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gupta2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The networking effect (Christiansen and Varnes

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Christiansen2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;) can easily be structured around the
dialogue interdependent and fixation knots. It encourages channelling
the access to (distant) knowledge, legitimize the mutual conditioning
between exploration and exploitation (Simon and Tellier

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Simon2011a&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;). But here again, we insist on the technology of
organizing collective action through decisional ambidexterity
facilitating the grounding of such interactive patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    So far, we have proposed then to embed the organization design within
our decisional ambidexterity. We have emphasized the need to organize
the decision-design around exploitation constraints such as
interdependencies and fixation effects, not only at the product
engineering level, but also at the organizational level. Routines and
capabilities can be articulated around the designed decision to sustain
the &lt;em&gt;metabolism&lt;/em&gt; triggered by associated concepts. These elements
contribute to making its &lt;em&gt;innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; dragging
along not only a cognitive fit, but also an organizational generative
fit.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;full-model-synthesis&#34;&gt;Full model synthesis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have then specified the interest of having organization design
embedded in the designing of decisions, by considering that
organizations are part of the knowledge required to enact decision
concepts. Consequently, we propose simply to represent in the C-K
formalism what makes decision and its hypotheses with organizational
ties and mirroring: interdependencies and fixation effects. They are the
translation at the organizational level that can be easily disturbed by
generative processes: i.e. where tension and anomalies come from between
models of ambidexterity and exploration project management. In other
words, we insist once again on the link between actionable knowledge and
relationships, and how it can metabolize innovation in the organization
with its structure and processes.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-decisional-ambidexterity-decision-designing-and-organization-design&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/modelADMb.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Decisional ambidexterity: decision-designing and organization design&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/modelADMb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Decisional ambidexterity: decision-designing and organization design
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listing the engineering design fixations, interdependencies and built-in
product architecture, will help addressing the regenerative dynamic
capabilities and recombination of routines required to manage the
organizational metabolism. The change management will then be steered
through the inter-relationships bearing generative learning triggered by
the collective decision-designing. It is again the mutual conditioning
of exploration and exploitation which allows simply measuring change.
In the following table
&lt;a href=&#34;#table:modelADMtabfull&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;table:modelADMtabfull&#34;&gt;[table:modelADMtabfull]&lt;/a&gt;,
we can complete the model synthesis with the descriptors derived from
previous literature review. We remember the synthetic literature model
of non-mutual conditioning enabling its comparison with
decisional-ambidexterity model which blends the conditioning between
exploration and exploitation. It allows overcoming biases induced by
organization ambidexterity and its limitations such as neglect of
organization design fixations revealed by exploration project
management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model descriptors&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Non-mutual conditioning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mutual conditioning extended model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1. Not necessarily on the same continuum, exploration and exploitation call for two dissociate action regimes. &lt;br&gt;2.Balancing is left as a paradox at different levels of analysis: structure (centralization, distribution), time and individuals.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1. Exploration and exploitation are mutually used to support extended decision-making. &lt;br&gt;2. The balancing paradox is dealt by design operators valuing mutual benefits of exploration and exploitation. Decision-designers interactively unlock and manage (new) interdependencies and (organizational) design fixations. A form of governance may be required to orchestrate and sustain such practice.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3. The nature of generative processes supporting exploration appears quite free, random and sometimes even foolishness-based. &lt;br&gt;4. Generativity of the product development may not be sustained by (temporary) organizations (floating issue).&lt;br&gt;5. The performance and reference is light structured: reduced to a selection issue or sometimes to complex interactionist phenomenon.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3. Generative processes target the exploration/exploitation bone of contention and associated decision-making.&lt;br&gt;4. Generativity is articulated around design fixations and interdependencies for better interactive value management with other (silent) decision-designer.&lt;br&gt;5. Performance is repositioned on the transformative feature of decision-design where its criteria are redefined. Managing the organizational mirroring of interdependencies and fixations is part of the performance assessment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environment cognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6. One-way interaction: Environment to Organization.&lt;br&gt;7. The environment structures the response, nature and distribution of generative processes.&lt;br&gt;8. The environment is used to augment the product development requirements.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6. The environment is managed through the design of decision to realize designed states of nature.&lt;br&gt;7. The decision-design addresses environment-induced fixations.&lt;br&gt;8. The environment awareness developed through decision-design targets also (potential) interdependencies, future exploitation features, and organization design fixations induced by environment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9. Organization design is pre-conceived or uncontrolled. &lt;br&gt;10. Organization design creates gaps for managing generative processes and the dynamics of their organizational ties.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9. Organization design is simultaneously managed with decision-design in project management as it has explored exploitation interdependencies and fixations.&lt;br&gt;10. Relationships and actionable knowledge are concurrently managed through decisional-ambidexterity thus embedding the organizational change management.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis-decisional-ambidexterity-and-organization-design&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis: decisional ambidexterity and organization design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This chapter has extended the first version of decisional ambidexterity
model with our concern for organization design and change management. We
are then able to satisfy the requirements defined in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/chapter7/&#34;&gt;chapter 7&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We re-use the idea of simultaneity of change management with project
management (Pollack &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Pollack2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;) to endogenize the unknown
further with decision-design perspective. Organization design and
regenerating capabilities were included as knowledge elements required
to generate new decision concepts and enabling the organization of
collective action supporting them. We can then manage a metabolism
sustaining innovation effort through organizational change. Our model
should be considered as basis for &lt;strong&gt;technology of organizing&lt;/strong&gt; to
orchestrate and channel interactions for decision-designers contribution
to exploration project management and dynamically mirrored
organizational change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anomalies were discussed at the light of decisional ambidexterity.
The case studies reveal several features of decisional ambidexterity and
why they were misunderstood given models of ambidexterity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, we have a full model of mutual conditioning between
exploration and exploitation capable of explaining the descriptors
reconciling with the identified literature models’ limitations: model of
coordination and collective action, and the innovation potential of
attraction (generative processes, environment cognition, organization
design).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Adler1995&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adler, Paul S. 1995. “Interdepartmental Interdependence and
Coordination: The Case of the Design/Manufacturing Interface.”
&lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 6 (2): 147–67.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.6.2.147&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.6.2.147&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Ambrosini2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambrosini, Véronique, Cliff Bowman, and Nardine Collier. 2009. “Dynamic
Capabilities: An Exploration of How Firms Renew their Resource Base.”
&lt;em&gt;British Journal of Management&lt;/em&gt; 20 (SUPP. 1): S9–S24.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8551.2008.00610.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8551.2008.00610.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Avital2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avital, Michel, and Dov Te’eni. 2009. “From generative fit to generative
capacity: exploring an emerging dimension of information systems design
and task performance.” &lt;em&gt;Information Systems Journal&lt;/em&gt; 19 (4): 345–67.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2575.2007.00291.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2575.2007.00291.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birkinshaw, Julian, and Kamini Gupta. 2013. “Clarifying the distinctive
contribution of ambidexterity to the field of organization studies.”
&lt;em&gt;The Academy of Management Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; 27 (4): 287–98.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Campbell1979&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell, Donald T. 1979. “Assessing the impact of planned social
change.” &lt;em&gt;Evaluation and Program Planning&lt;/em&gt; 2 (1): 67–90.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/0149-7189(79)90048-X&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/0149-7189(79)90048-X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Christiansen2007&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christiansen, John K., and Claus J. Varnes. 2007. “Making decisions on
innovation: Meetings or networks?” &lt;em&gt;Creativity and Innovation
Management&lt;/em&gt; 16 (3): 282–98.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8691.2007.00441.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8691.2007.00441.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Christiansen2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2009. “Formal rules in product development: Sensemaking of
structured approaches.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Product Innovation Management&lt;/em&gt; 26
(5): 502–19. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-5885.2009.00677.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-5885.2009.00677.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Cohendet2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohendet, Patrick, and Laurent Simon. 2016. “Always Playable:
Recombining Routines for Creative Efficiency at Ubisoft Montreal’s Video
Game Studio.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 27 (3): 614–32.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.2016.1062&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.2016.1062&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Colfer2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colfer, Lyra J., and Carliss Y. Baldwin. 2016. “The mirroring
hypothesis: Theory, evidence, and exceptions.” &lt;em&gt;Industrial and Corporate
Change&lt;/em&gt; 25 (5): 709–38. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/icc/dtw027&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/icc/dtw027&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Davies2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davies, Andrew, Stephan Manning, and Jonas Söderlund. 2018. “When
neighboring disciplines fail to learn from each other: The case of
innovation and project management research.” &lt;em&gt;Research Policy&lt;/em&gt; 47 (5):
965–79. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2018.03.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2018.03.002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gemunden2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gemünden, Hans Georg, Patrick Lehner, and Alexander Kock. 2018. “The
project-oriented organization and its contribution to innovation.”
&lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 36 (1): 147–60.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2017.07.009&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2017.07.009&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gulati2012&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gulati, Ranjay, Phanish Puranam, and Michael Tushman. 2012.
“Meta-organization design: Rethinking design in interorganizational and
community contexts.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 33 (6): 571–86.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.1975&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.1975&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gupta2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gupta, Anil K, Ken G Smith, and Christina E Shalley. 2006. “The
Interplay Between Exploration and Exploitation.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management
Journal&lt;/em&gt; 49 (4): 693–706. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amj.2006.22083026&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amj.2006.22083026&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hatchuel2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatchuel, Armand, Benoît Weil, and Pascal Le Masson. 2006. “Building
innovation capabilities. The development of design-oriented
organizations.” In &lt;em&gt;Innovation, Learning and Macro Institutional Change:
Patterns of Knowledge Changes&lt;/em&gt;, edited by J T Hage, 1–26. Oxford,
England: Oxford University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hooge2014&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hooge, Sophie, Olga Kokshagina, Pascal Le Masson, Kevin Levillain,
Benoit Weil, Vincent Fabreguettes, and Nathalie Popiolek. 2014.
“Designing generic technologies in Energy Research: learning from two
CEA technologies for double unknown management.” In &lt;em&gt;European Academy of
Management - Euram 2014&lt;/em&gt;, 33. Valencia, Spain.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hal-mines-paristech.archives-ouvertes.fr/hal-00987214&#34;&gt;https://hal-mines-paristech.archives-ouvertes.fr/hal-00987214&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hornstein2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hornstein, Henry A. 2015. “The integration of project management and
organizational change management is now a necessity.” &lt;em&gt;International
Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 33 (2): 291–98.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.08.005&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2014.08.005&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Keidel1994&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keidel, R. W. 1994. “Rethinking organizational design.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of
Management Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; 8 (4): 12–28.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/AME.1994.9412071698&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/AME.1994.9412071698&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Kokshagina2016a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kokshagina, Olga, Pascal Le Masson, Benoit Weil, and Patrick Cogez.
2016. “Portfolio Management in Double Unknown Situations: Technological
Platforms and the Role of Cross-Application Managers.” &lt;em&gt;Creativity and
Innovation Management&lt;/em&gt; 25 (2): 270–91.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/caim.12121&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/caim.12121&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lakhani2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lakhani, Karim R., Hila Lifshitz-Assaf, and Michael Tushman. 2013. “Open
Innovation and Organizational Boundaries: The Impact of Task
Decomposition and Knowledge Distribution on the Locus of Innovation.” In
&lt;em&gt;Handbook of Economic Organization&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Anna Grandori, 355–82. 1.
Cheltenham, UK: Edward Elgar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lenfle2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenfle, Sylvain. 2016. “Floating in Space? On the Strangeness of
Exploratory Projects.” &lt;em&gt;Project Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 47 (2): 15.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21584&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21584&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-OConnor2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Connor, Gina Colarelli. 2016. “Institutionalizing corporate
entrepreneurship as the firm’s innovation function: reflections from a
longitudinal research program.” In &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Research on Corporate
Entrepreneurship&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Shaker Zahra, Donald Neubaum, and James
Hayton, 145–74. Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar Publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Pollack2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pollack, Julien. 2017. “Change Management as an Organizational and
Project Capability.” In &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Handbook of Organizational Project
Management&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Shankar Sankaran, Ralf Muller, and Nathalie
Drouin, 236–49. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316662243.021&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/9781316662243.021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Puranam2012&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puranam, Phanish. 2012. “A Future for the Science of Organization
Design.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Organization Design&lt;/em&gt; 1 (1): 18.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7146/jod.6337&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.7146/jod.6337&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Puranam2012a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puranam, Phanish, Marlo Raveendran, and Thorbjørn Knudsen. 2012.
“Organization Design: The Epistemic Interdependence Perspective.”
&lt;em&gt;Academy of Management Review&lt;/em&gt; 37 (3): 419–40.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2010.0535&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2010.0535&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Sanchez1996&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanchez, Ron, and Joseph T. Mahoney. 1996. “Modularity, Flexibility, and
Knowledge Management in Product and Organization Design.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic
Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 17: 63–76.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781107415324.004&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781107415324.004&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Segrestin2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Segrestin, Blanche, Franck Aggeri, Albert David, and Pascal Le Masson.
2017. “Armand Hatchuel and the Refoundation of Management Research:
Design Theory and the Epistemology of Collective Action.” In &lt;em&gt;The
Palgrave Handbook of Organizational Change Thinkers&lt;/em&gt;, 1–15.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-49820-1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-49820-1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Senge1990&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senge, Peter. 1990. “Leaders’ new role: building learning
organizations.” &lt;em&gt;MIT Sloan Management Review&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Siggelkow2003&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siggelkow, Nicolaj, and Daniel A. Levinthal. 2003. “Temporarily Divide
to Conquer: Centralized, Decentralized, and Reintegrated Organizational
Approaches to Exploration and Adaptation.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 14
(6): 650–69. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.14.6.650.24840&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.14.6.650.24840&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Simon2011a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon, Fanny, and Albéric Tellier. 2011. “How do actors shape social
networks during the process of new product development?” &lt;em&gt;European
Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 29 (5): 414–30.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.emj.2011.05.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.emj.2011.05.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Simon2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2016. “Balancing contradictory temporality during the unfold of
innovation streams.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 34
(6): 983–96. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2016.05.004&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2016.05.004&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Simon2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2018. “The ambivalent influence of a business developer’s social
ties in a multinational company.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of
Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management&lt;/em&gt; 22 (1-2): 166–87.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1504/IJEIM.2018.089718&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1504/IJEIM.2018.089718&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Stan2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stan, Mihaela, and Phanish Puranam. 2017. “Organizational adaptation to
interdependence shifts: The role of integrator structures.” &lt;em&gt;Strategic
Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 38 (5): 1041–61. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.2546&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/smj.2546&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Stjerne2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stjerne, Iben Sandal, and Silviya Svejenova. 2016. “Connecting Temporary
and Permanent Organizing: Tensions and Boundary Work in Sequential Film
Projects.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Studies&lt;/em&gt; 37 (12): 1771–92.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840616655492&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0170840616655492&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-VandeVen2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van de Ven, Andrew H., Martin Ganco, and C. R. (BOB) Hinings. 2013.
“Returning to the Frontier of Contingency Theory of Organizational and
Institutional Designs.” &lt;em&gt;The Academy of Management Annals&lt;/em&gt; 7 (1):
393–440. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/19416520.2013.774981&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/19416520.2013.774981&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
