<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 2 - Research methodology | Mario LE GLATIN</title>
    <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Part 2 - Research methodology</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Part 2 - Research methodology</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Methodological approach and research journey</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, we present the methodology deployed over the three
years of the PhD thesis. The methodology relies on an
intervention-research approach (Hatchuel and David

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/a&gt;) facilitated by the CIFRE contract
(&lt;em&gt;Convention Industrielle de Formation par la REcherche&lt;/em&gt; - Industrial
Convention of Training through Research).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, in section &lt;a href=&#34;#principles-of-intervention-research-in-management&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;,
we introduce the principles of intervention-research in management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in section &lt;a href=&#34;#anomaly-detection-and-modelling&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;,
we present the data collection process with the associated analysis
based on the literature model. We follow an anomaly detection
methodology in order to formulate a new model that was tested during the
last stretch of three years of the research program through validation
and application within ZA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final section &lt;a href=&#34;#role-and-position-of-the-researcher---intervention-research&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; portraits the position of the PhD candidate within the firm.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;principles-of-intervention-research-in-management&#34;&gt;Principles of intervention research in management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Intervention Research in Management (IRM) has been elaborated over
several decades of research partnerships at &lt;em&gt;Centre de Gestion
Scientifique&lt;/em&gt; (Hatchuel and David 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hatchuel2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/a&gt;).This
approach has proven efficient in revealing the intricacies of complex
managerial situations specially in the innovation management field with
the multiplicity and novelty of interactions, decisions, knowledge flows
in project and strategy management. IRM relies on two pillars: a
&lt;strong&gt;collaborative protocol and theoretical perspective&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is not to solve a definite problem proposed by an organization.
The theoretical setting can actually be rather dull at the beginning
despite bearing a certain potential. Nonetheless, a dialectic between
&lt;em&gt;established-theories-in&lt;/em&gt; use and &lt;em&gt;contextual-established-in-use&lt;/em&gt; allows
improving models of action. The point is nor to perform change
management, but rather to gain an understanding of theories-in-use,
their performativity and how models of thought can evolve within the
business. This continuous monitoring between academia and industry
through the PhD candidate enables uncovering a real research issue
supported by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-conditions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;partner with a pioneering logic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;open management issue free interviews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;contractual commitment to a research issue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;support of an academic team with research potential (PhD
directors/supervisors and research lab)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring principles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free interviews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warranted isonomy&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confidentiality of all individual interviews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capacity to create new empirical material&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controlled design&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management innovations evaluated as rational myths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this set of conditions and practices, the outputs emerge naturally
following the dynamic and symmetric feedback supported by the PhD
candidate through his meetings, steering committees with academia and
industrial colleagues. It implies testing models of thought, frameworks
drawn from the literature, and models grounded on field data based on
the case studies conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-management-issue-formulation&#34;&gt;Initial management issue formulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, the PhD research program was designed to address the topic
of economic performance of design at Airbus Aircraft. At that time, the
PhD candidate was already working within Zodiac Aerospace.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The
program discussed how design activities of project and program
management could be valued by alternative means to project objectives.
For instance, it raised that traditional learning mechanisms between
projects were hard to track such as spill-overs (Cohen and Levinthal

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Cohen1989a&#34;&gt;1989&lt;/a&gt;), and how learning could be managed from a
project to another in an efficient manner. The performance dimension,
its definition and underlying value management was central for the
topic. Today, as the PhD project was not launched in July 2015, it was
put on hold and is currently being dealt by a PhD fellow at CGS (Agathe
Gillain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this PhD subject would not come to life in its original form by 2015,
we proposed to reallocate the project to Zodiac Aerospace. With the
support of the Group HR management, a new sponsor was to be found:
Thierry Rouge Carrassat, Chief Technical and Innovation Officer for
Zodiac Aerospace. Several meetings were organized between the PhD
Directors and the CTO to provide information on the company, its
history, its context, innovation management practices and how the PhD
program would be framed by IRM methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topic was adapted, it discarded part of the economic performance
axis: the topic recentred around the old dilemma of market-pull vs.
techno-push. ZA presented several cases trying to overcome the growing
rationalization of market-pull by aircraft manufacturers and airlines.
For instance, they had two development teams close enough to market
prescribers in order to try to anticipate market-pull trends and
formulate proposal of new products/services that could federate several
BUs for more added value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, as business units were highly profitable in their
respective niche-markets covered over the history of acquisitions,
corporate management had been sponsoring techno-push initiatives. These
were steered through a &lt;em&gt;Multi-BU committee&lt;/em&gt; showcasing a mix of top-down
and bottom-up approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another salient feature was the history of acquisitions and expansion
since the establishment of the company in 1896. Zodiac Aerospace was a
conglomerate of SMEs with individual responsibility for each BUs grouped
based on market segmentation and technology proximity into so-called:
business lines, divisions and branches.
For further details on the how the PhD program was formulated, you can
refer to the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/appendix/&#34;&gt;Appendix&lt;/a&gt;.
It is a clean copy of the submission made to the ANRT (&lt;em&gt;Agence Nationale
pour la Recherche et la Technologie&lt;/em&gt;) - the agency sponsoring the CIFRE
PhD Programs nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phases-of-irm&#34;&gt;Phases of IRM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intervention research can be split into different phases that do not
necessarily represent a linear story in the research journey. The phases
are the following: feeling of discomfort, rational myth, intervention
and research, portraying a set of logics and change process.
Starting with this &lt;em&gt;feeling of discomfort&lt;/em&gt; with respect to the open
management issues identified, the researcher in an abductive fashion
starts generating hypothesis on raw data collected through open
interviews with a wide variety of actors across business units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The investigation is followed by the definition and gradual elaboration
of a &lt;em&gt;rational myth&lt;/em&gt;. This myth reflects as a potential model, and
reference to rely on to explain and coordinate collective action. As
exposed by Bachelard in his thesis &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Essai sur la connaissance
approchée&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; (Essay on approximated knowledge) (Bachelard

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Bachelard1927&#34;&gt;1927&lt;/a&gt;) to explain scientific knowledge development
and constructivist epistemology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The order of sensibilities does not necessarily follow the salient
features, what we could call the &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;dynamic
topography of our experience&lt;/span&gt;. We indeed have little agreement
with the simplification of the prior phenomenon of every scientific
development. We think the primordial features stand out by themselves
and establish themselves forcibly to our study through their
generality. Nevertheless, sometimes it is the accident and not the
general that is explanation principle to the point where problems
should be overturned to restore the generality to the phenomenal
features the spirit had represented in special meaning.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should not be mistaken for serendipitous discoveries but his work
stresses the importance of experimentation, seen as the &lt;em&gt;contact between
Thought and Reality&lt;/em&gt; which is the only way of specifying the mode of
existence. The knowledge is thus approximated by a movement of
conjunction from Thought to Reality, which are supported by means of
&lt;em&gt;intervention and interaction&lt;/em&gt;. The gradual and often non-linear shaping
of knowledge allows the researcher to &lt;em&gt;portray a set of logics&lt;/em&gt;. Up to
this phasing, the purpose of the researcher is mainly to explain and
bring to the surface the rationality mobilized in the collective action.
In that regard, we adopt an &lt;em&gt;ordinary&lt;/em&gt; perspective of rationality
(Boudon 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Boudon2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;). We avoid the potential patchwork and
associated burst of the notion of rationality, and stunning relativism
that social sciences can sometimes produce. Of course, we cannot pretend
to discard existing theories that explain collective action through
according to different research programs (Lakatos

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Lakatos1980&#34;&gt;1980&lt;/a&gt;): utility, materiality, mechanistic or
cognitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methodological individualism required to reveal the &lt;em&gt;set of logics&lt;/em&gt;,
and &lt;em&gt;rational myth&lt;/em&gt;, tends to adopt a cognitive approach to understand
social phenomena which are the implications of the individual actions
inspired by reasons. It is a means of avoiding pitfalls as explained by
R.Boudon (Boudon 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Boudon2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;): solipsism, psychologism,
procedural knowledge and programmatic approaches, dispositional
variables, restrictive axiomatic such as rational choice theory and
expressive rationality (Frega 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Frega2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;). So, we tend to
look for how these reasons are shaped within and without context. We
also identify the research program Max Weber’s proposition in his
treatise on the Sociology of Religion (Weber 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Weber1946&#34;&gt;1946&lt;/a&gt;,
280):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not ideas, but material and ideal interests directly govern men’s conduct. Yet very frequently the ‘world-images’ that have been created by ‘ideas’ have, like switchmen, determined the tracks along which action has been pushed by the dynamic of interest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher in his generative search will then test his evolving
understanding with the field through different &lt;em&gt;intervention and
interaction&lt;/em&gt; devices, acting as measuring devices and testing:
interviews, questions with given semantics, presentations of models,
steering committees, discussions with supervisors. And finally, there is
a need for predictability in the new understanding built by the
researcher which comes in the form of a &lt;em&gt;change process&lt;/em&gt;. This change
occurs mainly from the understanding of &lt;em&gt;Reality&lt;/em&gt; of the studied domain.
It does not necessarily imply the implementation of new management tool,
or rationality organizing collective action, but rather a learning
process due to the scientific understanding. We will come back to this
in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;#anomaly-detection-and-modelling&#34;&gt;following section&lt;/a&gt;,
as we propose a methodology of anomaly detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-collection&#34;&gt;Data collection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of data was collected in the group Zodiac Aerospace
through the variety of interactions with actors of the firm. Given the
nature of our research, a diverse sample of data type was sourced across
the research ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the beginning of the PhD journey until the end, a large sample of
resources: meeting minutes, presentations, TRL assessments,
technology/product roadmaps, project statements, project &amp;amp; program
documentation stored on local networks, intranet, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another set of data was gathered through active participation to
workshop, seminars, meetings where sometimes where the researcher was
invited for observation and we must add data collection with varying
degrees of intervention: writing workshops, working groups, interviews,
project meetings and seminars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anomaly-detection-and-modelling&#34;&gt;Anomaly detection and modelling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we will present in the following sections and following chapters
(
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/&#34;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/a&gt; ) we have a small-sample research contained in a large conglomerate of
SMEs. The different phases of IRM tend to overlap and provide feedback
between themselves. Overall, we have the three main categories of logics
interacting with each other(Dana and Dumez 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dana2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deduction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inference&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abduction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the sample size and in order to provide meaningful results for
academia and practice, demonstrating a case of anomaly is key from a
statistical standpoint (Siggelkow 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Siggelkow2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;). The
purpose is to carefully observe a counter-example to the models
extracted from literature (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/&#34;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt;),
then propose a new model explaining the phenomenon and extending
existing theories (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/&#34;&gt;Part 4&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, we present how we mobilize the idea of comprehensive
research (Dana and Dumez 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dana2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;; Dumez

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dumez2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;) to elicit counter-examples of existing models in
the literature and design a new one. There are three main risks
associated highlighted by the method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract actors or being of reasons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circularity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equifinality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three major risks will serve as a baseline to promote
counter-factual reasoning with the elucidated anomalies by putting the
effort on creating a typology, stress mechanisms between levels of
analysis through a set unit of analysis, and proposition of a new
concept redefining and extending existing theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;detecting-an-anomaly-in-management&#34;&gt;Detecting an anomaly in management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the movements of a comprehensive research (Dana and Dumez

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Dana2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;) can be seen as a modulation of deductive
research. The selected literature and associated models tell us what to
observe when scouting the research ground, with a risk of being trapped
with circularity. The first step consisted in analysing theoretical
frameworks relating to ambidexterity, exploration project management,
strategy management and organizational design/studies in face of the
unknown. It is also a way of rephrasing the elaboration of the &lt;em&gt;rational
myth&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;set of logics portrait&lt;/em&gt;. Based on the literature review (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;), we were able to select several of these frameworks which are key to identify a phenomenon unknown to academic literature in contrast with
the synthesised model of &lt;strong&gt;non-mutual conditioning of exploration/exploitation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis requires to extract typologies and mechanisms of phenomena
observed in the selected literature that shed light on the anomaly. The
descriptors are introduced to stress issues and limitations already
identified in the literature. It will also facilitate the
instrumentation to describe the purpose of our research questions, hence
the anomalies and their implications (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/&#34;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have selected the common descriptors: &lt;strong&gt;model of coordination and
collective action&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;innovation potential of attraction&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;generative
processes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;environment cognition&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;organization design&lt;/em&gt;). The
literature review aimed at stress testing major models of ambidexterity
in order to see that the construct had drifted overtime and locally
&lt;em&gt;delaminated&lt;/em&gt; as innovation management had evolve to embrace the unknown
specially with exploration project management. These were analysed with
inputs from design theories and reasoning embodying generative
processes. Several assumptions and limitations were identified with the
help of the descriptors as presented in the research questions (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter3/&#34;&gt;chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In a first &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/chapter6/&#34;&gt;chapter&lt;/a&gt;,
a first batch of results from selected case studies (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#associated-paper-writing&#34;&gt;table in following chapter&lt;/a&gt;)
will be presented revealing anomalies. This is based on the chosen
descriptors and synthesized version of the anomaly detection articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a second &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/chapter7/&#34;&gt;chapter&lt;/a&gt;,
we will then have to further specify these anomalies revealing in more
detail the limitations and underlying assumptions found in the
literature review (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter3/&#34;&gt;research questions&lt;/a&gt;). Finally, the anomaly
detection should lay the requirements to build up a new model revisiting
and extending literature models in order to explain the abnormal
phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-analysis&#34;&gt;Data analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must mobilize a unit of analysis that opposes inference and abductive
logics. The first calls for explanations, typologies and mechanisms the
selected literature will allow us to observe. The second is more
independent from the literature and tends to extract what the research
ground can &amp;ldquo;tell us&amp;rdquo; through the variations observations and
interactions/interventions. The two are far from being independent in
practice, there is a constant confrontation bore by the researcher
himself echoing a declination of the Hawthorne Effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two different sets of data allow us to confront the two logics
separately over the collected documentation and the variety of field
notes (interviews, meetings and workshops participation). The unit of
analysis is crucial to elicit the articulation between the levels of
analysis (from the individual to the organization/ecosystem) and
associated mechanisms evolving through the timeline of the case studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we would tend to have a ‘&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mesoscopic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;’ approach as the typologies
drawn from the literature review, in association with event-system
theory invite us to play on different levels and temporalities (Griffin

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Griffin1993&#34;&gt;1993&lt;/a&gt;; Griffin and Ragin 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Griffin1994&#34;&gt;1994&lt;/a&gt;;
Morgeson, Mitchell, and Liu 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Morgeson2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;). The other
benefit is that it forces the researcher to disentangle black-boxes that
may have been contoured in the literature such as &lt;em&gt;abstract actors&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;beings of reason&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose then to explicit the selected descriptors (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter3/&#34;&gt;chapter 3&lt;/a&gt; over time as the decision-making and action is engaged by actors
(designers, engineers, managers, etc.), within projects and within
committees. We then suggest to look at the time-sequence of the
following derived descriptors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;decision/problem space design&lt;/strong&gt;: decision and problem formulation
is extracted from documentation and conducted interviews for the
different surveyed selected projects. The input from design theory
from a methodological standpoint also helps to envision a large
decision/problem space which was discussed with interviewees (as the
possible course of action).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;actual made decisions&lt;/strong&gt;: recorded from project history,
documentation and interviews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;engaged course of action&lt;/strong&gt;: recorded from project history,
documentation and interviews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;organization design&lt;/strong&gt;: supporting (temporary) organizations were
found in project documentations and interviews and also directly
observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, if we propose to represent a project management for a
standardized product development, the descriptors allow us to show the
linear and supposed stability that is adapted through risk management
procedures. The figure
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:refdescriptors&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:refdescriptors&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;
below gives an idea of how this would be done.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-derived-descriptors-representation-for-a-emtraditionalem-development-project&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/refdescriptors.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Derived descriptors representation for a traditional development project&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/refdescriptors.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Derived descriptors representation for a &lt;em&gt;traditional&lt;/em&gt; development project
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This analytical lens remains very useful to draw the project trajectory,
its coordination mechanisms and collective action. However, we must
stress that it may also become chaotic as real life management, and
interaction with the environment and organizations is not without
obstacles. So we must highlight these obstacles and specify what the
literature models of &lt;strong&gt;non-mutual conditioning between exploration and
exploitation&lt;/strong&gt; would have predicted compared to the actual course action
depicted with our descriptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; In order to specify and make sense of these obstacles,
numerous control variables can of course be added as we have discussed
in the literature review to counter contingencies and concomitant
phenomena. Adding them may raise model’s fitness with data but not
necessarily up to a point of reaching perfect congruence from a
statistical viewpoint. Consequently, we will address some of common
control variables and clarify how influential they could have been or
not in order to make a case for the anomaly as easily as possible.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modelling-naming-explaining-and-testing&#34;&gt;Modelling: Naming, explaining and testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the anomaly detection encourages the researcher to formalize a
new model mitigating some perspectives addressed by the research
questions and the observed phenomena. The novelty invites &lt;em&gt;naming&lt;/em&gt; the
phenomenon based on traces left by academics or practitioners to weave a
model from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new model is introduced in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/&#34;&gt;Part 4&lt;/a&gt;,
it should be &lt;em&gt;free-standing&lt;/em&gt;: plausible on its own due to the showcased
logics of the conceptual argument (Siggelkow 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Siggelkow2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;,
21). Despite being backed by the cases, it also requires elevating the
model from the idiosyncrasy of the cases themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our model will support a novel explanation of the anomalies presented in
the chapters 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter8/&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;
and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter9/&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;
in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/&#34;&gt;Part 4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The validity of the model is presented in chapter [10]https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/chapter10/)
and in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/&#34;&gt;Part 5&lt;/a&gt;
through the different ways in which the researcher intervened in the
research ground: contributions to projects and management procedures.
For IRM phasing, it corresponds to the establishment of a new &lt;em&gt;rational
myth&lt;/em&gt; proposing a new way of organizing collective action. The support
and reaction to this experimentation is detailed in the two chapters
where the model was experimented and validated by peers. Moreover, this
experimentation of the model validates the status of the model as a
building block providing an understanding of complex mechanisms, laying
a path along the research questions perspectives for a future theory
with exploratory hypotheses in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part6/&#34;&gt;Part 6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we have specified the different descriptors to detect the potential
anomalies, we need to be able to compare models derived from literature
with the case studies. We propose then in the following paragraphs the
adaptive, interactive and encapsulated models. They represent different
models of ambidexterity as we have seen throughout our literature review
along the chosen descriptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;adaptive model&lt;/strong&gt; is mainly concerned with responding to the
environment by organizing the firm in a way that it is a priori capable
to answer to potential changes. The generative processes such as radical
innovation are then structured by the organization design and
environment cognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;interactive model&lt;/strong&gt; tends to deepen the contingencies of
generative processes by stressing the importance of relationships,
emergent new ones so that new routines can be recombined through the
open-ended network dynamics. The organization design are shaped to the
complexity of relationships tied through generative interactions.
The &lt;strong&gt;encapsulated model&lt;/strong&gt; brings a more ‘organic’ view by framing
generativity with the scope of a project supported by a temporary
organization also tied functionally to resource-providing organizations.
The change dynamics of the (temporary) organization are the mirror’s
image of the net of projects engaged with the environment and program
office/governance’s strategic input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;adaptive-model-coping-with-the-environments-dynamics&#34;&gt;Adaptive model: coping with the environment’s dynamics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the adaptive model, what is critical is the way in which the adaptive
process rooted in problem-solving, and by-extension decision-making
(probabilities on solutions), moved from organizational learning with a
concern for exploration and exploitation regime to being a key construct
to think the firm’s innovation performance in addition to having
competitive advantage. Mutations of the organization structure and
process are the answer to environment changes. Variation and selection
should be then managed to ensure an efficient exploration.
The other salient feature is that it tends to prescribe organization
design with different level of analysis that should be the
responsibility of top management as they are considered among the few to
bring system thinking and thus conduct strategy. The underlying
foundations such as decision-making and dynamic capabilities building
remain quite obscure (Birkinshaw and Gupta 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;)
and may lead to complicated managerial action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; Generative processes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; Environment cognition&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;Organization design&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Top management and leadership are the corner stone shaping the adaptive processes supporting innovation management. They oversee organizational learning and relationships balancing exploration and exploitation. Selection, valuation and strategic decision-making is their responsibility.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Generativity is supported by search-based processes to discover missing alternatives hidden by bounded rationality. Foolishness or simple landscape searching can uncover unbounded rational alternatives. The overall product development process tends to be by-product of the ambidextrous organization.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The environment offers the alternatives to the decision-maker and seeker. High levels of flexibility and capabilities are required to respond quickly enough to changes. Search-based behaviour help to prepare and build up capabilities to cope with the environment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The firm should balance its organization structurally, sequentially or contextually (different levels of the system) to support exploration and exploitation regimes. Ambidextrous organizations are the norm, and the careful balance is chosen depending on the environment dynamics observability.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;interactive-model-enabling-an-ecology-of-generativity&#34;&gt;Interactive model: enabling an ecology of generativity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactive model approaches the issue in a far more contingent way.
The circulation of concepts and interactions with artefacts contribute
to the exploration regime and simultaneously to the exploitation effort
as stakeholders take part in the process. The decision-making has a
tendency to be left on the back seat, as the engaging action with others
will allow addressing uncertainties and the unknown. Yet, organizing
open innovation, or freeing innovation raises the question of problem
formulation and deciding of its decomposition in the network of
interactions.
The organization boundaries can be easily blurred by the numerous
engagement of agents and artefacts with the environment. It naturally
reveals numerous question on the governance, if not control, of such
fractal organizations as the identity and purpose of the products being
developed could bring heterogeneity and incoherence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; Generative processes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; Environment cognition&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;Organization design&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Middle management and individuals (designers and silent designers) bear the interactions. Spaces, occasions and artefacts should be designed. Top management may be involved to shape networks and relationships. Decision-making and problem framing may be required to be decomposed and distributed by top management.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Interactions between agents and artefacts support circulation of meaning, create and manage value. Metaphors, desirable concepts are used to drive coordination and cohesion for radical innovation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Flexibility is supported by the network and favours open innovation to reach out for new design requirements. Reaching out for the full value chain and extending it to user-designers allows shaping future environments. It is a means to formulate and solve problems.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Network and distributed design. Open/close boundaries on multiple fronts, potentially fractal. Organization tends to be a by-product of the product development processes in the network.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;encapsulated-model-challenging-organization-design-and-learning&#34;&gt;Encapsulated model: challenging organization design and learning&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The encapsulation of generative process into projects and the management
of a portfolio with a program elevate the interactive perspective by
putting the emphasis on strategic management, an enclose collective
action, as well as a potential issue of governance and temporary
organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The temporary organization supporting the project-based management also
relies on functional departments providing key resources and knowledge
management. The organizational learning and organization ties of
projects floating across these organizations can induce difficulties
that encourage to think of change management with the scope of a given
project, instead of a separate activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model of coordination and collective action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; Generative processes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; Environment cognition&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation potential of attraction&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;Organization design&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project management and/or program management lead innovation. Project management office preserves project management rules. Program governance may frame projects with a roadmap and other strategic management input.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Practices, methods are embedded in project/program. Resources are drawn and requested depending on novelty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Perception and action engaged locally, at project level and with possible oversight from program governance. Learning between projects is key to build awareness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Projects shape temporary organizations relying on functional departments. The boundaries move according to environment interactions and may be governed by program management and office. Temporary organization tends to be a by-product of the product development processes supported by the portfolio of projects.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-journey&#34;&gt;Research Journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, we present the research journey over the three years
corresponding to the IRM phasing and its modalities. The researcher took
part in several Steering Committees with the firm and PhD directors, as
well as numerous Academic confrontations which have participated to the
evolution of perception of literature frameworks and gradual
specification of a new &lt;em&gt;rational myth&lt;/em&gt;. The figure below gives a global
picture of the journey over several dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-research-journey&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/researchjourney.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Research journey&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/researchjourney.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Research journey
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;steering-committees&#34;&gt;Steering committees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to elaborate the different phases of IRM, several steering
committees were organized on a quarterly basis with the academic and
industrial supervisors, in addition to weekly interactions with both
separately.
The first set of meetings gave a frame for an open discussion
(&lt;em&gt;isonomy&lt;/em&gt;) around a proposed model of action, framework projected over
the data collected on several case studies. Presentations and
discussions allowed testing hypothesis, different narratives, and
semantics taken from literature models. Two major meetings were
organized with the CTO, R&amp;amp;T, engineering and business development
managers, in addition to PhD Directors. Otherwise 10 other steering
committees were held with the CTO and PhD supervisors to keep track of
the &lt;em&gt;open management issue&lt;/em&gt;.
The second set of meetings were perhaps less formal as the challenge was
to update PhD supervisors as frequently as possible on the collected
data and analysis made. In a more personal way, it was the occasion for
the research to test extreme hypothesis or simple extrapolations in
order to explore the boundaries of the domain of the models taken from
the literature or grounded in the data. Practically, it implied testing
narratives, semantics from different literature streams to test how the
supervisors would project themselves in the understanding built by the
researcher. It is a dual learning process for both sides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;academic-confrontations&#34;&gt;Academic confrontations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research had the occasion to participate to a range of academic
activities: thesis presentation at the laboratory, presentation for the
annual PhD candidates meetings of the CNRS research unit (UMR 9237),
presentation at seminars, conferences and journal submissions with peer
reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;PhD year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Lab presentations&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;February 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;First case studies results&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;April 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design Thinking and design theory case studies&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;June 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;First year Thesis status&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;September 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Literature review on decision-theory/making&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;March - May 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 Thesis presentations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;PhD year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Seminar presentations&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First year&lt;/strong&gt;- &lt;em&gt;February 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Travail et créativité : une approche croisée à l’international” organised by Yanita Andonova &amp;amp; Emmanuel Sevignac&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;April 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thesis Presentation Chalmers University&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;March 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thesis presentation PhD Seminar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;June 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;EURAM PhD Colloquium&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;PhD year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Conferences presentation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;October 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6th CIM Community Workshop&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;January 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10th SIG Design Theory Conference&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;August 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ICED Conference&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;June 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;EURAM Conference&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third year&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;July 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&amp;amp;D Management Conference&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the three years, the researcher engaged discussions with several
researchers to learn more from their publications and research
interests. It was the occasion to present the research project, results
of case studies and trying to find echoes with their works. The table
below offers an overview in a chronological order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;table:academic_interactions&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;table style=&#34;width:97%;&#34;&gt;
&lt;caption&gt;Academic interactions - Discussions with researchers&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col style=&#34;width: 48%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;col style=&#34;width: 48%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Pierre Couronne&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Former Professor at &lt;em&gt;Université de Lille 3&lt;/em&gt; and at &lt;em&gt;ISAE SUPAERO-Toulouse&lt;/em&gt;, we had several discussions on the nature of design engineering and its contribution to management. His concern regarding the PhD project was seen from the angle of human resources and organization theory. His input was very helpful during the first months when trying to make sense and preliminary assumptions on the first cases analysed at ZA.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Gilles Garrel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Professor of Management at &lt;em&gt;Conservatoire Natinal des Arts et Métiers (CNAM)&lt;/em&gt; - we had a first open exchange and shared a course together for the MSC in Entrepreneurship organized by &lt;em&gt;Ecole Polytechnique&lt;/em&gt; on bio-technologies. The purpose of this exchange was to share some insights on Zodiac Aerospace cases. He shed light with perspectives on project management and strategic management. He shared some experience on cases and ongoing research in creative (game and circus) and sport equipment industries.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Lisa Carlgren&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Post-doc at &lt;em&gt;Chalmers University&lt;/em&gt; - I had the occasion to review her EURAM 2016 submission, so we took time after the conference to discuss her research. Several insights on Design Thinking and its relationship to organization routines and strategic management were discussed. The discussion helped clarify the multiple impacts of design thinking (method) and design reasoning in general and the relative issues of framing &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;Carlgren2016a&#34;&gt;(Carlgren, Rauth, and Elmquist &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Carlgren2016a&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Georg Von Krogh&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Professor of Management at &lt;em&gt;ETH Zürich&lt;/em&gt; - Discussion on the nature of need-solution pairs &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;VonHippel2016&#34;&gt;(Hippel and Krogh &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-VonHippel2016&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; and the managerial action required to identify them and sustain an ecology of creativity. He suggested the reading of the edited books of Mark Runco and referring also the works of Robert Epstein.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Emmanuel Marcon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Professor of Management and Business Intelligence at &lt;em&gt;IAE Poitiers&lt;/em&gt; - The exchange occurred following a PhD seminar on business intelligence organized by PSL University. Given his research and interactionist approaches on information gathering and processing, we had some debate on decision-making and its limitations. He encouraged the reading of &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;Oury1983&#34;&gt;(Oury and Schmidt &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Oury1983&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;1983&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; on the place of &#34;vigilance&#34; in economics. It allowed feeding a new approach to the paper submitted at ICED 2017 by insisting on the economy of project management and decision-making.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Laurent Simon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Professor of Management at &lt;em&gt;HEC Montréal&lt;/em&gt; - Short meeting arranged during a visit to Montreal following ICED in Vancouver. After presenting the research conducted at ZA, he presented his research at Ubisoft &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;Cohendet2016 Simon2006&#34;&gt;(Cohendet and Simon &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Cohendet2016&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;; Simon &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Simon2006&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;. Whilst keeping a concern for organization routines, he gave reasons to work on how concepts are ‘forked’ during design processes (traceable through in C-K but not necessarily explained in detail) and these emergent micro-decisions are managed collectively. His concern echoed the criticality of linking design theory and management with organization theory, which we have addressed in the literature review.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Marine Agogué&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Assistant Professor of Management at &lt;em&gt;HEC Montréal&lt;/em&gt; - Short meeting arranged during a visit to Montreal following ICED in Vancouver. The discussion pointed out the design of decisions, and how the decision theory and design theory could be experimented in laboratory environment, or at least tracked in project management.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Florence Charue-Duboc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor of Management at &lt;em&gt;CRG-Ecole Polytechnique&lt;/em&gt; - Several critical comments were made during my PhD status presentation, at &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; 2nd year PhD Seminar (May 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It marks a key turning poing in the thesis&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, the purpose of the presentation was to try to show the anomaly. The presentation went awfully bad, but I took it as a weakness for not having the appropriate descriptors. As the notion organizational ambidexterity was discussed, the presentation was criticized for not nuancing enough the dichotomy between exploration/exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Laure Cabantous&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Professor of Management at &lt;em&gt;CASS Business School, University of London&lt;/em&gt; - The researcher was consulted for her work on decision-making with Alberto Feduzi &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;Feduzi2016&#34;&gt;(Feduzi et al. &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Feduzi2016&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;. She raised interest in the cases in the decision-making practices of ZA and encouraged having a closer look at strategy-as-practice stream of research and legitimation with the firm.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Katharina Hölzle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Professor of Management at &lt;em&gt;University of Potsdam - d.school&lt;/em&gt; at editor for CIM Journal - Following the CIM Community Workshop in Potsdam (November 2016) and gathered feedback, a submission was made to the CIM Journal. A first round of reviews pointed at several weaknesses of the submitted article including the multi-level analysis. Several months later, during a visit to Mines ParisTech, we took some time to discuss the paper. Misunderstandings were cleared out and together with Sophie Hooge, we had time to elaborate on the use of design theory and reasoning (practice and methodology) to understand the build up of dynamic capabilities sustaining innovation management in addition to conduct management research.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Sophie Hooge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Assistant Professor - On several occasions, we had the opportunity to discuss the shades of ambidexterity and how ZA cases proved new practice requiring management tools and support. Her knowledge of the car industry was used as a reference to explicit how different the aircraft industry is, and the features brought by my research compared to literature on exploration project management and radical innovation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Cédric Dalmasso&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Assistant Professor - During the last 6 months of the PhD, he was referred to for two articles co-authored on ambidexterity &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;Garcias2015&#34;&gt;(Garcias, Dalmasso, and Sardas &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Garcias2015&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; and high uncertainty project management &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;Hooge2015&#34;&gt;(Hooge and Dalmasso &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Hooge2015&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;. Not being so engaged with design theory and reasoning as other researchers in the lab, but more familiar with decision-making, project management and organization studies, his feedback was very helpful in clarifying my narrative.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Philippe Lefebvre&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Assistant Professor - His courses on organization design and organization studies, and his research on engineering departments, were enlightening to test the anomaly detection and the models revising decision-making and organization design.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Pierre-Henri Wuillemin&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Assistant Professor at &lt;em&gt;LIP6, Université Pierre &amp;amp; Marie Curie&lt;/em&gt; - When surveying literature on decision theory, a theoretical graph model (pyAgrum) was found to simulate decision problems. A meeting was set to discuss how the developed Python code could be extended to designing decisions, or at least simulating the effect of surprises. The main output was that the nature the probabilities and underlying algebra should be revisited to properly simulate such behaviour unless sticking multi-variate decision-making.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Matthias Troffaes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Associate Professor at &lt;em&gt;Durham University&lt;/em&gt; - Another Python model was found in the field of imprecise probabilities (Improb), thus opening an opportunity to model the design of alternatives and states of nature. However, again the model proved insufficient to model the design by a decision-maker.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Anaëlle Camarda &amp;amp; Mathieu Cassotti&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Post-doc at &lt;em&gt;Université Paris Descartes&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CGS Mines ParisTech&lt;/em&gt;; Professor at &lt;em&gt;LaPsyDé, Université Paris Descartes&lt;/em&gt; - Following discussion with Marine Agogué, the idea of combining the experimental protocols of decision-making and creativity was discussed but reveals numerous obstacles as they have epistemic differences. It remains an open topic.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evolution-of-the-rational-myth-contributors&#34;&gt;Evolution of the &lt;em&gt;rational myth&lt;/em&gt; contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this subsection, we propose to cover the literature journey of the
researcher. We briefly present how the modelling effort came around over
which literature was mobilized, in addition which articles were
presented at conferences and sent to journals. The elaboration of the
&lt;em&gt;rational myth&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;set of logics portrait&lt;/em&gt; is not a linear process. So
the following paragraphs are an &lt;em&gt;ex-post&lt;/em&gt; viewpoint of the PhD journey.
We have taken the liberty to make three categories for which articles
were written and presentations made on various occasions to test
literature models on case studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the reader will see, they do not follow the literature review
chapters 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter1/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter2/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;,
instead they follow the PhD candidate through the three years and how he
tested several frameworks to engage with academia. The researcher made a
first effort regarding the literature around the construct of
&amp;ldquo;decision-making&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;design thinking&amp;rdquo; before going into the field
&amp;ldquo;organizational ambidexterity&amp;rdquo; and ramifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;decision-making&#34;&gt;Decision-making&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the case study at ZSSM, we had the opportunity to study the
decision theories in order to explain the project management. Data was
presented in a way that it encouraged the decision-making study: the
story was told as sequences of events with commitment to decisions,
beliefs and their representation in several documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;rational-theories-of-choice&#34;&gt;Rational theories of choice&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we will see later, we proposed to test the validity of rational
models of choice, where rationality is seen as instrumental(Boudon

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Boudon2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;). Large reviews of decision theories were
executed: from the ones based on &lt;em&gt;maximum expected utility&lt;/em&gt; to
modulations made between the 1950s to early 1990s with models discussing
the underlying axiomatic and formulation mathematics. The works of
Allais, Kahnmenan, Tversky, Machina, Camerer, Giocolli, Quiggin,
G.Klein, Slovic, Regenwetter and Gilboa were paramount in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debates on rationality, coherence between decision, beliefs and action
were covered to understand how the construct of decision-making was
considered in different literature domains ranging from economics,
management to philosophy. It was also the occasion to make a detour
through mathematics with decision models using multi-criteria approaches
and imprecise probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;irrationality-in-decision-making&#34;&gt;Irrationality in decision-making&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of not being able to expect, changing the notion of utility
to deal with the way decisions are made, led the researcher to dive into
the way what makes irrationality and how the decisions are constructed.
So the perspective of ex-post construction of decision to justify the
course of action, and deviance according instrumental rationality was
addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, as we were looking to bridge a gap with design theories, considered
as a change of paradigm, we were looking for ways in which rationality
could be preserved and still extend decision-making with design theories
without falling in the trap of leaving model-out-of-domain phenomena to
dispositional variables such as irrationality or constructs determined
by ad-hoc phenomena such as Bourdieu’s &lt;em&gt;habitus&lt;/em&gt;. One could refer to the
books of Christophe Morel on absurd decisions, and the works Nils
Brunson for their perspective on irrationality and absurdity. However,
the researcher was more inspired by the works of Richard Bronk on the
importance of imagination and creativity in markets (Bronk

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Bronk2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;) as a means to propose extensions and deep
revisions of outdated models of Thought explaining Reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    The last two paragraph led to an article presented at the International
Conference on Engineering Design (Le Glatin, Le Masson, and Weil
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017&#34;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt;) and to a parallel
submission to CERN IdeaSquare Journal of Experimental Innovation (Le
Glatin, Le Masson, and Weil
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34;&gt;b&lt;/a&gt;) (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-leglatin2017a/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;).
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;strategy-management-and-politics-of-decision-making&#34;&gt;Strategy management and politics of decision-making&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, studying the role of strategy-making, strategy-as-practice,
encouraged the researcher to find ways of formalizing decisions in a
different way. The works of Crozier, Fredberg, Pettigrew, Sfez were key
to test other frameworks were the role-playing is mobilized. The
researcher discussed with Laurent Simon, who referred also to Laure
Cabantous for further debates on decision-making and emergent
strategies. The difficulty for the researcher was to make sense of the
observations. Some of decisions taken were not coherent with the course
of action or beliefs. Violations of rationality axiomatic could be
highlighted but as the outcomes were mitigated and questioned utility
and performance, a different model was to be found to add details to
known phenomena or substantiate anomalies in a novel model. A turning
point was reached with a detour through the literature of routines and
organizational ambidexterity. Indeed, stimulating papers with a
sociological perspective written by Fanny Simon and Albéric Tellier with
the &lt;em&gt;event system theory&lt;/em&gt; of Frederick Morgeson and &lt;em&gt;event-structure
analysis&lt;/em&gt; of Larry Griffin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;design-thinking&#34;&gt;Design Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As two case studies were based on the use of Design Thinking (DT)
methodology, in-depth literature review was conducted to understand its
origins, evolution and complementarity with other design perspectives in
literature: design studies, design theories and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;design-thinking-in-organizations&#34;&gt;Design Thinking in organizations&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The place of a creativity methods, supporting the Fuzzy Front End and a
subsequent efficient NPD, has been largely studied in the past decades
starting with creative problem solving, brainstorming, and more recently
with Design Thinking methodology. Since it came through practice mainly,
several academics starting in d.schools (Stanford and Potsdam) but also
Swedish researcher centres, worked towards positioning DT with respect
to engineering, creativity and innovation management and organization
studies also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as design in general is usually seen as a confined activity
confined to engineering, or perhaps strategy, or even organizational
design, several barriers were faced when trying to framing and valuing
DT as part of an ecology of routines in the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;design-theory-and-engineering&#34;&gt;Design Theory and engineering&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of design theory, design science, and engineering,
reaching out for their impact of the organization was not a easy task.
But, as the field appeared more structured, it helped as reference to
position DT and try to reach out for organizational issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;design-oriented-organization&#34;&gt;Design-Oriented Organization&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the tradition of works of design theories and the importance of
management devices in organization, embracing post-Simonian paradigm,
the works of design-oriented organizations for innovative capabilities
(Andy Dong, Armand Hatchuel). They place design as a generalized
activity taking place at all levels of the organized, hence requiring to
be carefully managed to sustain firm’s regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This literature complements existing literature on dynamic capabilities
and organizing for radical innovation (O’Connor, Dougherty, Leonard) but
also the contributing organizational routines needed to support these:
knowledge management, valuation, power and legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The last three paragraph led to an article presented at 6th Creative
Innovation Management Community Workshop at University of Potsdam
d.school (Le Glatin, Le Masson, and Weil &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;). The
latter was adapted after having some input of several researchers for a
submission at Creative Innovation Management Journal. The paper had
taken different frameworks in the literature whilst trying to bridge the
difficulty to link design theory literature with organization, and catch
Design Thinking in between. The editorial along with the reviewer
highlighted several weaknesses of the paper and asked to resubmit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After several months of maturation, the researcher had the opportunity to
engage discussion with one of the editorial board members. Katharina
Hölzle insight was crucial and we realized we are addressing the same
issue despite the PhD candidate’s clumsy writing. Therefore, an extended
abstract had been submitted for the R&amp;amp;D Conference in Milano (2018), and
the re-writing of a full article for the conference (Le Glatin et al.
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;) but also for a clean resubmission to CIM
Journal (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-leglatin2018/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;organizational-ambidexterity&#34;&gt;Organizational ambidexterity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, in the same way that the duality between
market-pull and techno-push was first addressed by the research project,
the researcher inquired on the model of ambidexterity. The motivation
for such topic started when trying to formalize a portfolio of case
studies, and projects observed at the intra/inter-BU level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;organizational-perspective&#34;&gt;Organizational perspective&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These projects were hard to label in the organizations. The belonging
and having appropriate management tools appeared critical to
interviewees and attendees of the PhD steering committees. They
acknowledged that projects all along where not fully exploration nor
fully exploitation. Consequently, the researcher looked for literature
items that would touch upon this grey zone contributing to strategy and
competitive advantage. Luckily, in recent years (2013-2015), several
authors such as Tushmann, Birkinshaw, O’Reilly pointed towards the
necessity to study decision-making and managerial capabilities to better
understand the translation of ambidexterity at a micro-level, beyond top
management and environment perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;exploration-vsexploitation-of-routines&#34;&gt;Exploration vs. exploitation of routines&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since ambidexterity can be approached in two main different ways.
Besides the organizational one, the other stresses the nature of
routines and they should be coordinated in a global way for
organizational learning. In 1991, March’s proposes a more behavioural
approach by considering problem-solving, theories of choice,
evolutionary theory and information-processing. This echoes the
decision-making issues mentioned earlier with an &lt;em&gt;a priori&lt;/em&gt;
irrationality. The cases encouraged to conceptualize the possibility of
switching between modes, but also to find a middle ground avoiding the
dichotomy. In other words, a new kind of rationality where absurdities
and anomalies can be resolved, hence blurring the artificial separation
between exploration and exploitation or even forcing them to be over a
same continuum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;project-management&#34;&gt;Project Management&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, during the last stretch of the PhD journey, we reached out to
project management literature. Recent research on exploration project
management and the role of the unknown in such situation, have amended
the literature with new ways of addressing the tension between
exploration and exploitation. The works of Loch and Lenfle are now a
cornerstone in the field. Since the organizational studies were key for
the research, naturally we were drawn towards the role of matrix
organization, adhocracies, and more generally
temporary-based-organization in the field of project management. It was
a means to loop back with organizational design and by which means the
organization supports these projects: resources, routines and dynamic
capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To test the understanding of the literature and its limitations, the
researcher also engaged in a critical presentation during a PhD Seminar
(June 2017) encouraging to clearly position the analysis and explain how
the described phenomena differs from the literature models. It was a
turning point in the journey since it encouraged the understanding of
presented anomalies and design of a new model resolving them. The notion
of &lt;em&gt;decisional ambidexterity&lt;/em&gt; was clarified and extended also with the
contribution to European Management Review article (Le Masson et al.
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeMasson2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;) (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-lemasson2018/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, a full article was sent to EURAM 2018 Conference (Le
Glatin, Le Masson, and Weil &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-LeGlatin2018a&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;) (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-leglatin2018a/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;),
a synthesis for the Doctoral Colloquium was submitted. Finally, another
working paper will be submitted to future conferences (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/project/ambidexterity-exploration-exploitation/&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paper-writing-and-case-studies&#34;&gt;Paper writing and case studies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The several discussions, debates and literature reviews were key to
formalise reasoning into several papers. These are summarized and
reformulated here in the manuscript and can be extensively consulted in

&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt;. The associated case studies are briefly presented in the following chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous methodological sections, we have explained the intent to
demonstrate an anomaly. Three papers were written for this common
objective with different streams of literature. They are based on three
major cases representing the variety of innovation management. These are
presented in the first part of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#associated-paper-writing&#34;&gt;table&lt;/a&gt; in the followin chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a theoretical paper offers a model to reconcile with the anomaly.
Compared to published version (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/publication/pub-lemasson2018/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;,
we propose in this manuscript an extension that is then discussed in the
last paper of this thesis (see second part of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#associated-paper-writing&#34;&gt;table&lt;/a&gt; in following chapter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;role-and-position-of-the-researcher---intervention-research&#34;&gt;Role and position of the researcher - Intervention Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, we explain what were the activities and relations of
the researcher but also employee of the firm. We explain the mission of
the Innovation Direction and how the researcher took part in it. We also
cover daily activities, main drivers of integration with respect to the
management issue at stake in the research project, and peculiarities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;being-part-of-the-innovation-direction&#34;&gt;Being part of the Innovation Direction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Innovation Direction was created in 2013, following the creation of
the Zodiac Scientific and Technical Council (ZSTC) by Thierry
Rouge-Carrassat. He had been in charge of engineering departments and
the general management of business units. In parallel, several
discussions with the Group Human Resources benchmarked how Research &amp;amp;
Technology or Research &amp;amp; Development was organized. Among the surveys,
it was decided to establish an “Experts Career” program that would value
technical careers besides the traditional management one and the program
management (ZA-H-5003 Expert Technical Career Path Standard). This dual
ladder model (Allen and Katz 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Allen1986&#34;&gt;1986&lt;/a&gt;) was largely
inspired by the car equipment manufacturer Valéo. Thierry
Rouge-Carrassat had also previously established a dedicated R&amp;amp;T within
business unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEO, Olivier Zarrouati had decided to create a Group Technical &amp;amp;
Innovation Officer, and Thierry was offered the opportunity. With the
support of a consulting firm, management tools were introduced to offer
BUs means of managing the nascent dedicated R&amp;amp;T activity. Previously,
these were part of more traditional engineering activities designing
products for client demands, but induced high risk. A separate process
and structure was proposed to mitigate risks between an
upstream/exploratory set of activities compared to more
downstream/exploitative ones taking place in client programs (new
product development).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The management tools consisted in what is almost a standard for
aeronautics after having being one for the Department of Defence in the
United States of America: Technology Readiness Level and Technology Road
maps (Mankins 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Mankins2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;). Airbus and Boeing, in addition
to the institutions such as public funding schemes, certification
authorities have been in the past decades gradually introducing the
concept of technology readiness assessment in 9 levels. Some
discrepancies between scales can sometimes be observed such as Boeing’s
being longer one (see Boeing’s procedure PRO-5157 - Technology and
Application Readiness Criteria (Issue March 21, 2007)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Level&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Definition&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scientific research has resulted in the observation of basic principles for a given concept, these begin to be translated into more applied R&amp;amp;T.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Technologies are identified for a given concept, and more than one application/environment is identified. Still speculative, no experimental proof or detailed analysis to support the conjecture.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Applied research is initiated. Analytical studies to set the technologies into given environments, and lab based studies to physically validate predictions = proof-of-concept.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elements must be integrated to establish that the &amp;ldquo;pieces&amp;rdquo; will work together to achieve concept enabling levels of performance for the system. Low-fidelity, lab environment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fidelity of the elements being tested increases significantly. They must be integrated with reasonably realistic elements for testing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A major step in the level of fidelity of technology is demonstrated. A prototype is tested with the actual whole system application or only similar to the planned application but with the same technologies.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An actual system prototype demonstration is expected in a operational environment. The prototype should be near or at the scale of the planned operational system.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;True system development, and full integration.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The system is fully operational and in-service, it may included some final fixes if applicable.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mission-definition&#34;&gt;Mission definition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher arrived in late July 2015 in the newly created team: a
CTO delegate for the Americas from the start in early 2014, the Director
of Intellectual Property had been recruited in October 2014 and the
Director of R&amp;amp;T European funded programs in May 2015. An additional
member was delegated at the Institute for Technology Research in
Toulouse (&lt;em&gt;IRT Saint-Exupéry&lt;/em&gt;) in charge of the department of Electrical
Systems. In the following months, an experienced project manager would
be hired to take care of a national program for metal additive layer
manufacturing, joined by a PhD candidate based in an university
laboratory in Orléans (&lt;em&gt;Ecole Nationale Supérieure de Mécanique
Aéronautique&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team was rather young in the group except for the CTO and the one
based in Toulouse, we were then all discovering the intricacies of the
group. We would share a lot of information and thoughts on what we would
discover as we held meetings across business units.
In December 14, 2015, team’s mission was defined, despite all being
already being autonomous in their functions (project management, patent
management, funding and R&amp;amp;T management support):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead the development of a long term technological vision with
associated tools &amp;amp; processes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manage efficiently the expertise and IP, develop relevant internal &amp;amp;
external partnerships and secure funding to ensure a sustainable
road map&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead the development of a long term technological vision with an
associated sustainable road map&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manage efficiently the expertise and IP, develop relevant internal &amp;amp;
external partnerships and secure funding by applying required tools
&amp;amp; processes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;phd-candidate-in-innovation-management-position&#34;&gt;PhD Candidate in Innovation Management position&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher would report to the CTO as he would potentially benefit
from the feedback from field work, analyses and model creation and
testing. Bi-weekly meetings were organized to keep track of what the
researcher was conducting, and potentially answer to his questions and
test hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On several occasions, the PhD Candidate took some of the CTO’s tasks.
These were quite varied but all served the research project in some way
or another. The table offers a glimpse of the different activities (see below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Activities&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRL procedure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;October-January 2016&lt;/em&gt; - Support Zodiac Seats France to implement the TRL assessment procedure and the management of technology handover between R&amp;amp;T and Development Engineering activities. Appropriation of the definitions given in the existing group procedures was mandatory and required further details and adaption to the local engineering context. The several workshop days organized for the R&amp;amp;T and Development Engineering departments helped the identification of a case study. Frequent discussion with managers for innovation management related issues, led to providing a training session on Innovative Design methods.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ZAOS Program Management&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;March-July 2016&lt;/em&gt; - Within the Zodiac Aerospace Operation System launched in 2016 as part of the Quality Management system. It established a common baseline for all business units to support program management activities. Several workshops were held by Operational Excellence team and the researcher contributed to stressing the link with R&amp;amp;T activities. It was also the occasion to get to know several other program managers and directors from across the firm and gain familiarity with the program management activities&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Strategy Management Review&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;June 2016&lt;/em&gt; - A review for the Cabin Branch on Technology and Product Roadmap was scheduled and the researcher represented the CTO to collect feedback on ongoing projects and communicate messages from the CTO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ZAOS Develop &amp;amp; Sustain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;November 2016 - March 2017&lt;/em&gt; - In the same way to the Program Management process, the parallel and supporting process of Developing and Sustaining products and services was defined. A baseline was created for all BUs and the researcher took the responsibility during workshops to synthesize, challenge and write the “Design &amp;amp; Develop” process. It was a key turning point to be fully comfortable with the processes and BU practices. The experience contributed to clarify the understanding of the decision-making process and &lt;em&gt;rational myth&lt;/em&gt; for development engineering activities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CORAC meetings&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;November 2017 - February 2018&lt;/em&gt; - For a topic related to connectivity and aircraft operations, the Council for Research in Civil Aviation (&lt;em&gt;Conseil pour la Recherche en Aviation Civile&lt;/em&gt;), the CTO invited the researcher to follow-up on these meetings where the main French aeronautical firms propose projects contributing to the given topics. Besides representing one of the only company relevant for aircraft cabin equipment, the content of the meetings largely contributing to the understanding of how firms showcase their strategy and perception of innovation in their ecosystem.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ZAOS Innovate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;November 2017 - April 2018&lt;/em&gt; - In a similar way to Program Management and Develop &amp;amp; Sustain processes, a new set of procedures were defined to fit the ZAOS framework. The researcher took the lead of the activities dedicated to technology roadmaps and innovation management, to propose extensions of earlier versions of procedures based on the case studies analyses and research journey.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&amp;amp;T Managers meeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A colleague of Zodiac Interconnect Europe launched a series of meeting dedicated to share practices, issues and knowledge on technology domains for R&amp;amp;T managers based in France. The researcher participated to these meetings to discuss their topics, present and test hypotheses built during the last year of the PhD journey.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-steps-and-gaining-autonomy&#34;&gt;First steps and gaining autonomy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From August to November 2015, the time was dedicated to gain
acquaintance with several business units, understand the purpose of the
Technical and Innovation Direction, as well as try to reveal potential
&lt;em&gt;open management issues&lt;/em&gt; for case studies supporting the research
project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;being-introduced-by-the-cto&#34;&gt;Being introduced by the CTO&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first month was fully dedicated to open discussions with several
managers (engineering, marketing, sales), technical experts and project
managers part of the middle management of BUs across the group. Meetings
were held in the corporate headquarters in Plaisir where several BU
representatives have offices, as well as several other
video-conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CTO had sent an email introducing the researcher’s PhD project to
the ZSTC community, as well as key experts and managers who have a
rather dense network within their business unit or across others. In
total, 15 employees were consulted. Not all of them contributed equally
to data collection. They were from 8 different business units all from
middle management and Direction committees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher received a warm welcome from all interviewees who were
curious in finding what he could bring to their daily concerns. As these
first meetings were quite open, the setting was about having them tell
stories about their work, their projects, difficulties, good practices
and general management topics. They were in a favourable setting to
disclose valuable signals feeding a &lt;em&gt;feeling of discomfort&lt;/em&gt; guiding the
&lt;em&gt;rational myth&lt;/em&gt; sensing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;first-intervention-trl-assessment-tool&#34;&gt;First intervention: TRL assessment tool&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researcher was gradually being identified, recognized in the R&amp;amp;T
community, the R&amp;amp;T Manager of Zodiac Seats France (ZSFR) reached out for
support on the implementation of the TRL assessment, before
reconsidering the TRM structuring. The request originated from a demand
of funding scheme who steers carefully the progress of portfolio of
projects. TRL targets had been given and several debates occurred on the
understanding of their definitions, so they needed support on providing
accuracy to definition baseline given in the ZA procedure and justify
the TRL assessment through a proper tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four workshops were organized with the support and input of the CTO for
the first meetings. The researcher had benchmarked several business
units beforehand following the round of open interviews, and other
aeronautical firms for examples of TRL assessment use. Based on the
latter, a draft created by the researcher served as a basis for
discussions with R&amp;amp;T stakeholders at ZSFR to propose an update TRL
assessment tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A by-product of this intervention, a new ZA procedure was re-issued to
share the updated baseline definition with detailed tool to support
other BUs. The TRL was seen as an evaluation and not necessarily
associated with gates to be passed. Such perspective fed many debates on
the maturity assessment of systems or designs since technologies would
be integrated in a given product at some point. Thus, it also encouraged
the revision of the complementary procedure on &lt;em&gt;Technology Roadmap
definition, creation and sustaining&lt;/em&gt; and its articulation with Product
Roadmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, the relationship established with the business unit led to
the identification of a case study on the engineering of a modular
platform for business class seat (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#business-class-seat-platform&#34;&gt;case description&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;master-courses-for-literature-frameworks&#34;&gt;Master courses for literature frameworks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In parallel to the Zodiac Aerospace integration, during the months of
September-October, several courses were taken in the Design Engineering
curriculum of Mines ParisTech organized by the chair of Design Theory
and Methods for Innovation to confirm learnings on design theories,
innovation management, epistemology of management sciences and
organization studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These courses were taken in the perspective of gaining robustness over
certain topics related to the &lt;em&gt;feeling of discomfort&lt;/em&gt; originated from
the open management issues faced during the first set of open
interviews. It was also a means of trying different &lt;em&gt;set of logics
portraits&lt;/em&gt; to explain first batch of observations and further
observations through &lt;em&gt;intervention and interaction&lt;/em&gt; in the form of case
studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;surveying-bus-for-topics&#34;&gt;Surveying BUs for topics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As explained briefly, a first intervention was the opportunity to
identify a first case study at Zodiac Seats France on the engineering
design of a modular platform of business class seat. The rest of case
studies were mostly identified following the first interviews and
validation with the CTO. He played an important role in challenging the
interest of the case studies and serve as liaison with the managers at
stake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, the case identified at Zodiac Sensing and Systems
Management (ZSSM, former Intertechnique, and now called Zodiac Fuel and
Control Systems) came around as the CTO proposed to study a case of a
technology developed from scratch, above TRL6 and about to be integrated
in a Boeing aircraft program. The intent was to study a case of success
despite numerous difficulties along the way. A first interview was set
with the R&amp;amp;T Manager. The history of the project was told, but the
narrative did not reflect anything special besides collaboration issues
with Boeing and unfavourable conjecture due to commercial litigation
concerning other ZA business units. However, the manager had mentioned
another potential case study he quickly presented. The researcher looked
for feedback from the CTO and concurred to the idea that this other case
would perhaps reveal more stimulating management issues than the bumpy
road of the other project’s trajectory. Another interview was set to dig
deeper and try to grasp the manager’s motivation (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#icing-conditions-detection&#34;&gt;case description&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another case, the CTO introduced the researcher to the Airbus
Development Team for on-going projects and invited him to several other
meetings held by the Executive Committee to follow up on the concepts,
projects and several debates related to the activity domain and
associated innovation management issues (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#airbus-development-team---design-thinking-cases&#34;&gt;case description&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regular attendance to Executive Committee meetings for strategic
technologies and product/service concepts (see case description of

&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#multi-bu-committee&#34;&gt;Multi-BU meetings&lt;/a&gt;) also led to the acquaintance of other managers who
had a deep interest in understanding the performance and success of
their ongoing projects (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#connected-cabin&#34;&gt;case description&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CTO’s guidance through bi-weekly meetings focused on discussing the
researcher’s analysis, modelling, and collected data. These interactions
were key for the research trajectory in addition to the autonomy of the
researcher having built his relations/network across business units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;end-of-phd-and-autonomy&#34;&gt;End of PhD and autonomy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the second half of the PhD, as several case studies were ended
but required further analysis and modelling, the researcher had already
established regular contact with several R&amp;amp;T Managers or Director of
Engineering. Naturally, the researcher was requested for his
contributions to TRL assessment and TRM definition, as well as
procedures written for the Zodiac Aerospace Operational System (ZAOS)
(see 
&lt;a href=&#34;#phd-candidate-in-innovation-management-position%22&#34;&gt;table&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, the researcher was gradually acknowledged among these
managers for his input on innovation management. For instance, the case
study and intervention for Zodiac Oxygen Systems Europe (ZOSE, see

&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/#hypoxia-protection---researchers-intervention&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;)
was proposed by the R&amp;amp;T manager. He had started an internal program to
anticipate evolution and disruption of pilot oxygen masks to complement
the benchmark made by the marketing department. Creativity sessions were
considered and the researcher assisted the R&amp;amp;T team to organize them and
capitalize on the design efforts made as well as with the evaluation. In
parallel, an internal open innovation challenge had been organized by
the ZSTC, of which one topic concerned the comfort and functions
associated to the pilot protection against the risks of hypoxia.
Consequently, the researched helped transcribing the open innovation
outcomes into an innovative design mapping based on C-K theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the initiated program was carried on and partially
translated into an answer to a call for partners in the European funded
program: Clean Sky 2. Airbus was leader of the topic reviewing the
future pilot oxygen mask. A team was put in place at ZOSE and started
designing concepts dealing with the ill-defined problem presented in the
program. The researcher was invited again to help formalizing the
efforts made and explain their design process. The challenge was to
gradually explain how to address highly uncertain and unknown parameters
in their design process and discussions with the principal
partner/client (Airbus).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researcher was called to provide internal training, recognized by HR
department, for the R&amp;amp;T department of Zodiac Seats France. The training
consisted in an introduction to design theories, design regimes and a
workshop to practice. Another example, during the PhD writing, the
researcher had the opportunity to contribute to an innovative design
initiative at Zodiac Electrical Power Systems. Beyond the design issue,
in the same way as in the ZOSE case, the researcher intervened and
tested models based on his research, as part of the process of testing
the &lt;em&gt;set of logics&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;change process&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages-and-risks-of-intervention-research-for-the-study&#34;&gt;Advantages and risks of intervention research for the study&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The position of the researcher, as an executive PhD given the CIFRE
convention, exposed him to valuable insight on open management issues
but also some potential &lt;em&gt;contamination&lt;/em&gt; of data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;catching-ctos-political-influence-and-complaining&#34;&gt;Catching CTO’s political influence and complaining&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being hosted at the Innovation Direction and studying the topic of
innovation management opened many doors in business units and corporate
meetings. It was quite easy to gather information during the first round
of interviews and the subsequent interactions with engineers, designers
and managers, as well as interventions in business units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some rare occasions, some interviews were hard to manage as the
speech being held was very negative (complaining). The dialogue had to
be redirected towards proposing solutions, alternatives or different
management philosophy to deal with. And sometimes, the closeness to the
CTO was tentatively tried to put a word or find backup. Of course, these
are dimensions of daily life in organizations and reflect a certain
situation, but for the role of the researcher, it can complicate the
activity of separating a clean analysis from one that is contaminated by
potential superfluous details. For instance, the question of
irrationality and absurdity of decisions or lack of understanding of
strategies of some managers were hard cases that could have been quickly
put into the quarantine of useless collected data. Yet, the role of the
researcher is to propose hypotheses, new models that can explain Reality
and be predictive in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;being-consulted-for-multiple-and-varied-topics&#34;&gt;Being consulted for multiple and varied topics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, in a previous section on gaining autonomy, the researcher
had new opportunities to study cases, following Jacques Girin’s
&amp;ldquo;opportunistic methodology&amp;rdquo; and also introduced in the comprehensive
methodology as expressed by Hervé Dumez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, as new procedures had been written by the researcher for
the TRL assessment, the Internal Audit Team quite often relied on him to
provide appropriate recommendations to BUs. It was the occasion for the
researcher to bring additional information when interacting the
concerned R&amp;amp;T manager and try to probe the field in search for critical
events, shifts in their speech, or simply new projects catching one’s
attention: new design/technology embarking a organizational change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this chapter, we have presented the research journey over the last
three years. We covered how intervention research was implemented at
Zodiac Aerospace emphasizing the different movements of participating to
the firm’s activities, studying them and also gaining in reflexivity
with academic activities including meetings, seminars, presentations,
conferences and article writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the overarching research methodology, the literature review
highlighted several limitations and potential anomaly which were partly
confirmed through several interactions and difficulties faced by the
researcher in his academic interactions. We proposed how to address the
anomaly and the associate effort to name and model the novel phenomenon.
We put to the fore descriptors and synthetics models (adaptive,
interactive and encapsulated) to instrument the anomaly detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have also indicated several other activities of the
researcher in the firm and how fruitful the environment and interactions
were to facilitate the original research agenda and disentangle the
&lt;em&gt;open management issue&lt;/em&gt; with colleagues concerned by the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Allen1986&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen, Thomas J., and Ralph Katz. 1986. “The dual ladder: motivational
solution or managerial delusion?” &lt;em&gt;R&amp;amp;D Management&lt;/em&gt; 16 (2): 185–97.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9310.1986.tb01171.x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9310.1986.tb01171.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Bachelard1927&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bachelard, Gaston. 1927. &lt;em&gt;Essai sur la connaissance approchée&lt;/em&gt;. J.Vrin.
Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Birkinshaw2013&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birkinshaw, Julian, and Kamini Gupta. 2013. “Clarifying the distinctive
contribution of ambidexterity to the field of organization studies.”
&lt;em&gt;The Academy of Management Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; 27 (4): 287–98.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Boudon2012&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boudon, Raymond. 2012. &lt;em&gt;La rationalité&lt;/em&gt;. Edited by Quadrige. Paris,
France: Presse Université de France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Bronk2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bronk, Richard. 2009. “Imagination and creativity in markets.” In &lt;em&gt;The
Romantic Economist: Imagination in Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 196–224. Cambridge
University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Carlgren2016a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlgren, Lisa, Ingo Rauth, and Maria Elmquist. 2016. “Framing Design
Thinking: The Concept in Idea and Enactment.” &lt;em&gt;Creativity and Innovation
Management&lt;/em&gt; 25 (1): 38–57. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/caim.12153&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/caim.12153&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Cohen1989a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohen, Wesley M, and Daniel A Levinthal. 1989. “Innovation and Learning:
The Two Faces of R &amp;amp; D.” &lt;em&gt;The Economic Journal&lt;/em&gt; 99 (397): 569–96.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/2233763&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/2233763&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Cohendet2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohendet, Patrick, and Laurent Simon. 2016. “Always Playable:
Recombining Routines for Creative Efficiency at Ubisoft Montreal’s Video
Game Studio.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 27 (3): 614–32.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.2016.1062&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1287/orsc.2016.1062&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Dana2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dana, Léo-Paul, and Hervé Dumez. 2015. “Qualitative research revisited:
epistemology of a comprehensive approach.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of
Entrepreneurship and Small Business&lt;/em&gt; 26 (2): 154–70.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1504/IJESB.2015.071822&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1504/IJESB.2015.071822&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Dumez2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dumez, Hervé. 2016. &lt;em&gt;Comprehensive research. A methodological and
epistemological introduction to qualitative research&lt;/em&gt;. 1st ed.
Copenhaguen Business School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Feduzi2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feduzi, Alberto, Jochen Runde, Christoph Loch, and Laure Cabantous.
2016. “Methods of inquiry and comprehensiveness in strategic
decision-making under extreme uncertainty.” In &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management
Meeting 2016&lt;/em&gt;, 41.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Frega2010&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frega, Roberto. 2010. “Expressive Inquiry and Practical Reasoning.” &lt;em&gt;The
Journal of Speculative Philosophy&lt;/em&gt; 23 (4): 307–27.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1353/jsp.0.0093&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1353/jsp.0.0093&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Garcias2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garcias, Frédéric, Cédric Dalmasso, and Jean-Claude Sardas. 2015.
“Paradoxical Tensions in Learning Processes: Exploration, Exploitation
and Exploitative Learning.” &lt;em&gt;M@n@gement&lt;/em&gt; 18 (2): 156–78.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Griffin1993&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Griffin, Larry J. 1993. “Narrative, Event-Structure Analysis, and Causal
Interpretation in Historical Sociology.” &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Sociology&lt;/em&gt;
98 (5): 1094–1133. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1086/230140&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1086/230140&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Griffin1994&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Griffin, Larry, and Charles C. Ragin. 1994. “Some Observations on Formal
Methods of Qualitative Analysis.” &lt;em&gt;Sociological Methods &amp;amp; Research&lt;/em&gt; 23
(1): 4–21. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0049124194023001001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0049124194023001001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hatchuel2008&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatchuel, A, and A David. 2008. “Collaborating for management research:
from action research to intervention research in management.” &lt;em&gt;Handbook
of Collaborative Management Research&lt;/em&gt;, 143–62.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-VonHippel2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hippel, Eric von, and Georg von Krogh. 2016. “CROSSROADS—Identifying
Viable ‘Need–Solution Pairs’: Problem Solving Without Problem
Formulation.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 27 (1): 207–21.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/doi:10.1287/orsc.2015.1023&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/doi:10.1287/orsc.2015.1023&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Hooge2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hooge, Sophie, and Cédric Dalmasso. 2015. “Breakthrough R&amp;amp;D
Stakeholders: The Challenges of Legitimacy in Highly Uncertain
Projects.” &lt;em&gt;Project Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 46 (6): 54–73.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21554&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/pmj.21554&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Lakatos1980&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lakatos, Imre. 1980. &lt;em&gt;The methodology of scientific research programmes:
Volume 1: Philosophical papers&lt;/em&gt;. Edited by John Worral and Gregory
Currie. Vol. 1. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Glatin, Mario, Pascal Le Masson, Armand Hatchuel, and Benoît Weil.
2018. “Design Paradigm in innovation management - analysing and
extending design thinking methods with design theory.” In &lt;em&gt;R&amp;amp;D
Management Conference&lt;/em&gt;. Milan, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2016&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Glatin, Mario, Pascal Le Masson, and Benoit Weil. 2016. “Measuring
the generative power of an organisational routine with design theories:
the case of design thinking in a large firm.” In &lt;em&gt;6th Cim Community
Workshop - 25th Anniversary of the Creativity and Innovation Management
Journal&lt;/em&gt;. Potsdam.

&lt;a href=&#34;https://hal.archives-ouvertes.fr/hal-01367471%7B%5c#%7D.V9u4ZMmiS0k.mendeley&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://hal.archives-ouvertes.fr/hal-01367471{\#}.V9u4ZMmiS0k.mendeley&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2017&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Glatin, Mario, Pascal Le Masson, and Benoît Weil. 2017a. “Decision
design and re-ordering preferences: the case of an exploration project
in a large firms.” In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 21st International Conference
on Engineering Design (Iced17)&lt;/em&gt;, 7:81–90. August. Vancouver, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2017a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2017b. “Generative action and preference reversal in exploratory
project management.” &lt;em&gt;CERN IdeaSquare Journal of Experimental
Innovation&lt;/em&gt; 1 (2): 39–46. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5170/cij.2017.539&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeGlatin2018a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2018. “Can Ambidexterity kill innovation? A case for non-expected
utility decision-making.” In &lt;em&gt;EURAM 2018&lt;/em&gt;. Reykjavik, Iceland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-LeMasson2018&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Masson, Pascal, Armand Hatchuel, Mario Le Glatin, and Benoit Weil.
2018. “Designing Decisions in the Unknown: A Generative Model.”
&lt;em&gt;European Management Review&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/emre.12289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/emre.12289&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Mankins2009&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mankins, John C. 2009. “Technology readiness assessments: A
retrospective.” &lt;em&gt;Acta Astronautica&lt;/em&gt; 65 (9): 1216–23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Morgeson2015&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morgeson, Frederick P., Terence R. Mitchell, and Dong Liu. 2015. “Event
system theory: An event-oriented approach to the organizational
sciences.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of Management Review&lt;/em&gt; 40 (4): 515–37.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2012.0099&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.2012.0099&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Oury1983&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oury, Jean-Marc, and Christian Schmidt. 1983. &lt;em&gt;Economie politique de la
vigilance&lt;/em&gt;. Paris: Calmann-Lévy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Siggelkow2007&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siggelkow, Nicolaj. 2007. “Persuasion with case studies.” &lt;em&gt;Academy of
Management Journal&lt;/em&gt; 50 (1): 20–24.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Simon2006&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon, Laurent. 2006. “Managing creative projects: An empirical
synthesis of activities.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt;
24 (2): 116–26. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2005.09.002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2005.09.002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Weber1946&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weber, Max. 1946. &lt;em&gt;From Max Weber: Essays in Sociology&lt;/em&gt;. Edited by H.
Gerth and C. Wright Mills. Oxford University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from the Greek &lt;em&gt;isonomia&lt;/em&gt; = &lt;em&gt;iso-&lt;/em&gt; (equal) and &lt;em&gt;nomos&lt;/em&gt; (the order
of the world). Ability to discuss freely theories-in-use through
steering committees and prepared meetings &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;supervising a testing laboratory of Zodiac Interconnect UK
following his MSc in Aeronautical Engineering &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translation by the researcher: &amp;ldquo;L’ordre des sensibilités ne suit
pas nécessairement les traits saillants, ce qu’on pourait appeler le
&lt;em&gt;relief dynamique de notre expérience&lt;/em&gt;. On est bien en effet peu
d’accord sur la simplification du phénomène préalable à tout
développement scientifique. On croit que les caractères primordiaux
ressortent d’eux-mêmes et s’imposent à notre étude par la seule
force de leur généralité. Parfois cependant, c’est l’accident et non
le général qui est principe d’explication au point qu’il faut
renverser les problèmes pour restituer la généralité à des
caractères phénoménaux que l’esprit avait schématisés dans un sens
spécial.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Presentation of the research field and justification of case studies</title>
      <link>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part2/chapter5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, we start by presenting the aviation industry market and
specially the context of equipment manufacturers with current challenges
for this ecosystem (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;#aviation-industry-market&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;)
We insist through its history the nature of constraints, their
formalization and how the industry professionalized over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we continue by introducing our research ground and the specificity
of Zodiac Aerospace and how relevant it is for our research questions
(see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part1/chapter3/&#34;&gt;chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;). The organization structure of this conglomerate of SMEs and
history of acquisitions is described in order to provide enough context
for the reader to grasp engineering and marketing challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we will briefly present the selected cases (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;#case-studies-selection&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;)
before diving into the analysis in the following parts 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part3/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part4/&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/phd/part5/&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;.
We explain the contribution of each case to our research methodology and
to article writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aviation-industry-market&#34;&gt;Aviation industry market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aviation industry started off with many successful and failed
attempts since the eighteenth century. It is only after the 19th century
industrial revolutions that investors and influencers started promoting
the development air balloons, Zeppelins and gliders along with
engine-powered aircrafts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, we develop the establishment and evolution of this
market, the challenges associated with product development, its
perspectives, and the position of a large equipment manufacturer such as
Zodiac Aerospace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources used for this section range for courses taken by the researcher
during his studies in aeronautical engineering (ISAE-SUPAERO), the
Museum of Conservatoire National des Arts-et-Métiers, public domain
documentation (Airbus/Boeing market forecasts and EASA/FAA documents)
and internal documentation provided by the communication office of
Zodiac Aerospace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-global-sector-for-an-increasing-traffic&#34;&gt;A global sector for an increasing traffic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;pioneering-establishment-and-consolidation&#34;&gt;Pioneering, establishment and consolidation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is usually recognized that the first flight of a fixed-wing
powered-aircraft was the &lt;em&gt;Éole&lt;/em&gt; in 1890, developed by Clément Ader with
the support of the Péreire family - who had previously financed part of
Hausman’s renovation. His works were an application of discoveries and
theoretical models formulated earlier in the century by George Cayley
(first fixed-wing glider and formulation of drag and lift forces and the
usefulness of cambered wings&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The French Military Ministry had gained interest in his engineering
efforts who encouraged further experimentation with the support of the
ministry’s engineering departments, a council of professors and the
establishment of a school of &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;aircraftery&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
The subsequent developments led to &lt;em&gt;Avion II&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Avion III&lt;/em&gt; (see
Fig.&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:AderAvion3&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:AderAvion3&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;),
the army had plans for observation and bombing. Several experiments were
conducted to master the aircraft. However, with the crash of &lt;em&gt;Avion
III&lt;/em&gt;, the difficulties to explain what lessons could be drawn, and the
secrecy imposed by the Army, left C.Ader without any further financial
support to continue the trial-and-error process started. As explained by
himself in his book (Ader 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Ader1907&#34;&gt;1907&lt;/a&gt;), he may have started
too early and it would have been preferable to work publicly. It then
abandoned the legacy of the &lt;em&gt;Éole&lt;/em&gt; and his larger project of
contributing to the National Defence through the founding of a school
for aviation.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-clement-aders-avion-iii-in-1897&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/AderAvion3.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Clement Ader’s Avion III in 1897&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/AderAvion3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Clement Ader’s &lt;em&gt;Avion III&lt;/em&gt; in 1897
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clément Ader’s project would be fulfilled later by Colonel Jean-Baptiste
Roche when creating the Superior School of Aeronautics and Mechanical
Construction in 1909, now known under the name of ISAE-SUPAERO
(Toulouse)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. But another trend had gained more visibility in parallel
to development attempts of rotating/fixed-wing aircrafts: hot air
balloons had been developed starting in 1784 with the &lt;em&gt;Intrépide&lt;/em&gt; flying
over the Versailles castle with Montgolfier brothers&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
Several &amp;ldquo;research companies&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;Société d’Études&lt;/em&gt;) were established to
develop airships with the support of investors (a key venture capitalist
at that time was Henri Deutsch de la Meurthe), politicians, and
academics from different institutions (Aéro-club de France, Science
Academy, Engineering Schools such as Mines ParisTech, Ecole
Polytechnique and St Cyr). For example, here are a few key names: Grands
Ateliers Aérostatiques du Champ-de-Mars by E.Surcouf in 1880, later
renamed Société Astra who would manufacture Wright brothers’ aircraft
under licence and Société &amp;ldquo;Mallet, Mélandri et de Pitray&amp;rdquo; in 1896 (later
named Zodiac in 1911)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. They had an industrial vision for these
applications that were the hype in that time in World Exhibitions. Along
with air races and numerous experiments, applications for the Army and
Transportation were also targeted as use cases. They had been validated
for instance during the American Civil War with the Union Army Balloon
Corps&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-exposition-universelle-zodiac-airship-in-1909&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/zodiac1900.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Exposition Universelle Zodiac airship in 1909&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/zodiac1900.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Exposition Universelle &lt;em&gt;Zodiac&lt;/em&gt; airship in 1909
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides airships, technology transfers and alternative approaches where
developed during the same period such as the effort of Alberto
Santos-Dumont with the famous 14bis (1906) and Demoiselle (1907)
fixed-wing aircrafts, Henry Fabre (first seaplane in 1910) and Coanda’s
first alleged jet engines (ducted air fan with combustion chamber in
1910), &lt;em&gt;Appareils d’Aviation Les Frères Voisin&lt;/em&gt; (est. 1906, later split
and integrated into what would become &lt;em&gt;Gnome&amp;amp;Rhône&lt;/em&gt; est. 1905, i.e.
SNECMA/Safran Aircraft Engines) and &lt;em&gt;Blériot Aéronautique&lt;/em&gt;, a
constituent of today’s Airbus along with former Dassault Aviation
(&lt;em&gt;Société des Avions Marcel Bloch&lt;/em&gt;, est. 1929) who had merged with
pioneering work of &lt;em&gt;Bréguet Aviation&lt;/em&gt; (est. 1911).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the list is not exhaustive, but we would like to stress the
numerous links tied by inventors and investors across several decades of
experiments, partnerships and industrial settings. And similar stories
could also be presented in other countries of Europe and North
America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frenzy was also channelled by the founding of companies such as
&lt;em&gt;Compagnie générale transaérienne&lt;/em&gt; (est.1908 by Blériot) &lt;em&gt;Compagnie des
Messagers Aériens&lt;/em&gt; (founded in 1919 by Bréguet, Blériot, Renault and
Caudron) and &lt;em&gt;Compagnie Générale Aéropostale&lt;/em&gt; (est. 1918, by
Pierre-Georges Latécoère) who created a market to sustain an emerging
industry besides military applications. The former would then be
acquired by growing competition, mergers to become Air France for
instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premises of the aviation industry was a collective effort of
engineering where a dominant design was gradually established discarding
airships for reliability issues. Different architectures with engines
moving from the back (pusher) to the front of the fuselage (tractor),
different profiles for lift and drag trade-offs (&amp;ldquo;canard configuration&amp;rdquo;,
box-kite) and steering/stability equipment (box-kite, dihedral, rudders,
ailerons), fixed wheels or idlers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    The value of the &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;aircraftery&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; took decades to be demonstrated with
trials made by a community of pioneers who thrived from building in
parallel an ecosystem and organizations supporting their product
designs: Army, influential investors, mutual investments and self
investment in the creation of market (e.g. mailing and transportation),
academic institution creation, learned societies, associations and
federations. This is a crucial aspect to emphasize as the setting of the
market was not a linear process, nor the lonely process of several
pioneers who demonstrated the superiority of product design.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-turning-point-jet-age&#34;&gt;A turning point: jet age&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following major improvements made during and after World War I (WWI),
the jet era would finally come to existence despite first tentative
steps made by Henri-Marie Coanda in 1910. The latter being marginalized
during the second exhibition of the International Aeronautic Salon in
October 1910 against standard designs and persisting
doubts/controversies on the actual airworthiness of the aircraft and the
engine (ducted air fan or actual jet engine). The figures below show the
Coanda-1910
(&lt;a href=&#34;#sub:Coanda1910&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;sub:Coanda1910&#34;&gt;[sub:Coanda1910]&lt;/a&gt;)
versus the two dominant designs of that time: airships and unshrouded
propellers aircrafts
(&lt;a href=&#34;#sub:Salon1909&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;sub:Salon1909&#34;&gt;[sub:Salon1909]&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href=&#34;#sub:Salon1910&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;sub:Salon1910&#34;&gt;[sub:Salon1910]&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-first-dominant-designs---coanda-1910&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/Coanda1910.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;First dominant designs - Coanda-1910&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/Coanda1910.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    First dominant designs - Coanda-1910
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-first-dominant-designs---salon-1909&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/salon1909.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;First dominant designs - Salon 1909&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/salon1909.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    First dominant designs - Salon 1909
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-first-dominant-designs---salon-1910&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/salon1910.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;First dominant designs - Salon 1910&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/salon1910.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    First dominant designs - Salon 1910
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As several records would be broken by aviators (distance, time and
speed), aircraft designers and manufacturers would also compete in
engineering novel engines, optimising propellers, materials, in addition
to wing and fuselage designs. For instance, one can recall the success
of &lt;em&gt;Blériot XI&lt;/em&gt; when crossing the English Channel against Antoinette
aircraft, encouraging its promotion during the 1st Paris Air show (see
Fig.
&lt;a href=&#34;#sub:Salon1909&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;sub:Salon1909&#34;&gt;[sub:Salon1909]&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conceptual models and theoretical efforts were made by physicists and
engineers building upon the earlier works of George Cayley in the 19th
century. Besides the need for pilot training such as rudimentary
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;tonneau Antoinette&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;, wind tunnels were built to formalize design
parameters in addition to testing facilities sponsored by the army. For
example, Gustave Eiffel wind tunnels built in 1909 in Paris (Champ de
Mars) (Gallant 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Gallant2002&#34;&gt;2002&lt;/a&gt;; Barr 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Barr1992&#34;&gt;1992&lt;/a&gt;)
contributed not only to mechanical engineering for buildings but also to
aerodynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air Transportation would only start to exist with several routes of
airships in North America and Europe, but with WWI bombers converted for
passengers, the first airlines were created and dedicated aircraft
designs such as the Farman Goliath F60 derived from the F50 bomber (see
Fig.
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:GoliathF60a&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:GoliathF60a&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;).
With increasing speeds, optimization of turbo-propellers, sonic speeds
can be reached at the propellers tips, so shrouded configurations can be
beneficial encouraging the development of ducted-fan and then turbofan,
a kind of jet engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advancements in jet engines became a major architectural innovation for
heavier-than-air aircrafts (Henderson and Clark

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Henderson1990&#34;&gt;1990&lt;/a&gt;). It sets a milestone in the development of
long haul flights and commercial aviation. It would be hard to say that
it was unexpected for established industrial players. However, it raises
the issue of perception and cognition of change in product design
(incremental, radical, architectural and modular) and the ecosystem
deals with the emergence of this shifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The onset of the jet era occurred with the commercial aviation
intensification, flight routes tailored supporting a wider phenomenon
usually dubbed &amp;ldquo;globalization&amp;rdquo;. Distances are shortened, leisure is
democratized for wider categories of population, with major emphasis put
on the efficiency of engines for airlines operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frequency and variety of aircraft missions across the globe also
raised numerous evolutions for safety and robustness. Redundancy is the
baseline for most aircraft systems (operational). Several other
architectural innovations can be listed in the evolution such as the
elimination of the Flight Engineer in the cockpit as a side-effect of
development of electronics and digital commands.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-farmans-f60-aircraft-for-12-passengers-in-1919&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/GoliathF60a.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Farman’s F60 aircraft for 12 passengers in 1919&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/GoliathF60a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Farman’s F60 aircraft for 12 passengers in 1919
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-order-and-segmentation&#34;&gt;Market order and segmentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;major-players-and-market-organization&#34;&gt;Major players and market organization&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market is mainly organized by aircraft manufacturers who integrate
the systems and equipment (co-)designed by suppliers. It is hardly
impossible to avoid the prescription mechanisms associated to Boeing and
Airbus, and marginally by Bombardier, Embraer and increasingly Irkut and
Comac. Several mergers of engineering services and manufacturers
consolidated what Boeing and Airbus are today. For instance, Boeing
absorbed McDonnell Douglas, Airbus is the result of the merger of Sud
Aviation and Nord Aviation to become first Aérospatiale. Forces were
joined, redistributing the roles of among historic roles: airframers,
structural part engineering and aircraft integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the market can be seen as an oligopoly for systems and
equipment manufacturers. The whole being layered to meet the integration
requirements of the aircraft manufacturer. See Fig.
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:MarketOrg&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:MarketOrg&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;
for further details.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-schematics-of-market-organization&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/MarketOrg.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Schematics of market organization&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/MarketOrg.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Schematics of market organization
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After numerous series of mergers and acquisitions at all market levels,
the number of players has reduced drastically. This consolidation has
put a certain order and hierarchy in market relationships, encouraging
players to by-pass some players to gain insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can refer for instance to the mapping built by Grundman Advisory
from 1993 to 2016. A few more can be added such as Safran acquiring
Zodiac Aerospace and United Technologies Corporation (UTC) with Rockwell
Collins (who recently acquired B/E Aerospace). The very large mapping
(pdf format) can be accessed on Grundman’s Advisory news section:
&lt;em&gt;Aviation Week publishes Grundman Opinion, &amp;ldquo;A map of aerospace mergers
and acquisitions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this context, airlines undergoing changes in demographics,
population displacement, market design (e.g. hub structure) have
evolving requirements for aircraft missions: longer routes, multiple
stopovers across a continent, low maintenance etc. The aircraft
manufactures perform a preliminary proposal to meet their key customers
(major airlines).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aircrafts can be categorized in now three groups: short/long haul, and
currently business magazines tend to introduce the concept of
&amp;ldquo;middle-of-market&amp;rdquo;. Below, Fig.
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:AircraftMarketSegments&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:AircraftMarketSegments&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;
shows along two &lt;em&gt;performance criteria&lt;/em&gt; the three sets of aircrafts.
Despite visual and alleged similarities between short/long haul
aircrafts, physics, design rules and systems’ architectures do not allow
a simple rule of three. Aircraft programs are spanned across roughly a
decade in average (from the early designs to first delivery) mobilizing
several suppliers in a co-development process and requirements cascaded
down along the hierarchy of product/service design.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-aircraft-market-segments&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/AircraftMarketSegments.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Aircraft Market Segments&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/AircraftMarketSegments.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Aircraft Market Segments
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among suppliers, as most players are conglomerate of SMEs, these follow
in broad strokes the perimeters given by the ATA chapters (Air
Transportation Association). The classification is originally intended
for engineers and technicians performing repairs and maintenance duties
on aircrafts. Aircraft systems are covered from ATA no.20 to 92. For
example, ATA 44 corresponds to Cabin Systems, where one can find the
following sub-systems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;44-00 General&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;44-10 Cabin Core System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;44-20 In-flight Entertainment System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;44-30 External Communication System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;44-40 Cabin Mass Memory System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;44-50 Cabin Monitoring System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;44-60 Miscellaneous Cabin System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one can see, it does not cover for instance several &amp;ldquo;monuments&amp;rdquo; found
in the cabin: seats, class dividers, lavatories, galleys, etc. ATA
follows a system architecture description and the cabin domain should be
seen as an area sanctuarised by airline for customization and branding.
Naturally, it has more players specialized equipment certified by
Technical Standard Order (TSO, see below for further details).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;importance-of-safety-and-regulations&#34;&gt;Importance of safety and regulations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First safety regulation can be associated with a publication of the
Paris Police headquarters dating from April 23, 1784. It followed the
flight of the hot air balloon built by the Montgolfier brothers in late
1783 for King Louis XVI at Versailles castle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It shall be unlawful to manufacture and lift off balloons and other
aerostatic machines with heaters using wine spirit, fire crackers and
other flammable materials and orders that all other aerostatic
balloons may not take-off without permission. Such permission shall
only be granted to people with recognized experience and
capability&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the early delays, the approach to aircraft safety came as insurance
for justifying on one hand what objects were safe and reliable according
to a set of standardized criteria and on the other hand the how and the
who required to design, develop and sustain these objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite some differences between the rules established for North America
and Europe - Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and European Aviation
Safety Agency (EASA) respectively - they ensure airworthiness&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; along
four main domains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring Safety issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product Certified &amp;amp; Checked&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safety Rules &amp;amp; regulations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approved Organizations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These topics are declined in the certification process that is
recognized with the issue of Type Certificate for the aircraft and
associated scope covering critical systems and equipment (e.g.
electrical power generation and distribution). In addition, almost
standalone equipment such as engine have their own Type Certificate and
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;less critical&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; equipment with Technical Standard Order (TSO); so
they can be qualified and certified with a relative independence from
the aircraft manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general process is described in the Fig.
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:CertificationProcess&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:CertificationProcess&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;
pictures the phases until the release of a form (e.g. EASA Form-1/FAA
8130-3) validating the conformity of the manufactured/repaired product
given an extensive list of justification documents issued by Design,
Manufacturing and Maintenance activities. The figure also insists on the
fact that airworthiness is maintained throughout the life of the
product, meaning until it is dismantled and removed from the aircraft
fleet.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-certification-process&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/CertificationProcess.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Certification Process&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/CertificationProcess.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Certification Process
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The certification and crucial airworthiness aspect, a more technical set
of requirements are addressed by system/equipment/technology/material-specific standards. These are issued by several regulatory bodies such as SAE International (Society of Automotive Engineers) issuing Aerospace Recommended Practice (ARP),
EUROCAE (European Organization for Civil Aviation Equipment), RTCA
(Radio Technical Commission for Aeronautics) issuing standards for
instance &amp;ldquo;Environmental Conditions and Test Procedures for Airborne
Equipment&amp;rdquo;, MIL-STD from the US Military Standard, etc. Qualification
and design processes requirements are largely compliant with these
standards in addition to customer requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, the International Organization for Standardization
(ISO) has greatly contributed to the standardization of processes with
ISO9100 / AS9100 (Aerospace Basic Quality System Standard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;challenges-and-future-changes&#34;&gt;Challenges and future changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market is rapidly growing based on surveys and forecasts made by
Boeing and Airbus on yearly basis. Asia-Pacific countries are greatly
contributing to this trend with legacy aircrafts being retrofitted in
major American and European countries despite several external shocks.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-world-annual-traffic-evolution---airbus-global-market-forecast-2017&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/TrafficGrowth.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;World Annual traffic evolution - Airbus Global Market Forecast 2017&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/TrafficGrowth.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    World Annual traffic evolution - Airbus Global Market Forecast 2017
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;35000 aircrafts will be delivered by 2036, among which 13000 are for
replacement and the rest being actual new deliveries growth. Traffic
will keep on increasing with rate per annum from 2.5% between advanced
countries up to 6.2% between emergent countries taking most of the
traffic share (40%). Finally, several other trends can be foreseen with
environmental considerations, passengers demographics and changing urban
mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;greener-aircrafts&#34;&gt;Greener aircrafts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rising awareness of human’s activity on Earth has also encouraged
the aviation industry to develop means of reducing its greenhouse effect
share. For instance, from the viewpoint of fuel combustion, optimizing
engines with a criteria such as number of passengers per kilometre per
litre of kerosene in addition to emitted $CO_2$ and $NOx$ particles per
number of passengers per kilometre. Tremendous engineering efforts were
made to enhance the efficiency of the combustion chambers, engine
sections (fan, compressor and turbines) and overall architecture
(by-pass). These efforts are still on going with open-rotor engine.
Taxiing of aircrafts could also be changed to avoid burning fuel with
electrical drive in landing gears or pushback car integrated on taxiing
rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other architectures such as delta wing for commercial aircrafts and
V-formation flight (inspired by geese flying patterns) have been
imagined by industrial actors. These approaches also tend to think the
overall aircraft and its integration within the airspace and airports.
Incremental innovations however can be designed by using lighter
materials while guaranteeing strength. For instance, marginal
improvements on wingtips or using composite materials for the skin of
wings and fuselage reduce overall weight. Nevertheless, these
replacement are not modular as it dramatically reduces the
electromagnetic shielding required against thunderstorms or simple
electromagnetic interferences. Shielding should then be improved across
wirings and harnesses needed for fly-by-wire systems&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and several
other electricity powered devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A greener aircraft does not only imply optimization along several
green-performance-indicators exploiting the dominant design, nor
replacing some features, but also has a greater impact on the
architecture of the aircraft itself and sensitivity to the evolutions of
the aircraft integration (e.g. airport, air traffic patterns, flight
route demands, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;passenger-demographics-and-trends&#34;&gt;Passenger demographics and trends&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passengers through airlines interaction the evolution of the market.
Passengers are more and more observed and consulted by airlines,
aircraft manufacturers and equipment manufacturers. Beyond traditional
satisfaction survey, creativity sessions and ethnographic observations
in &amp;ldquo;labs&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, the expectation of passengers are changing. Let us take, for
instance, the evolution of seats in the cabin. Historically, no
distinction existed. Then with the gradual democratization, class
segments were created: first, club and economy. The club disappeared to
be replaced by the idea of a business class, with now sometimes dense
business class, reducing the size of the first that aims for a
hotel-like experience. These nuances should also be declined depending
on culture and flight routes across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ageing population is another concern for cabin layout including: seating
and lavatories. Reduced mobility of certain categories of passengers
also causes several issues for seating, movement along corridors and
reaching for different cabin areas. Seats architecture and access are
modified, additional equipment to assist are also designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So called &lt;em&gt;millenials&lt;/em&gt; emphasize the rising ubiquity of (Internet)
connectivity on mainland and ground transportation. Airlines have been
gradually shaping the business model of connectivity with new suppliers
and services providers offering solutions guaranteeing an almost
continuous connectivity. From traditional shared displays hanging over
seats, to seat-centric inflight-entertainment, the passengers are now
also willing to connect to existing solutions: in-flight connectivity
(Wi-Fi and entertainment server) supported by antennae and ground/space
relays, and active/passive displays for mirror casting personal device
content or accessing airline provided content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These novelties being transferred from an evolving society and use cases
where aircraft experience may appear old fashioned. They bring numerous
uncertainties to a professionalized and highly constrained engineering.
New product development may then fit the given architecture but may also
encourage the generation of ad-hoc solutions and reconfiguration of
(epistemic) interdependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;urban-mobility&#34;&gt;Urban mobility&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, another major trend is the regain in urban mobility. The
reducing flight times and connecting time at stopovers, has dramatically
reduced distances across the globe. Combining this trend with city
expansion, road and general public transportation can become saturated
to point where other means must be developed. In cities of high
inequalities such as Sao Paulo, helicopters are an efficient alternative
to travel across the city avoid traffic jams for those who can afford.
Social imaginaries tend to contribute to urban mobility effort on
adapting aircraft to fly safely through the city skies. Science fiction
works in literature and movies have embodied these ideas for more than a
century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it is gradually becoming a reality with Unmanned Aerial
Vehicle’s technologies developed in the past two decades. Automation,
algorithmic robustness, and mastering of flight dynamics for quadcopter
designs for instance were key in addressing the scaling of remote
control devices to civil/military applications, and up to autonomous
taxi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last 5 years, several initiatives, usually referred as Passenger
Drones, were launched. In China, &lt;em&gt;eHang 184&lt;/em&gt; flew early 2018, in
Germany, &lt;em&gt;Lilium&lt;/em&gt; is being developed, in Dubai and Germany the
&lt;em&gt;Volocopter&lt;/em&gt; was developed and test flights were conducted, Airbus has
two concepts developed in two different centres: a traditional
vertical-take-off and landing (VTOL) called &lt;em&gt;Vahana&lt;/em&gt;, and a modular
solution combined with car &lt;em&gt;Pop.Up&lt;/em&gt;. These passenger drones enable
on-demand air transportation expanding the horizons of taxi fleets and
personal/public transportation with safer means of flight travel that
are not reachable with traditional light aviation airworthiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evolution of the market order and segmentation given the highlighted
trends encourage equipment manufacturers to carefully reconsider the way
products and services are developed. In the following section, we
develop how projects and programs are managed given the aviation history
depicted previously. Its professionalization has established rules,
processes and structures to support new product development which we
will address at the light of several novelties, increasing uncertainties
and the need to innovate, i.e. managing the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zodiac-aerospace-innovation-context&#34;&gt;Zodiac Aerospace Innovation Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, we propose to present the context of the research
project offered by Zodiac Aerospace. We cover its overall organization,
its history, examples of major innovations in the aviation industry and
how R&amp;amp;T and Innovation are managed across the group of SMEs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-organization-conglomerate-of-smes&#34;&gt;General organization: conglomerate of SMEs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thesis was conducted at the Technical &amp;amp; Innovation Direction of
Zodiac Aerospace (ZSA, holding). Established in 1896 by Maurice Mallet,
the venture initially targeted airship and fabric engineering. It has
now turned into a large industrial group of 75 entities designing,
developing and manufacturing aeronautical equipment for
aircraft/helicopters manufacturer and airlines. These are located over
100 facilities across the globe and mainly centralized in Europe and
North America. In the last couple of decades, some facilities were
established in cost-competitive countries for the serial production of
some entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group of SMEs where each of them, with a few hundreds employees
each, equating to a total of 35,000, have their own responsibility and
performance logic. A light group holding of 200 employees with several
support functions have the challenge to manage the sometimes competing
SMEs due to the market structures and build up synergies targeted by the
executive committee. As shown in the following page, we present the
variety of Zodiac Aerospace products that can be found on an aircraft.
The segmentation by branches dates from 2015, but the current status is
a merge between Cabin &amp;amp; Structures and Galleys &amp;amp; Equipment (now called
Zodiac Cabin), and Aircraft Systems and Aerosafety (now called Zodiac
Aerosystems). Most equipment is represented by a single business unit,
overlap is rare between entities. For example, in the kitchen area
(galley) the configuration is the following with all separate
engineering departments, standards and regulations and sales channels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The galley structure (frame, panels and fixtures) is developed by
Zodiac Galleys Europe/US&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inserts (oven, boilers, coffee makers, bun warmers and ice
containers) are developed by Zodiac Electrical Inserts Europe/US&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trolleys designed by Zodiac Air Catering Equipment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lavatories are composed of the lining/decorative elements
(Zodiac Airline Interior Integration) and of toilet seat and
underlying water &amp;amp; waste systems (Zodiac Water &amp;amp; Waste Systems)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zodiac-aerospace-overview-corporate-communication&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/zddiac-carto.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Zodiac Aerospace overview (Corporate Communication)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/zddiac-carto.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Zodiac Aerospace overview (Corporate Communication)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-history-of-complementary-niche-strategy&#34;&gt;A history of complementary niche strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zodiac Aerospace, actually stems from the separation with Zodiac Marine.
The former Zodiac Group had been expanding between seas and skies with
technology transfers from air balloons to inflatable boat&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:12&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and
several other extensions playing on complementarities to expand its
footprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of mergers and acquisitions, leaving aside the former Zodiac
Marine group of entities, can be traced back to the seventies with EFA
(Parachutes in United States) reopening the aeronautics branch as shown
in the figure below (Fig.
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig:acquisitions&#34; data-reference-type=&#34;ref&#34; data-reference=&#34;fig:acquisitions&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;).
The main drivers for acquisitions, as explained on Zodiac Aerospace
corporate presentation, are synthesized into five key principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diversifying in businesses with a high technological content,
through internal and external growth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favouring niche markets to rapidly attain leader positions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensuring steady growth in earnings per share&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporting customers over the long-term through a strong after-sales
activity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aligning our operations with the Principles of the Global Compact&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first group of acquisitions intended to gain stronghold in the
aircraft safety systems market whilst still developing some related
marine activities around rubber coated fabrics (Kléber Industries),
flexible tanks (Superflexit), parachutes (EFA, Parachutes de France) and
arresting/evacuation systems (Air Cruisers, Aerazur). The family
shareholders’ trust put in the newly appointed CEO Jean-Louis Gérondeau.
He led an external growth strategy helping the financial recovery and
building a strong position in the aircraft equipment market. The
strategy was then extended with several other niche markets (mainly
oligopoly) with high added value justified by complex engineering
know-how complying with safety and airworthiness regulations. For
instance, early nineties was the entry into the aircraft seating (Weber
Aircraft, Sicma Aero Seat), water &amp;amp; waste systems (Monogram/MAG Aero and
Avon) and oxygen devices as well as sensing and systems management
(Groupe Intertechnique).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, we have more than 40 acquisitions since late seventies which
enabled diversification around the inflatable boat decaying market with
sport and leisure perspectives. But mostly, the group regained a
leadership position in the aircraft equipment market by federating
numerous SMEs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As told by Olivier Zarrouati&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:13&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; during an open interview in May 2018
conducted by the PhD candidate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We scouted our environment for niches with high added value, after a
selection process, we would then make sure that new business unit will
be able to perform and hold its position in the market. When it comes
then to innovative concepts, the trick is really to make sure they
understand the value of novelty on their own and not by forcing it by
top management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mindset was also confirmed by a separate interview made with the
Vice President of the group, Maurice Pinault, former CEO of Zodiac
Marine activities.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-history-of-acquisitions-by-zodiac-aerospace&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/acquisitions.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;History of acquisitions by Zodiac Aerospace&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/acquisitions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    History of acquisitions by Zodiac Aerospace
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;feats-of-engineering&#34;&gt;Feats of engineering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of Zodiac Aerospace has left several landmarks in the domain
of engineering. Starting the nascent airship venture, engineering
know-how was developed for fabric engineering and sewing techniques.
Then, when redeveloping the company in the aircraft market over less
than three decades, the group developed its competencies in complex
engineering for aircraft systems, and material and stress engineering
for cabin equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;technical-fabric-and-associated-technologies&#34;&gt;Technical fabric and associated technologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The airship industry at the wake of the $20^{th}$ century required not
only building an understanding of models of flight mechanics but being
able to design, engineering and manufacture robust fabric assemblies.
Standards of quality or test engineering were being gradually
established. Tensile strength of a piece of a fabric was crucial but
sewing techniques was an even more critical feature of these assemblies.
Advanced Sewing techniques were required for overall resistance to
aerodynamic forces (lift and drag) and associated designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With growing competition in an established market of inflatable boat,
Zodiac Aerospace managed to expand these competencies with the parachute
industry, inflatable boats, airbags, emergency evacuation systems
(slides, life rafts) and arresting systems (nets and harnesses on
runways). Several of these high skilled work can also be observed in
weaving and braiding techniques for conduits and hoses for harsh
environments. The developed industry thus greatly differs from clothing
industry with safety and airworthiness standards that imply a wide
spectrum of physical variables (temperature, tensile in static/dynamic
modes). It has greatly contributed to the unique position in a
quasi-duopoly with strong commercial and technical bonds with aircraft
manufacturers (Airbus, Boeing and McDonnell Douglas).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zodiac Aerospace has dominated the market of Parachutes, aircraft
arresting and evacuation systems and also part of the market associated
with braided/woven products. Unique technologies were developed to
remain competitive in several areas: flexible fuel tanks, open sleeves
for electrical harnesses and net arresting systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;composites-materials-and-cabin-equipment&#34;&gt;Composites materials and cabin equipment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early nineties, the Zodiac group had been developing the leisure and
sport marine domain to expand the inflatable boat market (Zodiac, Avon
and Bombard product lines). Their entry into the aircraft seating market
was done through Weber company who also had several engineering and
manufacturing capabilities in aircraft parts and synergies with its
former conglomerate Walter Kidde and Company Inc who had sold the
business to a largely diversified British conglomerate (Hanson
PLC).&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:14&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Kidde had also a foot in the inflatable boat market during
the war effort. A similar move was operated with SICMA in France, which
had been developing aircraft structural part, seats and also skis and
tennis rackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering could be then developed in the domain of material
engineering. Structural parts for pilot, crew and passenger seating were
developed and kept leadership by meeting and developing further safety
and certification requirements with authorities. The rest of the cabin
would then require similar technical capabilities for stress and
flammability constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All cabin interiors and galley’s area require qualification and
certification competencies to package for instance kitchen appliances to
airworthiness standards. All of which also requires to withstand severe
static and dynamic mechanical testing which are complex to monitor and
use for further design of assemblies and parts. Furthermore,
standardization is not common in this market because of market volumes
and changing demand of airlines looking for unique branding
opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;aircraft-systems&#34;&gt;Aircraft systems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the $20^{th}$ century, the group continued to settle its
position in other fields of the aircraft equipment market. Monogram (MAG
Aerospace) and Groupe Intertechnique were acquired. They had
respectively developed themselves in the field of water &amp;amp; waste systems
engineering and embedded systems for aircraft operations (computer,
printed circuit boards, fuel gauging systems, oxygen masks and control
systems). These two first acquisitions were a key advantage to secure
market niches. Added value is accomplished through complex system
engineering, functional robustness and secured certification
capabilities for further product development. It was the occasion to
combine engineering competencies into the creation of a business unit in
the field of airbags for automotive industry with inflatable technical
fabric and precise control electronic systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, these activities would be complemented by several power
electronics generation and distribution (ECE, Zodiac Electrical Power
Systems), wiring parts/systems and hydraulic, servo-control and ducting
systems. The underlying SMEs acquired on such domains had been building
their field first through components and quickly grew into engineering
of sub-systems and full systems in order to cover regulation and
certification domain. Several breakthroughs can be mentioned such as
inerting systems for fuel tanks, oxygen regulators, or even metal
fabrication in harsh environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;todays-rt-and-innovation-an-oddity-for-innovation-management&#34;&gt;Today’s R&amp;amp;T and Innovation: an oddity for innovation management?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;zstc-and-experts-network&#34;&gt;ZSTC and Experts Network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Established in 2010 by the managing director of former Intertechnique
group (covering former Aerotechnique group of activities, i.e. Fuel &amp;amp;
Control Systems and Oxygen Systems), the Zodiac Scientific and Technical
Council (ZSTC) gathers engineering managers and R&amp;amp;T managers equally
representing the variety of activities in the group. It was created for
four main objectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare technological evolution for the decade ahead and reinforce
synergies: long-term Technology Road Map were created to fit market
&amp;amp; sales perspectives to feed product lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Value technical experts across the company: expert career path
created with Human Resources for engineers preferring a technical
career instead of one dedicated to management&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:15&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:15&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinforce relationships with academia, start-ups, innovative
suppliers and potential partners: incentives to host PhD candidates
in R&amp;amp;T departments, collaborative research programs, &lt;em&gt;TechnoDays&lt;/em&gt;
seminars to gather people around common topics (e.g. composite
materials, electronics, systems engineering, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinforce Intellectual Property protection and management, as well
as R&amp;amp;T management practice (guidelines and procedures)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The council creation was supported by the Vice President of the group
(Maurice Pinault) for its strategic leverage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is a major leverage of growth for the Group such ours which designs
and manufacturers the most complex systems and that is required to meet
regulation constraints and quality &amp;amp; safety requirements increasingly
harder. In 2010, we created the ZSTC to improve the performance of our
technological research, to gather necessary resources for our
competitivity and foster the development of cross-cutting innovation
with high added value.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:16&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:16&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joint effort contributed to encourage transversality through some
major disciplines for the group such as material flammability, power
electronics, systems engineering and composite material engineering and
manufacturing. &lt;em&gt;TechnoDays&lt;/em&gt; have been organized for these topics,
experts were nominated locally in business units, and through round of
interviews experts gain different status degrees of the career path:&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-distribution-of-experts-by-status-and-technical-domain---zodiac-aerospace-human-resources-standard-za-h-5003&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/pyramid_experts.PNG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Distribution of experts by status and technical domain - Zodiac Aerospace Human Resources Standard ZA-H-5003&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mleglatin.github.io/img/pyramid_experts.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Distribution of experts by status and technical domain - Zodiac Aerospace Human Resources Standard ZA-H-5003
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;late-creation-of-rt-function-through-trl-assessment&#34;&gt;Late Creation of R&amp;amp;T function through TRL assessment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this initial background and internal efforts made in the business
units Zodiac Fuel &amp;amp; Control Systems to constitute a dedicated R&amp;amp;T Team
(in 2012-2013), workshops were organized with the support of a
consultancy firm to define and implement technology road maps (TRMs) for
all business units. With a bottom-up approach validated by top
management strategy, road maps were fed with marketing and sales data
picturing the future markets and technologies were identified to enable
and facilitate potential market access. Aircraft and equipment
manufacturers had been implementing the notion of Technology Readiness
Level (TRL) which streamlined the road-mapping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guidelines were subsequently written to support the rollout of this new
language and practice. Business units were then able to provide and use
a maturity assessment canvas for the technologies in development and the
road ahead for integration. The president of the ZSTC was then appointed
Chief Technical Officer (CTO) of the Zodiac Aerospace group, a new
position created by the CEO. His role consisted in gradually
institutionalizing the R&amp;amp;T function in business units, supporting them
for public funding opportunities and auditing the practice of R&amp;amp;T and
innovation management (TRL assessment, TRM, patent application and PhD
subjects).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-innovation-locus-where-exploration-project-management-and-organizational-design-clash&#34;&gt;An innovation locus where exploration project management and organizational design clash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we have portrayed in the previous pages the history of aircraft
engineering, the establishment of design rules and the acquisitions
strategy of Zodiac Aerospace. Several key features can be listed
characterizing the innovation context for Zodiac Aerospace (see below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An industrial ecosystem at stake with increasing uncertainties and
unknown due to strong segregated rigidities mirrored by engineering,
safety and regulations but facing potential radical transformations
of architecture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complexity and difficulty to master a full system (architecture and
components) - myopic behaviours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Architectures defined in a contingent manner by the ecosystem
raising uncertainties and the unknown shifts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urge to innovate for strategic competitive advantage in the wake of
a radical change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A consolidated market made of conglomerate but without being
traditional divisional firms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autonomy and responsibility of individual SMEs but the necessity to
orchestrate their interdependencies to innovate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects situated in a intra-BU and inter-BU context challenging
product/service design and organizations simultaneously&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A light corporate team dedicated to innovation with several relay
networks (professions, experts)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zodiac Aerospace presents a distributed innovation management with an
ongoing standardization for processes (Quality Management System) and to
some extent structures (R&amp;amp;T department separated from Development
Engineering). Each BU has its own responsibility and dedicated financial
reporting. They all face their own market segment with the associated
professionalisation but also the urge to embrace uncertainties and the
unknown to innovate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This situation encourages to understand the place in the (aircraft)
system architecture, the interfaces, the interdependencies and knowledge
yet to be discovered to guide exploration and consider synergies with
other BUs. It is a concern for top management as they worry about the
strategy of this portfolio of SMEs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEO and VP&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:17&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:17&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; have stressed the idea the intent was to secure the
niches in the long run, but still develop their own capabilities to
prepare the future. They specified the importance of branch directors to
oversee the portfolio of business units to build a sustainable strategy
for them. Top management had for instance launched several initiatives
they considered to be key for the group or gave a place for bottom-up
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, transversality was gradually being organized with
communities of experts, TechnoDays, (in)formal communities of practice
for engineering and R&amp;amp;T managers at the BU or division level.
Top management also decided to launch projects and places were novel
products and services could be developed &lt;em&gt;in-between&lt;/em&gt; the organizational
boundaries or just seen as strategic for the whole group. A fuel-cell
project was launched, hosted by a business unit with the prospect to
developing this technology for the aircraft equipment market with
perspectives on electricity, water and heat management. Two teams were
set near aircraft manufactures: one near Airbus and the other by Boeing.
These teams were composed of several engineers, designers and managers
from different business units. They dedicated 50% of their time to
technical support for their BU of origin; the rest was dedicated to
business intelligence and innovation management. Workshops, prototyping,
and presentations were regularly organized by the team to generate
concepts sometimes in partnership with clients, users and also
representatives of BUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gradual rationalization of the R&amp;amp;T and Innovation activities since
2010 with the establishment of R&amp;amp;T and Innovation management within each
BU was supplemented by an effort coordinated by top management to the
develop even more radical design of products and services. The former
tend to address incremental innovation, sometimes radical ones aimed
through a path punctuated by several steps to test their environment.
For instance, long term projects are part of partnership agreement
funded by institutions such as associative, national or international
Research Councils. The latter were a means for the Executive Committee
to protect existing niches from more radical concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these specific case raising strategic interest, such project were
addressed in a different &lt;em&gt;locus&lt;/em&gt; breaking away from the existing and
protected organization design: the multi-BU committee was rather
convenient. Otherwise, the Business Unit being is considered as an
indivisible unit. It encourages the development of alternative
approaches: fostering exploration topics, steering committees for
valuation and strategy, and project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-studies-selection&#34;&gt;Case studies selection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brief-case-description&#34;&gt;Brief case description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, we present the different case studies conducted at Zodiac
Aerospace and that where discussed in five different articles in
Appendix. Due to organizational dimension of innovation management of
this conglomerate of SMEs, and the organization design, we propose to
split the cases in two categories: intra-BU and inter-BU. The trajectory
of studied projects were, in fact, more or less contained within the
perimeter of a business unit, market segment,
qualification/certification requirements. Other cases were deliberately
set in between these boundaries or across with top management
sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;intra-bu-cases&#34;&gt;Intra-BU cases&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;icing-conditions-detection&#34;&gt;Icing conditions detection&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The first impulse originated in the early 90s with the concern a former
CEO - Intertechnique group (now Zodiac Fuel and Control Systems) - and
with the crash of an ATR72 in the U.S.A due to ice accretion on wings. A
project manager and engineer (who would eventually become the R&amp;amp;T
manager), developed an ultrasonic sensor for wing’s skin to detect ice
and measure icing-protection fluid dilution ratio. It allowed
participating to several test campaigns, to gain a reputation in the
field for safety and airworthiness (DGAC, EASA, Transport Canada), and
develop two versions of the technology with the support of funding
(SPAé, European Power Optimized Aircraft) and synergies with pending
product development (e.g. computer electronics for A380). A first patent
was applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early 2000s, the technology is compared in test campaigns with the
monopoly’s solution (Goodrich, former Richmond; mechanical oscillator).
It proved its efficiency on the ground but not for flying conditions due
to several technical limitations compared to competition’s: no defrost,
complex wing installation and high costs. Furthermore, Airbus did not
support the development as their aircraft (A380) is not sensitive to
icing. Airworthiness institutions were indeed specifying icing
conditions types and aircraft sensitivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, regional aircraft manufacturers such as ATR and Bombardier were
pushing former Aerazur entity (now Zodiac Elastomer Europe) and
Intertechnique for an integrated ice detection and ice protection
system. With the support of several engineers recruited in previous
years, they developed a solution tested again with the support of Airbus
as the icing conditions detection regulations were evolving. Three test
campaigns were conducted with convincing results from an alternative
technology (thermodynamics and Peltier effect) overcoming the previous
limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite an aircraft program request for proposal and with uncertainty
and potential surprises in airworthiness evolutions, the recently
established icing conditions team at Intertechnique pivoted towards an
unfamiliar technology for the BU (laser optics). Parallel studies were
conducted, and the R&amp;amp;T manager had participated to technology
evaluations with FAA and Transport Canada. In addition, strategy and
business development managers had considered potential acquisitions to
definitely break the monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in 2011 a new project on uncertain laser technology was
launched within a CleanSky program. And more recently, a second project
was launched, with CleanSky2, forking the technology concept developed
so far and extending the airworthiness validity domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The researcher came around this case with the support of the
CTO and R&amp;amp;T manager who explicitly mentioned the need to specify the
nature of this projects at odds with other R&amp;amp;T and Engineering
Departments activities and with BU management. The project was seen as
an unidentified object despite having legitimacy in the airworthiness,
safety fields and among aircraft manufacturer engineering departments.
The generative processes needed to be further specified to understand
the nuances of its innovation potential of attraction with respect to
the engineering department, knowledge and organization design.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;business-class-seat-platform&#34;&gt;Business Class Seat platform&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This case is an outcome of a recurrent topic at Zodiac Seats France:
standardization and modularization of seat architecture to facilitate
product development. Indeed, airlines demand for seats change every 5-10
years, including cabin reconfiguration for seasonal passengers flows,
and they request a short development cycle of about 2 years, compared to
the 10 years (approx.) for an aircraft. However, the seat is absolutely
critical in passenger safety with severe qualification and certification
requirements in association with increasing demands for
airline/passenger customization and ergonomic design. Despite the
beneficial prospects of platform engineering for economy and business
class seats, the rhythm of product development and complexity in
conjunction with optimized resources hadn’t left many opportunities to
develop such project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separated from development engineers, a recently constituted R&amp;amp;T
department was tasked to study the modularization of a business class
seat for easier packaging and certification. A large exploration
(patent, design options, architectures, technologies etc.) was
considered and selection of design concepts were made based on product
development criteria and support of several engineering, operations and
marketing stakeholders. Further stress simulation and testing was
required, but following the bid award from a demanding airline, the
subsequent design and development was driven by customer requirements
and its design studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several difficulties were discovered late in the development raising
questions on the maturity of the design and certification requirements
such as increased difficulties associated with the joint qualification
of seat and shell and inclusion of airbags. Delays were unfortunately
accumulated with numerous quality problems due to technical compromises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the exploration quality, exploitation issues had to be dealt
with. The project trajectory that aimed at developing a business class
seat platform was compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The research was introduced to such product development case
as he was supporting the R&amp;amp;T department in formalizing the TRL
assessment and associated management. The Director of Engineering and
R&amp;amp;T managers were intrigued and disturbed by the design choices and
integration issues, requesting a deeper understanding of the
coordination and collective action model, as well as how the innovation
potential of attraction of the platform was managed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;hypoxia-protection---researchers-intervention&#34;&gt;Hypoxia protection - researcher’s intervention&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The R&amp;amp;T department was preparing mid-2017 a participation to CleanSky2
program with Airbus as a partner in order to propose new radical
solution to protect pilots from hypoxia. The need emerged from the
necessity (safety) requiring a pilot to wear the emergency oxygen mask
when alone in the cockpit. Such requirement is however hardly compatible
with the required comfort of extended use due to emergency design of the
mask (high levels of stress, smoke in the cabin, emergency manoeuvre)..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team was originally constituted of R&amp;amp;T engineers, and then after 6
months, they were stretched over the traditional engineering department
dedicated to product development leaving only one R&amp;amp;T member. Numerous
brainstorming and design sessions with the support from an external
design studio contributed to a wide and in-depth exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In parallel, an internal &amp;ldquo;Open Innovation Challenge&amp;rdquo; organized by the
ZSTC for which one of the two topics was improving ergonomics of the
oxygen crew mask. The researcher had then proposed a C-K mapping to
position and value the concepts proposed by ZA participants. In addition
to the acquaintance with the R&amp;amp;T and Engineering manager for other
purposes, the researcher was requested to support the project team in
selecting concepts, and guiding them before the first proposal to the
CleanSky2 partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the occasion to work on the decision-making and the design of
alternatives and states of nature, as well as embedding the organization
design required to support the innovation effort expected in the
project. The dichotomy of exploration/exploitation could then be
revisited and nuanced within this project. It enabled the proposal of
novel ways to organize collective action within and around the
exploration project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;inter-bu-cases&#34;&gt;Inter-BU cases&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;airbus-development-team---design-thinking-cases&#34;&gt;Airbus Development Team - Design Thinking cases&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The ADT is sponsored and monitored by the C-suite for strategic
management purposes. The team was tasked to provide technical support
for several BUs and to generate concepts that would feed on unmet user
needs by gaining a better knowledge of real use cases of ZA products.
The team is constituted of 8 permanent engineers and designers delegated
by BUs for three years maximum, and dedicating half of their time to
their BU’s sales/technical support. They report to a local manager who
actively contributes to the team creative effort and facilitates
discussions with BUs. He reports to the group VP of Strategy and
Business Development as well as the Chief Technical Officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Design Thinking (DT) methodology was chosen to promote the
user-centric approach, explore usage, share gathered knowledge, and
ideate for and with relevant BUs. ADT’s two project leaders were trained
to DT at Stanford’s d.school, and other members were trained in other
institutions. A design and creativity spirit was largely promoted by the
local manager as well as the members themselves. The projects phasing
completely covered DT’s enactment themes (Carlgren, Rauth, and Elmquist
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Carlgren2016a&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both cases addressed transverse topics where many BUs are concerned in
some way or are actively part of the value chain. The first topic dealt
with waste managed onboard aircrafts. The second topic tackled the
optimization of aircraft turn around time (i.e. between landing and
take-off). Several users and extreme users can be searched and studied
to build empathy and also the technical/market knowledge from the
different BUs is tightly interfaced around both topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to fit the scope of work of the ADT, the team shared knowledge
with BUs to keep them up-to-date and build legitimacy all along the DT
process. A “Multi BU workshop” was organized for problem-reframing and
further ideation and prototyping with BUs. A final selection process was
defined based on DT criteria and ZA’s strategic intent: customer value,
technical feasibility, passenger experience, group strategic alignment,
in addition to a separate ranking for “creative sparks”. The selected
concepts were then approved by the Group VP of Strategy. Thereafter,
they were shared again and promoted to business units who could
potentially host their development in their renewed product lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; the researcher had first visited ADT in Toulouse, since it was
recognized as one of the new loci of innovation in ZA. Interested by the
PhD project and with several pending problems regarding concept
appropriation by BU, the local manager accepted and invited his
colleagues to provide relevant project documentation and interviews to
gain an understanding of the projects driven by Design Thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lower-deck&#34;&gt;Lower deck&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As several projects had been launched as well as numerous ideation
sessions at ADT, the researcher had presented his analysis of the two
Design Thinking cases in March 2016. Among the conclusions, the C-K
mapping and project trajectories had revealed the recurrent topic of
using the aircraft lower deck (cargo area) as a means to embody several
concepts enabling solutions for waste management and aircraft turn
around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local manager had also a hunch for such topic as it had been quite
recurrent in the three years of existence of ADT, including a
provisional patent application with a former intern. As the team was
about to be renewed, he decided to request the former intern to come
back and support a new project dedicated to the lower deck use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first market study was launched with a consulting firm to evaluate
airline’s ticket yield management in addition to fleet evolution and
maintenance dates, to envision the size of lower deck market in addition
to its integration. The latter was critical as it implied modifying the
aircraft’s cargo area for passengers without disrupting airlines’
operations. The technical feasibility of this retrofit was studied first
by an external engineering firm and then deepen by an internal BU
dedicated to certifying specific aircraft customization. In parallel,
concepts were tested with several airlines’ executives, and the overall
business case was discussed with ZA Executive Committee board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project proved to be a success as several key client (airlines and
Airbus) formalized requests for proposals and project development
framing is ongoing (see announcements during last Aircraft Interiors
Exposition in Hamburg 2018). Moreover, several BUs are willing to take
ownership of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This project has to be read at the light of the Design
Thinking projects conducted at ADT and other projects followed by
closely by the ExCom.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;connected-cabin&#34;&gt;Connected Cabin&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The raising interest for connectivity and Big Data for aviation industry
had made its way into Zodiac Aerospace. Such topic was a perfect fit for
Zodiac Inflight Innovations who developed inflight entertainment
solutions and communication devices as well as Zodiac Data Systems
(antennae and inflight test equipment). The topic was rather convenient
for another BU such as Zodiac Air Catering Equipment whose market value
chain extends from the aircraft galley area to catering services
delivering the trolleys to aircraft doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two members of the ZSTC, affiliated to Zodiac Inflight Innovations
started pitching the idea in front of the Executive Committee to launch
a project on Big Data services centred around an enhanced cabin with
connectivity hardware enabling machine to machine communication and
management. After two rounds with the support from a member of the ExCom
in charge of their business branch, they managed to precise the project
scope, potential business case, and needed resource to develop a
prototype to probe the market at 2017 Aircraft Interiors Exposition in
Hamburg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A team was constituted with engineers from different BUs providing
equipment for the cabin and who had an interest in constituting the
connected cabin and developing associated services. The project moved on
quickly with bi-weekly reporting meetings followed by the VP of Strategy
and Business Development, and numerous side meetings. Moreover, the
ExCom made an open statement to investors that a project was being
launched to value aircraft connectivity. A cabin prototype was
manufactured with built-in connectivity features and scenarized for
airlines. It put forward the benefits of retrofitting hardware and
software providing value-added services smoothing airline operations and
client experience and satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prototype enabled collecting valuable feedback from potential
clients and following the exposition the project did not continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The researcher came around this case as he knew the two ZSTC
members and regularly attended ExCom meetings relative to technology and
innovation. They were keen on having him following the progress of the
project and keep track of concepts generated along, even before the
budgeting agreed by ExCom. This case benefited from the same context and
sponsorship as the Lower deck. Consequently, we can contrast them and
nuance their respective innovation potential of attraction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;multi-bu-committee&#34;&gt;Multi-BU committee&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The researcher was regularly invited by the CTO to attend
ExCom meetings relative to technology and innovation. These meetings
were usually labelled Multi-BU meetings following the interest of former
CEO (Olivier Zarrouati) to have a top-down approach urging new projects
(such as the Fuel Cell briefly exposed earlier) and also to offer space
to projects originating in one or multiple BUs bearing a strategic
importance. All of these projects addressed new markets, gaps in between
market segments by bringing forward new technologies or new product
concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This case is approached not necessarily on the technical, engineering or
marketing content of the projects steered by the MBU committee, but
rather on the way decision-making was conducted by individuals and teams
attending these meetings. ExCom members were all present with leadership
from the CEO and VP of Business Development and Strategy. The meetings
were prepared by the MBU Director, also called Director of Large
Projects (&lt;em&gt;Directeur des Grands Projets&lt;/em&gt;) with the support of the
Director in charge of product roadmaps. The job involved monthly
reporting of the projects to the mentioned VP as they would be
subsidized by top management budget (stemming from fees collected by the
holding on BUs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meetings occurred in average every quarter, sometimes punctuated by
other meetings in between for projects requiring an urgent strategic
decision: commercial support for business development, group strategy
relative to overall market positioning and budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Committee operates as an alternative locus of (radical) innovation
compared to in-house R&amp;amp;T and Product Development activities in BUs. It
emphasizes the interest of corporate management for entrepreneurship
across the group. It also differs from the ZSTC and members of the
Innovation Direction whose role leans towards support (processes and
tools) and networking for knowledge domains sustained by experts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;associated-paper-writing&#34;&gt;Associated paper writing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;anomaly-detection---case-studies-and-written-papers&#34;&gt;Anomaly detection - Case studies and written papers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Paper no.&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Associated Paper&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Associated cases&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Thinking for innovation management&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;The purpose of this paper is to study the adoption of Design Thinking methods for multi-BU and B2B2C context. Design Theories are used to track generativity of the design practice: user fixation and learning metabolism supporting innovation management. &lt;br&gt; Presented at 6th Creativity Innovation Management (CIM) Community Workshop, first submitted and rejected Spring 2017 to CIM Journal, reformulated for R&amp;amp;D Management Conference 2018 and resubmitted to CIM journal with substantial modifications compared to first version.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airbus Development Team&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Waste Management (6 months) &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Turn Around Time (8 months) interviews for each case, field notes and full access to project documentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decision-making in exploration project management&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;In this article directly submitted to CERN IdeaSquare Journal of Experimental Innovation (2017), after a round of reviews for ICED 2017, we presented an exploration project conducted over more than a decade. It showcases the project’s timeline and what could be considered as an irrational due to a preference reversal. &lt;br&gt;We propose instead to extend the notion of rationality with the existence of generative actions and the deliberate will to reverse preferences. These are seen as means to manage the unknown. Departing from optimization, design and generative processes can support this extension and exploration. We consequently introduce the notion &lt;em&gt;decisional ambidexterity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zodiac Fuel and Control Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case:&lt;/strong&gt; Icing conditions detection system (one decade, and additional background history) interviewees consulted several times, field notes and full access to project documentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizational Ambidexterity and innovation management&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;This paper addresses the hypothesis that organizational ambidexterity (OA) can kill innovation. The first version called for the importance of decision-making to understand the operationalization of OA as mentioned by researchers in the field. We propose to leverage non-expected utility decision-making based on Paper 2, but in reality with the feedback from the research community we also recentred the presentation on problem-solving as originally discussed by James March seminal paper (March 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-March1991&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;). We stress the aporia of segregating exploration from exploitation for a meaningful exploration as generativity is otherwise biased and reduced. The latter revealed being crucial to manage the unknown and consequently to innovate. &lt;br&gt;Presented at EURAM 2018 Conference Innovation SIG and will be rewritten based on valuable collected feedback.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airbus Development Team and Zodiac Seats France&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Case 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Waste Management (6 months) &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Business Class Seat Platform interviews for case 1 and 10 interviews, in addition to field notes, full access to projects documentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;modelling-and-intervention---case-studies-and-written-papers&#34;&gt;Modelling and intervention - Case studies and written papers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Paper no.&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Associated Paper&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Associated cases&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designing decision: managing the unknown&lt;/strong&gt; This article discusses the need to overcome the decision paradigm by embracing design theories to extend the latter to the unknown. Four archetypes of decisions based on design paths are presented corresponding to different forms of collective action: learning, performance and organization. Compared to the published paper, we extend the model with organizational theories by integrating organizational constraints and hypothesis in the decision design reasoning to generate and execute alternatives/decisions to be managed in exploration/exploitation modes. &lt;br&gt;Presented on several occasions by Pascal Le Masson, debated with the researcher over the PhD’s second year. After a first round of reviews, a modified version is in press in the European Management Review.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theoretical paper&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;The traditional thought experiment of the decision to go out with an umbrella/hat given the weather belief is used.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Paper no.&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Associated Paper&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Associated cases&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambidextrous decisions and corporate entrepreneurship&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;Given the anomaly and the proposed model, we will present two cases that can explain their success and failure. These have a corporate entrepreneurship taste and present features relating to decisional ambidexterity, managing the unknown and organizing for it. One case appears to have the right set of practices to succeed in its innovative design and associated management whereas the other one struggles. The comparison allows justifying the usefulness of the new model and ways to implement certain practices. It is a working paper to be submitted by the end of 2018 to conferences (to be determined)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airbus Development Team, Connected Cabin and Multi-BU committee&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Aircraft’s lower deck (1 year) &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Connected cabin (10 months) Field notes, minutes of meetings, 6 interviewees each consulted on multiple occasions and full access to projects documentations, meeting minutes, in addition to input from former CEO and VP.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-synthesis&#34;&gt;Chapter synthesis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After having globally presented the general research methodology of the
PhD journey for the research questions refined over the last three
years, we have described in this chapter the actual research context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of the aviation industry, its emergence, and its gradual
organization and segmentation with the numerous original actors explain
the dynamics of today’s market and positioning of players such as Zodiac
Aerospace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This firm has developed specific innovation capabilities through several
decades of acquisitions, extending its market footprint. In the last
decade, we presented how centralization and gradual homogenization, new
coordination means and collective action patterns emerged to cope with
the unknown to be managed for future aircraft programs and markets. We
exposed also the difficulties for top/middle/local management to address
the challenges imposed by exploration project management with respect to
the underlying organization designs and market segmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we introduced the case studies conducted at Zodiac Aerospace
and how these led to published and presented articles in journals and
conferences. These papers fit with the methodology of anomaly detection,
theoretical modelling and empirical testing. We explain how the other
cases support the researcher’s intervention, testing and
experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references hanging-indent&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Ader1907&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ader, Clément. 1907. &lt;em&gt;La première étape de l’aviation militaire en
France&lt;/em&gt;. Paris: J. Bosc et Cie.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cnum.cnam.fr/CGI/redir.cgi?A890&#34;&gt;http://cnum.cnam.fr/CGI/redir.cgi?A890&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Barr1992&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barr, Vilma. 1992. “Alexandre Gustave Eiffel: a towering engineering
genius.” &lt;em&gt;Mechanical Engineering&lt;/em&gt; 114 (2): 58–65.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Carlgren2016a&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlgren, Lisa, Ingo Rauth, and Maria Elmquist. 2016. “Framing Design
Thinking: The Concept in Idea and Enactment.” &lt;em&gt;Creativity and Innovation
Management&lt;/em&gt; 25 (1): 38–57. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/caim.12153&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/caim.12153&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Gallant2002&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gallant, Joseph. 2002. “The shape of the Eiffel Tower.” &lt;em&gt;American
Journal of Physics&lt;/em&gt; 70 (2): 160–62. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1119/1.1417530&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1119/1.1417530&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Henderson1990&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henderson, Rebecca M., and Kim B. Clark. 1990. “Architectural
Innovation: The Reconfiguration of Existing Product Technologies and the
Failure of Established Firms.” &lt;em&gt;Administrative Science Quarterly&lt;/em&gt; 35
(1): 9–30. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2307/2393549&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2307/2393549&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-Holzle2010&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hölzle, Katharina. 2010. “Designing and implementing a career path for
project managers.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Project Management&lt;/em&gt; 28 (8):
779–86. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2010.05.004&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijproman.2010.05.004&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-March1991&#34; markdown=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March, James G. 1991. “Exploration and exploitation in organizational
learning.” &lt;em&gt;Organization Science&lt;/em&gt; 2: 71–87.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;see his treatise &lt;em&gt;On Aerial Navigation&lt;/em&gt;, 1810 &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecole d’Avionnerie&lt;/em&gt;: see for instance the letters exchanged
between Clémenter Ader and Generals Billot and Laurent in (Ader

&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Ader1907&#34;&gt;1907&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, see the history written by Claude Rosetti:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.isae-supaero.fr/fr/isae-supaero/Institut/hisis-l-histoire-illustree-de-nos-ecoles&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.isae-supaero.fr/fr/isae-supaero/Institut/hisis-l-histoire-illustree-de-nos-ecoles&#34;&gt;https://www.isae-supaero.fr/fr/isae-supaero/Institut/hisis-l-histoire-illustree-de-nos-ecoles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First flight with animals in front of the court of Louis XVI in
Versailles on 19 September 1783; and first manned flight with
Jean-François Pilâtre de Rozier on 21 November 1783 over Paris by
the Castle of La Muette for the crown prince: Louis XVII &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must specify here that in 1909, Maurice Mallet &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;
developed a standard biplane that flew over 70km on December 9, ten
months after Blériot XI crossed the English channel (approx. 40km) &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could even refer to the novel of Jules Verne &lt;em&gt;The Mysterious
Island&lt;/em&gt; where the characters escape from the siege of Richmond,
Virginia with an air balloon. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grundmanadvisory.com/?news=aviation-week-published-grundman-opinion-a-map-of-aerospace-mergers-and-acquisitions&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grundmanadvisory.com/?news=aviation-week-published-grundman-opinion-a-map-of-aerospace-mergers-and-acquisitions&#34;&gt;http://grundmanadvisory.com/?news=aviation-week-published-grundman-opinion-a-map-of-aerospace-mergers-and-acquisitions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definition: the capability of an aircraft to operate safely with
respect to its crew, its passengers, on-board goods and outside
environment (air traffic and other people including on-ground). &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: The reader should not consider that there are different
levels of criticality but rather that in order to ease the
development, qualification and certification, some equipment are not
necessarily queued in the qualification process of the aircraft but
as interdependencies are mastered in the integrating aircrafts the
certification process can be carried &amp;ldquo;separately&amp;rdquo; even though
several features are still adjusted through changes
requested/submitted between manufacturer and supplier. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;replacing traditional manual mechanical flight controls &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See for instance the experiment lead by Airbus $A^3$ in
California to test their modular cabin concept for refurbished
freight aircrafts called &lt;em&gt;Transpose&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:12&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, the genericization of the Zodiac trademark, rubber coated
fabric inflatable boats made also famous by military boats and the
Atlantic ocean crossing of Alain Bombard &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;former CEO from 2007 to 2017 who more than doubled the revenues
and tripled the stock price &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:14&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British Owner Sells Weber Aircraft for 85 Million, LA Times,
1992, 7th October &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:15&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: this career path implied a more traditional management of
teams until reaching managing director and escalating the
hierarchical line. The project and program management was at first
outlined as a comparison (Hölzle 
&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-Holzle2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;) but never
formalized by Human Resources. Several cross-overs would occur
between programs and traditional management. The projectification of
business units would somehow blur their differences despite
sustaining the importance of both functions and projects in the
matrix. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:15&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:16&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translated by the author: &amp;ldquo;C’est un levier majeur de croissance
pour un Groupe comme le nôtre qui conçoit et réalise les systèmes
les plus complexes et qui doit répondre à des contraintes
réglementaires et à des exigences de qualité et de sécurité toujours
plus fortes. En 2010, nous avons créé le ZSTC pour améliorer
l’efficacité de notre recherche technologique, disposer des
ressources nécessaires à notre compétitivité, favoriser le
développement d’innovations croisées à forte valeur ajoutée.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:16&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:17&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open interviews conducted by the author in May/June 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:17&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
